<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: friends | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/friends/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-31T20:09:28-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surprise, I'm 40!]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/09/06/surprise-im-40"/>
    <updated>2011-09-06T14:01:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/09/06/surprise-im-40</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/vinod40-1.jpg" title="Vinod is surprised" ></p>

<p>Have you ever been in one of those dreams where everything seems
normal and then a flying car (or something equally crazy) comes out of
nowhere? I'm used to having experiences like that when I'm dreaming,
but it was quite surreal to have it during waking hours.</p>

<p>Mala and Kavi had gone ahead (surreptiously to plan a surprise party
for someone else!). We were to meet at the ferris wheel at the Navy
Pier. I found her and she took my hand. She started leading me through
the crowds of tourists. I could sense excitement in her demeanor, but
didn't think anything of it. She led me towards a group of people and
I caught a glimpse of someone who looked like my Dad. That's
weird... why would he be here? It's at that point that neurons started
to malfunction and I began to feel like I was in a dream. Then I saw
Mala's mom and got even more confused. Slowly the group of strangers
came into focus and revealed themselves as my friends and family from
around the country. It was, without a doubt, the best birthday present
that I have ever received, or expect to receive. Thanks to Mala for
months of planning, and for wanting to make me feel special even
though I feel this way every day when I wake up next to her. Thanks to
all my friends and family who could make it and to the ones who
couldn't. If this is the culmination of 40 years on this earth, I
can't wait for the next 40!</p>

<p><img src="/images/vinod40-2.jpg" title="Vinod is 40" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[House party]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2008/08/03/house-party"/>
    <updated>2008-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2008/08/03/house-party</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a few friends over tonight for our first little get-together in our house. Mala made homemade pizza and cake. I provided moral support :-) Everyone had a great time. There were 4 little kiddos and 1 infant, which made for some craziness, but everyone left in good health. It's a treat to watch Kavi interact with other kids. He's a real observer. He sits back and watches what everyone is doing. While the other kids were running like crazy around the house, Kavi was content to sit on the carpet and watch them scream. He was pretty tired since he had taken an early nap, so maybe that was part of it. He also seemed happy to watch the other kids play with all of his toys. I mean, sometimes he would try to grab a toy that another kid was playing with, but for the most part, he didn't seem to care. When we finally cleaned up and got him ready for bed, it was nearly 10 PM. He fell asleep while I was singing a lullaby to him. He woke up for a minute when I put him down, but that was it. He was tired!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Update]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update"/>
    <updated>2007-05-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once again, I've fallen behind on my life updates, so let's get caught up.</p>

<ul>
<li>Mala's pregnancy is going well, at least from the husband's point of view. She's due June 15th.</li>
<li>We drove to Orlando for my CME conference because Delta cancelled our flight. It turned out to be a nice thing because we got to see Puja, Ethan and Loki on the way down and we got to stop in Charleston, SC on the way back.</li>
<li>Not to be outdone by Delta, Northwest cancelled my flight to Minneapolis. For those scoring at home, that's 2 consecutive flights cancelled due to "weather"</li>
<li>Our job search came down to the wire and, in a difficult decision, we chose North Carolina. I'll be working as a hospitalist at <a href="http://www.durhamregional.org/">Durham Regional Hospital</a> (associated with Duke University) and Mala will be at the <a href="http://pediatrics.med.unc.edu/div/endocrin/default.htm">University of North Carolina</a>.</li>
<li>We went to Baltimore for Mala's 10 year Hopkins Reunion. I got to see the campus where Mala went to college and we even took in a lacrosse game.</li>
<li>My brother <a href="http://www2.kurup.net/">Manu started to blog</a>. Yes, this is a thinly veiled jab to get him to update again.</li>
<li>Puja and Farah threw a wonderful little baby shower for us. It was a lot of fun (yes, I just said that a baby shower was a lot of fun)</li>
<li>I just got back from a quick trip to North Carolina to find an apartment. We'll be staying at a place called Southpoint Village, assuming that it gets built in time. Everyone please cross your fingers.</li>
<li>My parents have moved to Dallas, TX, which means that the house I grew up with will be sold. It didn't hit me until just now, but I'll probably never see the inside of that house again.</li>
<li>We're both beginning to wind down at our current jobs. Mala's fellowship ends in June and my last day is July 10th. We'll move to NC at some point after that.</li>
<li>They finally turned the A/C on in the building here, which is really nice when the weather is 90+ and your wife is pregnant :)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 weddings, 5 babies, 2 graduations and a dog]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog"/>
    <updated>2006-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/mala-nyc.jpg" width="500" alt="IMG_5830.JPG" /></p>

<p>I love taking pictures with my trusty old Canon S200. It takes great pics and I get to take the credit. I'm just horrible about getting them off my camera and onto my website. I finally uploaded a <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/?folder_id=61013">whole bunch</a> today, dating back to early May when we went to <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71973">Philadelphia for Kevin and Joanne's wedding</a>. The next group is from <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71975">Brooklyn and Staten Island for Mary Ann and Benjeil's wedding</a>. We interrupted wedding season to watch <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71979">Ethan graduate from law school</a> in Minneapolis. While in the Twin Cities, we got to spend a few minutes with <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=73510">Ajay</a>. Back home, we started <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71981">Memorial Day in the Cloisters</a>, had lunch in the city (photo above), and finished the day by meeting a cute girl named <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=73401">Amalie</a> (of Amalie &amp; Ivory fame!). A week later we were back in the Midwest for <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71983">Sivan's cozy high school graduation</a>. Nothing like watching your nephew graduate from high school to make you feel old. <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=74486">Mike and Susan threw a barbecue in Long Island</a> to celebrate their farewell. <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=74502">Asha</a> was there too! Next up on the wedding circuit were <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71985">Russ and Michelle</a>. They were nice enough to get married in DC, so we were able to stay with Puja and meet <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=74305">Loki</a>. <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71987">Mala interviewed in Norfolk</a> where we were introduced to <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=74063">Kylee</a> for the first time.</p>

<p>And if that's not enough for you, here are some <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71977">random pics from the Bronx</a>. I'm sad to say that I've yet to take any photos of <a href="http://kurup.org/dave/photo/photo?photo_id=71894">Hunter June</a>, so I'll point you instead to <a href="http://kurup.org/dave/photo/album?album_id=67042">her parents' photos</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Milla Blogs]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/08/02/milla-blogs"/>
    <updated>2006-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/08/02/milla-blogs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kurup.org/blog/2006/07/25/recurrent-dvt#comment68115">Milla correctly points out</a> that she is my blogging inspiration.  Not just for telling me to blog more, but for providing the inspiration in the form of the <a href="http://millatonkonogy.blogspot.com/">most promising blog-start ever</a>!  My <a href="http://millatonkonogy.blogspot.com/2006/07/blame-it-on-rain.html">favorite so far</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>I turned on 1010 Wins "you give us 20 minutes, we'll give you traffic updates from yesterday for roads you don't drive on" and heard nothing at all about the mudslide on the Saw Mill River Parkway, which turned my road home into a parking lot.</p></blockquote>

<p>Someone put her on a reality show, already!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
