<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: new-york | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/new-york/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-29T21:34:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ecce Bed &amp; Breakfast]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/ecce-bed-breakfast"/>
    <updated>2006-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/ecce-bed-breakfast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/ecce-panorama.jpg" width="580" alt="Ecce view" /></p>

<p>Can you believe that it's been a year since <a href="http://kurup.org/wedding">we got
married</a>? Me neither. For our wedding, Mike
and Ellie gave us a generous gift certificate to the bed &amp;
breakfast of our choice. It took a while to find the right one. We
started at bedandbreakfast.com and surfed dozens of listings. This
industry really needs some web consulting advice. Most B&amp;B
websites don't provide nearly enough information. I want more photos,
more reviews. I want to get a feel for the atmosphere.</p>

<p>We finally found a website that showed off those things and made a
reservation at <a href="http://www.eccebedandbreakfast.com/">Ecce</a>. We had
high expectations, but I'm happy to say that they were exceeded. You
won't find more hospitable proprietors than Alan and Kurt. Our <a href="/images/ecce-room.jpg">room
was tastefully designed</a> and was stocked
with a gourmet coffee machine, TV/DVD/VCR, fridge and jacuzzi! It was
pure luxury. The breakfasts were over the top. Definitely try the
french toast with chocolate.</p>

<p>The house sits on a bluff overlooking the Delaware River. The view is
amazing. I tried to take one of those panorama pics, but I don't think
it does it justice. This place must be breathtaking in the fall. We
saw 4 or 5 bald eagles and numerous hawks from the house. We also saw
a lot of deer hanging out near the highways.</p>

<p>Tropical Storm Ernesto was winding through the region this weekend, so
we didn't do too much in the way of outdoors stuff. We did enjoy the
Harvest Festival Market and had some great fried food at the bar at
Lackawaxen House. We were less impressed with the Front Porch Cafe,
but it was very busy and had gotten good reviews, so maybe we just got
unlucky.</p>

<p>So thanks again, Mike and Ellie. I'm certain we never would've
otherwise explored this paradise just 2 hours from our front door. And
thank you Mala, for the best year of my life (so far!)</p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>hey mon</b></p>
<p>
Hey Vinod,
</p>
<p>
Looks like you're taking the entries to a new level (with the photos).
Cool cool!
</p>
<p>
Thanks for the shout out wrt H.
</p>
<p>
Kurup.org keeps growing and growing.  Awesome.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Dave T</span>
<span class="date">2006-09-08 00:46:12</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>bed and breakfast blog from Puerto Rico</b></p>
<p>
I found your blog by searching for bed and breakfast blogs.
</p>
<p>
I'm having a terrible time finding more blogs written by bed and
breakfast owners like mine.
</p>
<p>
It is a <a href="http://myblog.rainforestinn.com"> bed and breakfast
blog </a> about our place deep in the heart of the El Yunque
rainforest of Puerto Rico. We are working on repairing hurricane
damage and we do a podcast about Puerto Rico
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Bill &amp; Laurie</span>
<span class="date">2006-10-07 17:12:15</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
