<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: zen | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/zen/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-31T20:09:28-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Found the Carolina North trail]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2009/10/09/found-the-carolina-north-trail"/>
    <updated>2009-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2009/10/09/found-the-carolina-north-trail</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When Mala and I started looking for homes, we listed on a yellow notepad
all the things that were important to us. Like most little notes in my
life, it got lost. I found it a few days after we moved into our home and
was pleasantly surprised that we had gotten everything on our list, except
a lake view. Not bad, and there's a lake about a half mile from our
door. One of the things on that list that we "kinda" got was "running
trails nearby". I say "kinda" because there is a trail which is just behind
the back of our property, but I wouldn't call it a running trail. It is a
paved trail which runs behind the houses in our neighborhood and extends
about 1 mile in total length. It is mostly through woods or along the lake,
so it's nice, but it's not a running trail. A running trail is not
paved. More importantly, a running trail goes for miles and miles, so that
you can feel like you are away from (sub)urban life.</p>

<p>So this was one of those things on our "list" that I would say we checked
off, but, not really, you know?</p>

<p>I <a href="http://twitter.com/vkurup/status/4533018776">went for a run</a> recently
and I can now say with certainty that this is my dream house. That paved
running trail which I had been so ambivalent about eventually ends at a
main road. And that's where I thought it ended. On Thursday, I crossed the
road and found a little mowed path which takes you to the local high
school. And then you take a right and WOW! A huge forest with a 10 foot
wide rock and dirt trail opens up in front of you. I started down this
trail, expecting it to end at someone's private property, but it kept going
and going and going. It ran next to a bubbling stream with water clear
enough to see the river's bottom. There were countless little paths snaking
away from the main one. I just kept running and it just got more and more
beautiful. I wish I had brought my camera. It felt like a religious
experience. I couldn't believe that this beautiful, seemingly endless trail
- the type of trail that I would have driven miles to get to in the past -
was in my backyard. I ended up running 11 miles, which is longer than I
have run since moving to North Carolina. I can't wait to run there
again. This is just another example of how I am the luckiest man in the
world. I always wanted to live in a house near trails like this, but didn't
think it was possible, so I settled for a little "running trail". Just my
luck, it turns out to be the trail of my dreams :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
