<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: marathon | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/marathon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-09T07:01:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New York Marathon Eve]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/11/05/new-york-marathon-eve"/>
    <updated>2005-11-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/11/05/new-york-marathon-eve</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The marathon is tomorrow. I can't wait, but I'm pretty nervous. I really want to break 5 hours this time. You can track me online at <a href="http://www.ingnycmarathon.org/results/index.php">the NY Marathon site</a>. I'll be runner number 27072.</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE 2005-11-14</strong>:</p>

<p>I finished in 4:28:09 (chip time). I'm very happy with my time and the whole experience. Running down 4th avenue in Brooklyn was crowded, but just breathtaking. You could see a river of people for what seemed like miles ahead. I kept it slow through the first 20 miles and had hoped to turn it on at the end, but there was nothing left to turn on. So, I just enjoyed the sights and sounds. Thanks to my vocal supporters at the 18 (Mala, Milla and Ben) and 22 (Dave and Theresa, et. al.) mile marks. You guys kept me going. Here's a couple pics from the <a href="http://brightroom.com">brightroom</a> site.</p>

<p><img class="inset" src="https://www.kurup.org/images/nyc-marathon.jpg" height="500" width="333" alt="NYC Marathon 2005" /></p>

<p><img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/nyc-marathon-finish.jpg" height="500" width="333"
alt="NYC Marathon 2005 Finish Line" /></p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>Nice work</b></p>
<p>
4:36:41 sounds well under your sub 5 hour goal. Nice work Vinod.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Carl Blesius</span>
<span class="date">2005-11-14 03:42:47</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="my-comment">
<p><b>Thanks Carl</b></p>
<p>
It actually took me 8 minutes to get to the start line, so my "chip"
time was 4:28:09, which is about 40 minutes faster than my previous
marathons. Good enough that I can retire from the sport, I think :-)
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Vinod Kurup</span>
<span class="date">2005-11-14 08:10:51</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>Way to go</b></p>
<p>
Hey Vin, way to go, not a bad time for an old man like yourself.  When
next year's marathon rolls around you'll be 35, you just might be
ready for retirement :P.  You also took a better picture this year as
opposed to last year's photo.  Again way to go.  Andy
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Andy Drout</span>
<span class="date">2005-11-18 23:59:26</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bronx Half-Marathon]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/07/15/bronx-half-marathon"/>
    <updated>2005-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/07/15/bronx-half-marathon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="inset right" src="https://www.kurup.org/images/bronx-half.jpg" height="500" width="333" alt="Finishing the Bronx Half Marathon" /></p>

<p>I ran the <a href="http://web2.nyrrc.org/cgi-bin/start.cgi/aes-programs/results/startup.html?result.id=a50710&amp;amp;result.year=2005">Bronx Half-Marathon</a> on Sunday in 2:07:05. I ran the same race last year in 2:07:02. How's that for consistent?. Of course, I'd rather be consistently <em>fast</em> than consistently <em>slow</em>, but I'm trying to look on the bright side. By the way, I really do enjoy these races more than my pictures would suggest :-)</p>

<p>We started near Lehman College and ran along beautiful tree-lined streets like Sedgwick Avenue and Mosholu Parkway. The course does a few U-turns, so you get to see the leaders coming back. That's always motivating for me. The only annoying stretch is the out and back down the middle of the sun-exposed Grand Concourse. On a bright sunny day, that really drains you.</p>

<p>I hadn't been running consistenly, so I didn't think i'd be setting any records. I'm happy with 2:07. I just need to get in gear and be more consistent with my weekly mileage. I'm following the <a href="http://www.ingnycmarathon.org/training/trainingschedule.php">NYRR Marathon - Casual Marathoner guide</a>. This week I'm supposed to run 24 miles. I've got 15 down so far with a <a href="http://www.nyrr.org/race/2005/r0716x00.php">5 mile race (Dash &amp; Splash)</a> planned on Saturday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New York Marathon, here I come]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/02/01/new-york-marathon-here-i-come"/>
    <updated>2005-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/02/01/new-york-marathon-here-i-come</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's official. I got an email the other day:</p>

<blockquote><p>Congratulations Vinod Kurup! You are eligible for guaranteed entry to the ING New York City Marathon 2005. Simply follow the instructions below and register between January 31 and May 1, 2005, in order to enter the marathon without applying for the lottery. The marathon will take place on Sunday, November 6, 2005.</p></blockquote>

<p>So, I registered today and am now committed to running the New York Marathon in under 4 hours. My number is #17166. Real training begins around June or so. Keep posted for updates :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wall is not a myth]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/10/28/the-wall-is-not-a-myth"/>
    <updated>2003-10-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/10/28/the-wall-is-not-a-myth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I ran the <a href="http://marinemarathon.com">Marine Corps Marathon</a> yesterday
and can now confirm that <a href="http://www.badwaterultra.com/training/bane.html">Hitting the
Wall</a> is a real
phenomenon. I finished about 5 minutes faster than I did in Chicago
(2000), but I was really hoping to break 4:30. Everything was going
great through the halfway point (2:11:48 - 10:04 mpm) when a few
doubts started to creep into my head. I'm only halfway? I gotta do
this again? Somehow I was able to make it through to mile 17 at
2:55:30 (10:19 mpm) before things really fell apart. I remember it
clearly yesterday and it seemed to be an instant replay from
Chicago. I started thinking about how much further I had to go and how
tired I already was. Then I think, well, maybe I need to rest up so I
can finish strong, huh? Maybe I should walk through the next water
break - that won't be such a bad thing, right? And then the next thing
I know, I'm walking more than I'm running. Once I start walking, I'm
done. The key is not to think about how much further you have to go,
but rather to take it one step at a time, but that's obviously easier
said than done. The marathon is not a rational thing - if you think
about it and you let your rational mind make decisions for you, you'll
never accomplish your goal.</p>

<p>I'm still quite happy with finishing. I'm sore all over, but in that
satisfying kinda way. I was able to take the train home yesterday and
even made it to work today. And unlike 2000, I'm motivated to keep
running, although I'm going to stay away from marathoning for a
while. My left brain isn't ready for it.</p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>Metaphor of life</b></p>
<p>
Hi Vinu,  Congratulations on the race.  I fully agree with everything
you said.  You know what I thought about the Marathon that I ran in
Chicago... it is really a metaphor of life... just like you said
taking things step by step.  I saw an advertisement of the Boston
Marathon I think that went something like this... there is nothing you
can't learn about yourself that you can't learn in 26.2 miles.  I was
really amazed at the diversity of people who were runnng.  There were
people who really looked out of shape running at a significantly
faster pace that I could imagine they could run.  I remember a guy
dressed up in a clown suit passing me up and the two guys that ran
with me most of the way.  One of the guys said "we can't let a clown
pass us" to which the other replied "oh yes we can."  I do agree that
the marathon takes a lot out of you both mentally and physically.  My
knees still ache a bit when I run.  I don't know though, it can
certainly be addictive.  I look forward to seeing you to talk about
our marathon experiences.

</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Dileep Nair</span>
<span class="date">2003-11-07 19:01:46</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="my-comment">
<p><b>Love the clown story</b></p>
<p>
It's funny - Harish and I had the same "metaphor for life"
conversation when we were running together in Indianapolis last
weekend.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Vinod Kurup</span>
<span class="date">2003-11-16 22:37:53</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marathon Story]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/08/17/marathon-story"/>
    <updated>2003-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/08/17/marathon-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kevin Kling of NPR gives a <a href="http://www.npr.org/ramarchives/nc6J1101-7.ram">highly accurate recollection of a marathon experience</a> (RealAudio).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
