<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>education on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in education on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Indian Civilization</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/05/31/history-of-indian-civilization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/05/31/history-of-indian-civilization/</guid>
      <description>I briefly mentioned finding the 2012 UCLA lecture series, &amp;ldquo;History of Indian Civilization&amp;rdquo;, a couple days ago. I&amp;rsquo;m about halfway through and have found it thorougly illuminating. I learned a lot about India growing up, but never in a formal way, so it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have someone as skilled as Vinay Lal connect all the loose threads into a coherent history. One of the things that surprises me is that aside from the fact that classes are being streamed over the internet, there is nothing different than the lectures I skipped (I mean religiously attended!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Student Oral Presentations</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/18/medical-student-oral-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 14:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/18/medical-student-oral-presentations/</guid>
      <description>I enjoyed @FutureDocs&amp;lsquo; guide to medical student oral presentations, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share the cheat sheet that I give to the medical students and PA students when I start each teaching block. As she mentioned, presentations always have to be tailored to the listener, and each attending is different, so you&amp;rsquo;ll see minor differences in what I recommend.
To me, the most important aspects are organization and preparation. I don&amp;rsquo;t like to have the sense that the student is &amp;ldquo;winging it&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literature delivered to your inbox</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox/</guid>
      <description>DailyLit.com is an interesting service that takes classic books and chops them up in to bite-sized pieces that you can read in just a few minutes. It then emails you one piece at a time until you finish the book. You can customize how often you get the emails.
I just finished &amp;ldquo;The Art of Money Getting&amp;rdquo;, by P.T. Barnum. It has a lot of practical advice, and predates (by 100 years) a lot of what you see these days in self-help books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osteoporosis Talk</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/24/osteoporosis-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/24/osteoporosis-talk/</guid>
      <description>I gave the residents a talk on osteoporosis at noon conference on Friday. Here&amp;rsquo;s the powerpoint slides that I created, in case they might be useful to anyone. They&amp;rsquo;re licensed under a Creative Commons license and available in 2 formats - ODP (good) and PPT (bad).
Medical information changes constantly, so hopefully these will be useful until at least the end of 2006. I&amp;rsquo;ve also uploaded slides from previous talks on Abnormal Liver Function Tests and Adult Immunizations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>