<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: html | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/html/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-08T21:58:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML5 Up and Running]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/08/25/html5-up-and-running"/>
    <updated>2010-08-25T14:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/08/25/html5-up-and-running</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I preordered Mark Pilgrim's <a href="http://www.amazon.com/HTML5-Up-Running-Mark-Pilgrim/dp/0596806027?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=diveintomark-20&amp;creativeASIN=0596806027">HTML5, Up and Running</a> from Amazon back in
March. It's available for free as <a href="http://diveintohtml5.org/">Dive into
HTML5</a>. I've been a fan of Mark's <a href="http://diveintomark.org">writing</a>
for a while, so buying the book was a way to thank him "with a
buck". Interestingly, the online book and paper book are not
identical. For starters, the titles are different. In addition, the
beautiful fonts and cutesy images of the online version are gone. The
paper book is your run-of-the-mill O'Reilly book. I'm not sure if
it'll make much of a difference in my enjoyment, but we'll see.</p>

<p>As I said, I preordered the book in March, so I had no idea when it
would be finished and delivered. It showed up on my doorstep this
morning, on my birthday! We're on our way to NYC tomorrow for our
first trip back there since we moved to North Carolina in 2007, so I
know have some light pleasure reading. Perfect Timing!</p>

<p>I've only read the first chapter so far, but I think I'm going to love
it. I've done a lot of web programming in my life, but only maintain
my own sites now. I'm reading this book like a programmer might read a
book on astronomy... purely for the love of it. The first chapter goes
into the details of how the <code>IMG</code> tag was invented. Marc Andreessen
mentioned it on a mailing list back in 1993, and after some back and
forth, shipped it in Mosaic, an early browser. Because it shipped and
because it was popular, it got included in the HTML standards.</p>

<p>I still remember when Mosaic came out. I got my first email address in
1992 (vkurup@macc.wisc.edu) and somehow was on a mailing list
announcing the impending release of Mosaic. I remember the text of the
email basically saying that "This will change the world." Once I saw
it, I thought it was cool, but way over-hyped. Who is going to want to
wait for pictures to download over a 14.4K modem? Ridiculous. This is
why you should not take my advice about new trends.</p>

<p>Anyway, the point of the <code>IMG</code> example is to show that HTML standards
have never been "pure", but have always been influenced by the
implementers and the users of the web. The way it should be. HTML5 is
an acknowledgment of that fact.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
