<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>writing on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in writing on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 14:45:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing paralysis</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/15/writing-paralysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 14:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/15/writing-paralysis/</guid>
      <description>I think twitter and facebook stunt my writing. The more that I read tweets, the more self-conscious I get when I write. Not that my writing is all that original, but I still feel that it is something that comes from me. I worry so much about presenting ideas of others as my own without even remembering that I had seen the ideas before. In the old days, the things that I read were long form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Again</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/03/blogging-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 14:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/03/blogging-again/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to start blogging more. I know I&amp;rsquo;ve said that before, so take it for what it&amp;rsquo;s worth. I think there is value in blogging. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about my life a lot lately, trying to find what makes me tick. One of those things that gets me excited is programming. I started thinking about that and remembered this meme that had passed around the blog world a few years back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running as a metaphor for life</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/09/running-as-a-metaphor-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 20:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/09/running-as-a-metaphor-for-life/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking the other day, on a run, of course, about the many ways that running is a metaphor for life. I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed some of this before with my cousins Dilu and Harish before.
 &amp;hellip; two roads diverged in a wood, and I &amp;ndash;
I took the one less traveled by,
And that has made all the difference.
 While trail running, I have come to the realization that you never have to worry about the fork in the road, nor the decision associated with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice on writing</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/04/advice-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/04/advice-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>I just found this great article on writing by Sebastian Marshall. His basic advice boils down to &amp;ldquo;just do it!&amp;rdquo;, but he makes some interesting points along the way. I had never heard of the Equal-Odds rule. Read more details at his blog, but basically, in order to do great work, you have to do a lot of &amp;ldquo;not-great&amp;rdquo; work. No one just does great work. So, let go and just write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Anti-Writing Cycle</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/27/my-anti-writing-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/27/my-anti-writing-cycle/</guid>
      <description>I blogged daily for a 6 day stretch a couple weeks ago, which is the longest continuous stretch I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done. It was stimulating and stressful at the same time. I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard from the Pulitzer committee about any of the posts yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s not the quality that matters. Writing is more about the process than the product, and I know from experience that writing helps me think. And while most of the posts were written for my own benefit, I really enjoyed the response that I got from family and friends about Playdoh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting again</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/13/starting-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/13/starting-again/</guid>
      <description>For the remaining 2 readers of kurup.org (one of them being me), let me apologize for the lack of posts here over the past couple years. I have always meant to write more, but most of my writing seems to consist of apologies for not writing, short bursts of writing, and then long stretches of inactivity. We are nearing the end of a long stretch of inactivity now, so it&amp;rsquo;s time for the apologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT&#39;s guide to writing</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/mits-guide-to-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/mits-guide-to-writing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to become a better writer. In order to become a better writer, you simply have to write more. Funny how most things are like that. Still, sometimes you want a little more structure. MIT has a nice guide to writing that is both simple and useful. Start out by making your document writer-centric. Just get the words down on paper. Satisfy only yourself. Then, revise your writing to make it reader-centric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Medicine</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/24/open-source-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/24/open-source-medicine/</guid>
      <description>I wrote up a little intro piece on the use of open source software in medical applications (PDF). HTML below&amp;hellip;
Improving the communication of patient information is the key to improving healthcare quality and efficiency. In most health care organizations, written records are the main conduit of this information, yet they are notoriously illegible and difficult to browse. Reviewing past problems and past interventions is time-consuming, if not impossible. The record is used mostly as a one-way device for the clinician to record data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>