<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: asd | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/asd/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-30T21:57:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ASD]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/08/01/asd"/>
    <updated>2003-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/08/01/asd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A young guy came in as a walk-in with some mild shortness of breath on exertion and associated chest pain. He was the last patient that I saw during a long, busy day and his symptoms were very mild. I was thinking that maybe he had mild asthma or a respiratory infection, but he didn't look sick at all. Then I listened to his heart. A loud holosystolic murmur throughout with a fixed split S2. Wait, wait. I know this one.... (sounds of my mind clunking along) ASD - <a href="http://www.heartpoint.com/congasd.html">Atrial Septal Defect</a> (<a href="http://www.ucsfhealth.org/childrens/medical_services/heart_center/congenital/conditions/atrial/signs.html">Patient Information</a>).</p>

<p>He had his echocardiogram today which confirmed that he had a large ASD (We don't need no stinking echo!). He'll be going to Bellevue for repair and most likely will do very well. I explained everything to him (in Spanish "un agujero in su coraz&oacute;n"). It's times like these that make me glad that I get to do what I do.</p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>ASD Repair</b></p>
<p>
Nice pick up!  Are they going to close it percutaneously (i.e. in the
cath lab?)
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Girish Nair</span>
<span class="date">2003-08-08 14:58:30</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="my-comment">
<p><b>Good question</b></p>
<p>
Unfortunately, we don't have a cath lab here at Metropolitan, so all
of our cards stuff goes to Bellevue, which is kinda like a black
box. Hopefully he'll follow-up soon and with a lot of luck, he may
even come with a procedure report :-)
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Vinod Kurup</span>
<span class="date">2003-08-08 19:17:04</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
