<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apple | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-31T20:09:28-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[R.I.P.]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2002/09/22/rip"/>
    <updated>2002-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2002/09/22/rip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bad news! My Powerbook G3 went kaput yesterday. After a day or so of
troubleshooting, I'm blaming it on a dead Power Management Unit. I
bought it used in 1999 and have been using it <em>heavily</em> since. It's
lived in 7 apartments with me (yup, 7!) from Boston to Green Bay to
Minneapolis to Boston (again!) and now to NYC. I still think that 4-5
years is way too short a lifespan for a computer, especially since it
was meeting my needs in every other way. But, alas, that's life in
these days of planned obsolescence.</p>

<p>Anyway, the really bad news is that I stored <em>everything</em> on that
computer. I'm hoping that my diagnosis above is correct and that the
hard drive is unharmed, but we'll find out soon. If not, I'll have
lost lots and lots of stuff...</p>

<p>I'm replacing it with an <a href="http://www.apple.com/emac/">eMac</a>. It has a
700 Mhz G4, a combo drive (CDRW,DVDROM) and a 17" screen. I came
<em>this</em> close to making an impulse purchase at the Apple Store in Soho
when I saw the 17" iMac, but my brother was able to talk me down :-)
The iMac is real pretty, but the eMac has everything that I need at
almost half the price ($1049 vs $1999). I did end up making one
impulse buy though - an iPod. But, I blame that on
<a href="http://badgertronics.com/blog">MarkD</a> since he slyly let me use his
while he was visiting last weekend. I have no question that he's
getting a kickback somehow :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Airport Conspiracy?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2001/09/18/airport-conspiracy"/>
    <updated>2001-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2001/09/18/airport-conspiracy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My allegiance to Apple is wavering. I came home to find my home
wireless network down. I walked over to my Apple Airport Basestation
and saw that instead of emitting reassuring green lights, it was
alternating between lighting the left red light and then all three
amber lights. I searched on apple's website for troubleshooting
information without any luck. Finally, (thanks again to Google) I
found these 3 reports of Basestations that had bit the dust shortly
after warranty expiration:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.vonwentzel.net/ABS/index.html">The first casualty</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.oreillynet.com/cs/weblog/view/wlg/423?x-showcontent=text">O'Reilly Report</a></li>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20010819213120/www.mykoh.com/blog/2001_03_01_archive.php">Another one</a> - Dead link</li>
</ul>


<p>Mine failed 15 months after it's arrival on my doorstep. Conspiracy?</p>

<p>Anyway, it served me well for 15 months, but I decided to go with the
<a href="http://www.applelinks.com/reviews/barricade.shtml">SMC Barricade Wireless Broadband
Router</a> for my next
basestation. It has 3 wired ports, acts as a print server and has a
greater range (although that's not really too important in my shoebox
here). It'll be here sometime next week.</p>

<p>So I've gone from having rock-solid wireless access to a lightning
fast cable internet connection 2 months ago to a wired connection to a
56K dialup modem today. I can see the internet gods up there laughing
at me :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
