<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>motivation on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in motivation on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice on writing</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/04/advice-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/04/advice-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>I just found this great article on writing by Sebastian Marshall. His basic advice boils down to &amp;ldquo;just do it!&amp;rdquo;, but he makes some interesting points along the way. I had never heard of the Equal-Odds rule. Read more details at his blog, but basically, in order to do great work, you have to do a lot of &amp;ldquo;not-great&amp;rdquo; work. No one just does great work. So, let go and just write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running slow</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/22/running-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/22/running-slow/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a runner for a long time. I started running in junior high school, so I could be on the track team. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few long stretches where I didn&amp;rsquo;t run, but for most of the past 25 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a runner.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the 2005 New York Marathon though, that I really felt like a runner. I had already run 2 marathons, but I had walked a lot in both of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flow</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/23/flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/23/flow/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found some old journal entries lying around my hard drive. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that these were meant to be cleaned up and edited before being spewed on the Internet, but in keeping with my newfound obsession with Imperfection, I now present them to you, my dear reader(s). Here is the first one, a review of the book, Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience
Bronx, NY, April 9th, 2007
I finished &amp;ldquo;Flow, The Psychology of Optimal Experience&amp;rdquo; by Mihaly Csikszenthmihalyi on the subway ride into work today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperfection</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/02/04/imperfection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/02/04/imperfection/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of great plans which I&amp;rsquo;ve never fulfilled. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. My life is beyond great and I see it getting better every day. There just happen to be a lot of things that I&amp;rsquo;ve planned to do which I have not done.
I planned to create a web-based running log. I actually did do this and used it for a long time, but I never did build in enough features to make it worthwhile for others to use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>