<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Google, M.D.</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/27/google-m.d./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/27/google-m.d./</guid>
      <description>I remember telling people at a dinner party that I often entered symptoms into Google to help me diagnose patients. I remember them being apalled.
Turns out that Google is pretty accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>finance.google.com</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/21/finance.google.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/21/finance.google.com/</guid>
      <description>Google just launched it&amp;rsquo;s new financial website, finance.google.com. It combines a lot of information in 1 page and the adjustable graph at the top of a stock&amp;rsquo;s page is just WAY cool. You can focus in on any period of time and see news &amp;amp; reports from that period. They&amp;rsquo;ve also added blog posts as a news source.
It&amp;rsquo;s the ideal place to get a quick snapshot of a stock. Lots of information in a very quick-loading page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Zeitgeist</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/google-zeitgeist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/google-zeitgeist/</guid>
      <description>Every year, Google does an analysis of search queries over the past year. They call it the Google Zeitgeist. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how &amp;lsquo;what we search for&amp;rsquo; is a very accurate historical record of our times. The Apple iPod takes up 4 of the top 10 searches on Froogle, Google&amp;rsquo;s consumer search engine.
If you liked Zeitgeist, you can monitor weekly updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Ads only for googlers</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/google-ads-only-for-googlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/google-ads-only-for-googlers/</guid>
      <description>I saw this great idea over at this place called Raganwald. Only show ads to visitors who come in from search engines. I really don&amp;rsquo;t want friends and family to see ads, so this effectively shields them since they will probably come here by typing kurup.org in the address bar or using a bookmark.
You&amp;rsquo;re welcome :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Pedometer</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/05/google-pedometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/05/google-pedometer/</guid>
      <description>I admit it. As a runner, I&amp;rsquo;m obsessive about my mileage. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I&amp;rsquo;m obsessive about running and getting my mileage in. That would be a good thing. Once I do go for a run, I&amp;rsquo;m obsessive about knowing exactly how far I&amp;rsquo;ve run.
In high school, I&amp;rsquo;d finish my run and then promptly jump on my 10-speed bike which had an odometer, so I could measure how far I&amp;rsquo;d gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Maps</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/08/google-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/08/google-maps/</guid>
      <description>Wow Google Maps is really cool. You can drag the maps around. How cool is that? Put in a location, then drag the map so that the location that you put in is just off the map. Then click the little red signpost on the right hand column and google rescrolls so that your location is back on the map. Very nice!
Read more at the Google Maps Tour.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>