<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: book-review | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/book-review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-08T21:58:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on Free Will]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/08/21/thoughts-on-free-will"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T12:01:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/08/21/thoughts-on-free-will</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time for some pop philosophy. I've never thought too deeply about the
concept of free will. Of course we have free will! I chose to live my
life a certain way. I could choose to live a different way. It is my
free will to choose how I live. I've never thought about it more
deeply than that.</p>

<p>I recently read Walter Isaacson's biography of Einstein and I was
forced to think more deeply about free will. The biography is
excellent. It gives more depth to Einstein, who, despite his flaws, is
still a heroic figure. One day, I'll do a proper review, but the piece
that struck me the hardest was Einstein's views on free will. He
didn't believe that free will existed, and not only that, he didn't
even to seem to think that this was a controversial position. It
appears that Isaacson didn't either, because he didn't spend much time
on that part of Einstein's character. But, it seemed so strange to me,
since I assumed that we all have free will.</p>

<p>So, I read Sam Harris's e-book
<a href="http://www.samharris.org/free-will">Free Will</a>, in which he concisely
explains why free will is a myth. Take any conscious decision that you
might make. Let's say you choose at this moment to go eat a pizza. Do
you have the free will to make that choice? Well, you certainly can go
eat pizza, but the question is if you had the free will to do it. What
were the steps that led to making that choice. Somewhere in your
brain, a certain set of neurons fired to trigger the idea in your mind
to have a pizza. How did those neurons fire? Either there was a
conscious decision to have that thought, or it was an unconscious
decision that you didn't control. And if it was a conscious decision,
then you can take that back a step further and ask how that decision
occurred. Eventually, you will have to start at some unconscious (or
subconscious) event which triggered the series of events which
eventually led to your decision to have a pizza. No matter how far
back you can track the conscious trail that led to a pizza forming in
your mind, eventually you are left with an unconscious starting point.
Certainly all of these thoughts are heavily influenced by your life
experiences. If you've never seen or heard of a pizza, there's a zero
percent chance that you'll think of a eating a pizza. But all of those
life experiences are themselves the result of conscious and
unconscious decisions, all of which we ultimately have no specific
control over.</p>

<p>Every thought you have is the only thought you could have at that
moment. It is the result of all of the life experiences and thoughts
that you have had up to that moment. If you consciously try to
"create" an original thought, just to prove that you have free will,
well... you can't. Because that decision itself originated from
somewhere in your subconscious, and is therefore something that you
don't have conscious control over.</p>

<p>In addition to this theoretical rationalization against the concept of
free will, Harris describes multiple studies from neuroscience
which show that neurons fire in our subconscious well before we
develop the urge to act. Examples:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://brain.oxfordjournals.org/content/106/3/623.short">The famous Libet Experiment from 1983</a></li>
<li><a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1749-6632.2011.05994.x/full#ss4">Decoding and predicting
intentions</a>.
Skip to the the short section titled 'Implications for the free-will debate?'</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0896627310010822">Internally Generated Preactivation of Single Neurons in Human
Medial Frontal Cortex Predicts
Volition</a>.
The neuroscience in this article is pretty deep. I only watched the
video abstract.</li>
</ul>


<p>Bottom line: I'm convinced that I don't have the free will that I
thought I did. The question is how this should affect my life. It
could be depressing. If every thought of mine originates in a way that
I don't control, then am I just being steered through life? It makes
my accomplishments in life seem less "worthy". On the other hand, it
can be quite freeing. My path through life is determined. Perhaps I
shouldn't be worrying so much about every decision, because I know
that they're not really "my" decisions to make. It can also give you
more empathy for others, knowing that they also have no will do
anything but what they are doing.</p>

<p>It's still a confusing topic, because I "feel" like I have options in
life and I "feel" like taking different options will change my life.
That part is true. The part that isn't true is that I have any control
over the range of available options, nor over the specific option that
I choose. Even Harris seems to be a little conflicted here:</p>

<blockquote><p>Losing a belief in free will has not made me fatalistic—in fact, it has increased my feelings of freedom. My hopes, fears, and neuroses seem less personal and indelible. There is no telling how much I might change in the future. Just as one wouldn’t draw a lasting conclusion about oneself on the basis of a brief experience of indigestion, one needn’t do so on the basis of how one has thought or behaved for vast stretches of time in the past. A creative change of inputs to the system—learning new skills, forming new relationships, adopting new habits of attention—may radically transform one’s life.</p></blockquote>

<p>The question is how do you accomplish a 'creative change of inputs',
if you don't have the will to do so? I guess the idea is that while I
don't have any control over the thoughts that arise in my brain, I do
have perceived control over my decisions. With whatever power my
conscious brain has, I can choose things that will improve my life,
with the hope that exposure to new experiences will 'change the
inputs' to my subconscious brain. Ugh, just thinking about how this
all works makes my brain hurt. I guess this is why I never studied
philosophy before. :-)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.samharris.org/free-will">Free Will</a> is short and cheap and
I highly recommend it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why We Get Fat Review]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/12/why-we-get-fat-review"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T12:44:31-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/12/why-we-get-fat-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear patients,</p>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/whywegetfat.jpg" title="Why We Get Fat" >
I am sorry. I have been giving you bad dietary advice. In medical
school we learned that fat in your diet causes fat to accumulate in
your arteries, causing heart attacks and strokes, so I told you to eat
a low fat diet. Of course, looking back, we had no evidence to support
that conclusion, but it just seemed rather obvious. Obvious ideas are
often the most dangerous ideas of all. When you see a study that
<strong>might</strong> confirm your obvious idea, you give it extra weight. When
you see a study that <strong>might</strong> refute your obvious idea, you find
problems with the study. When the idea is less certain, then you tend
to give the empirical evidence more weight. This is what we've done
with the hypothesis that dietary fat causes heart disease.</p>

<p>I just finished Gary Taubes' "<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307272702/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=vinodkurupshomep&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369&amp;creativeASIN=0307272702">Why We Get
Fat</a>. It's
not a perfect book, but I do recommend it. He dispels myths about why
obesity occurs, explains what really causes it, and discusses why our
current medical and public health approaches to obesity are hurting
rather than helping. He starts out by dispelling the myth that obesity
is caused by an imbalance of "Calories In" versus "Calories Out", and
more specifically, that obesity can be fixed by reversing that
imbalance. This is something I certainly believed. I've always told
patients to eat less and exercise more. <a href="/blog/2006/10/23/health-at-every-size/">It doesn't
work.</a> Instead of calorie
imbalance causing obesity, he states that obesity (and growth in
general) <strong>causes</strong> a calorie imbalance. The increased amount of fat
cells require more energy for sustenance, and therefore our bodies
find a way to increase the amount of calories that we take in,
compared to what we expend. So, while it is true that taking in more
calories than you expend causes your weight to go up, it is not true
that you have much control over your calorie intake or
expenditure. That's determined by hormones. This is the part that is
counter-intuitive. It would seem that I could control the amount of
calories that I eat or that I spend. You might have some control over
what foods you put in your mouth, buy you have no control over how the
calories are extracted or absorbed. You also have no control over the
lower level hormonal signals that make you hungry. Those signals have
evolved over millions of years to be very powerful because in
prehistoric periods, if they didn't work, you died. It's hard to
overcome that kind of evolutionary power with "willpower". Even if you
are successful in decreasing the calories that you eat, your body will
naturally decrease the calories that you burn. The variables are
dependent on each other.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='The villain is carbs.'>
This leads to the next question: Why do we get obese? If it's not a
simple matter of eating more calories than we expend, then why do we
get fat? The culprit is insulin. Insulin causes the cells of our body
to deposit fat. Insulin, in turn, is released whenever there is
glucose in our system, which is preferentially caused by carbohydrate
intake. The villain is carbs. Taubes goes into great detail about
the workings of the endocrine system, explaining why insulin is such a
powerful factor in causing fat deposition. It also explains the
phenomenon of why people who have plenty of fat still get so
ravenously hungry. Insulin prevents fat from being turned into energy
so muscle cells have to use carbohydrates, a much smaller pool of
energy. Once it runs out, intense hunger sets in and the eating cycle
starts again. Reading these chapters took me back to my med school
physiology courses. I learned all of this in med school, but we were
never taught to connect these well accepted facts with the things that
we were being taught in our dietary lectures.
</span></p>

<p>Eliminating carbs from our diet without restricting any other nutrient
will stop the fat deposition process, which in turn will decrease our
calorie requirements, which will cause us to lose weight. There is
quite a bit of genetic variation from person to person, so some
individuals will be able to tolerate more carbs than others, and not
everyone will be completely lean even without any carbs.</p>

<p>He spends a lot of time going over the history of dietary research
dating back centuries. The danger of carbs was well understood and
accepted in all scientific and nonscientific circles until the last 50
years or so, when there was a change that attributed obesity to
behavioral weakness. This was started by the acceptance of the calorie
imbalance hypothesis. Once people accepted the thinking that taking in
more calories than you expend causes obesity, it was a short step to
blaming obesity on the individual for not controlling their diet or
exercising more. The focus of scientific research was taken off of fat
deposition and on to behavioral changes.</p>

<p>I had been coming around to this conclusion slowly over the past few
years (and am embarrassed that it has taken me this long). I remember
reading about the Atkins Diet about 10 years ago and thinking how
reckless Dr. Atkins was being by suggesting something which was so
obviously wrong. My thinking started to change a few years back when I
saw Mala struggle to lose weight despite strictly following an 800
calorie diet. I didn't think that kind of calorie restriction was
possible, but I watched with my own eyes as she did it and still
barely saw results. That opened my eyes, and over the past few years,
I've seen more and more results with low carb diets. Results which
include weight loss, better cholesterol profiles, and overall better
health. Interestingly, the diet recommendations that are provided in
the book are from <a href="http://www.dukehealth.org/physicians/eric_c_westman">Eric Westman,
MD</a>, a UW trained
physician who works just down the street from me.</p>

<p>Mala and I have been trying to get healthier over the past 8
months. My brother started a Biggest Loser competition amongst a bunch
of us, and Mala won the first season. We've been exercising with more
regularity and eating better. Together, we've lost over 80 lbs. To
complicate the points that I've been making in this post, we have
<strong>NOT</strong> been following a strict low carb diet, and we <strong>have</strong> been
counting calories. On the other hand, I'm certain we're eating less
carbs than we did before. But Mala's focus has been on making
delicious (gourmet!) fresh food using "real food" ingredients. She's
tried to cut processed food completely out of our diet. I think that
makes a huge difference. We're not meant to eat chemicals and we have
no idea what these chemicals are doing to us. Optimizing food for
specific criteria, whether that's low-fat, low-carb, or whatever, is
bound to have unintended consequences. In that vein, I agree with
Michael Pollan's recommendation to "Eat Real Food".</p>

<p>At some point, I'd like to review all the science behind the
conclusions in Taubes' book, just so I can have a better understanding
for myself. I recommend that anyone treating patients (nurses,
doctors, nutritionists, trainers) or anyone trying to get healthier
read this book.</p>

<p>Some other much more entertaining and useful links:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.latestinpaleo.com/">Latest in Paleo podcast</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.westonaprice.org/">Weston A. Price Foundation</a></li>
<li><a href="http://hivelogic.com/articles/the-paleo-diet-a-link-primer/">Paleo Diet: Link Primer</a></li>
<li><a href="http://radio.theheart.org/bob-harrington-show/2010/12/10/31-atkins-diet-obesity-and-cardiovascular-disease-risk-with-dr-eric-westman">Great podcast episode by 2 Duke docs</a> - theheart.org</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anything You Want Review]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/07/04/anything-you-want-review"/>
    <updated>2011-07-04T21:12:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/07/04/anything-you-want-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://t.co/rdADtHa"><img class="inset right" src="http://ws.assoc-amazon.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&Format=_SL160_&ASIN=1936719118&MarketPlace=US&ID=AsinImage&WS=1&tag=vinodkurupshomep&ServiceVersion=20070822" ></a>
<img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=&l=as2&o=1&a=1936719118&camp=217145&creative=399373" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></p>

<p>I don't know why I keep reading books about entrepreneurship. I like
the idea of building a business, having passion for something, and
most importantly, living life on your own terms. I just <a href="/blog/2010/11/07/growing-a-business">don't think
I'm cut out for it</a>. But see if
that will stop me from devouring <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com">Hacker
News</a>, <a href="http://mixergy.com">startup
podcasts</a> and books like <a href="http://sivers.org">Derek Sivers'</a> <a href="http://t.co/rdADtHa">Anything
You
Want</a>.</p>

<p>Derek was a musician who started selling his own CDs online in the
days before Paypal. He agreed to help a friend by selling his friend's
CDs as well, and eventually CD Baby was born. He built it into a
successful business and sold it for $22 million. This book is a set of
stories of how that happened. An <a href="http://onstartups.com/tabid/3339/bid/57644/Anything-You-Want-21-Inspiring-Ideas-From-Derek-Sivers.aspx">excellent bullet point
summary</a>
of the book is available. This short book was filled with interesting
advice and stories, but here's my main takeaways.</p>

<h3>Focus on helping people</h3>

<p>It would seem like the way to build a successful business would be to
focus on things like profits, or markets, or costs, but Derek says to
ignore all that and focus on helping people. He started by helping out
a fellow musician, and he made sure that every decision he made was in
the name of helping independent musicians. If big labels asked to be
added to CD Baby, he said no. If people recommended placing ads on his
site, he said no. If a business offered some kind of big money
partnership which required him to change the way he ran his business,
he said no. Find someone you can help and provide enough value to that
person to make them happy to pay you for the help and you will have a
successful business.</p>

<h3>Make something perfect, not big</h3>

<blockquote><p>So, I thought that by taking an unrealistically utopian approach, I could keep the business from growing too much. Instead of trying to make it big, I was going to make it small. It was the opposite of ambition, so I had to think in a way that was the opposite of ambitious.</p>

<p>The key point is that I wasn't trying to make a big business. I was just daydreaming about how one little thing would look in a perfect world.</p></blockquote>

<p>Derek actively tried to keep his business from growing. At some point,
he was making enough money that he felt the growth of the business
would only create more headaches for him. Instead of trying to get
more business, he would try to make his current business
perfect. Focus on ways to make the business run the way you want the
world to work. Build your utopia. If you are always focused on growing
the business, you eventually have to make compromises between what
your current customers want and what "potential" customers want. But,
if your current customers are the ones who you're passionate about
serving, then making their experience even better will paradoxically
bring growth, while also making your life as a business owner more
fulfilling.</p>

<h3>This book is not about business</h3>

<blockquote><p>It's important to know in advance, to make sure you're staying focused on what's honestly important to you, instead of doing what others think you should.</p></blockquote>

<p>It's really a book about life. Focus on helping people and good things
will happen to you. Figure out what makes you tick, what makes you
happy, and what drains you. Adjust your life to give you more time to
do what makes you happy and stop doing the things that drain
you. Derek's rule about this is "HELL, YEAH!" or "no". If someone
offers you an opportunity and you don't say "HELL, YEAH!", then say
"no". Don't go halfway. Do things that you love. (His actual rule is a
little more 'explicit', as he describes in this
<a href="http://mixergy.com/derek-sivers-blog-interview/">podcast</a>)</p>

<h3>A few other quotes that I loved</h3>

<br>


<h5>Getting things done isn't the only goal</h5>

<blockquote><p>[Other people] assume the only reason we do anything is to get it done, and doing it yourself is not the most efficient way. But that's forgetting about the joy of learning and doing.</p></blockquote>

<h5>Know thyself</h5>

<blockquote><p>Just pay close attention to what excites you and what drains you. Pay close attention to when you're being the real you and when you're trying to impress the invisible jury.</p></blockquote>

<h5>Unexpected twist</h5>

<blockquote><p>So I considered firing everyone and hiring a whole new crew. ... I never saw or spoke to my employees again. Never saw the office again.</p></blockquote>

<p>Wasn't expecting to read that. Thought that he would find a way to
patch things up, but stuff like this happens in the real world.</p>

<h3>How to do customer service</h3>

<p>This wasn't from the book, but was in a <a href="http://mixergy.com/derek-sivers-blog-interview/">great Mixergy
interview</a> that I
heard after finishing the book. He describes his customer service
philosophy as the <strong>Mick Jagger philosophy</strong>. Pretend that every customer
service request you get is from Mick Jagger. (Assuming your company is
in the music business). If someone emails you a request about how they
can't access a PDF file on your site, that might seem like an annoying
complaint. But if you pretend that it's coming from Mick Jagger, you'd
respond "Wow, thanks for emailing me. Here, let me just get that PDF
for you and attach it to this email. Again, please let me know if
there's anything else I can do for you!" And if that is heartfelt,
customers will love you.</p>

<h3>Bottom line</h3>

<p>I enjoyed this book. It's a quick read, it's cheap (I read the Kindle
version on my Android tablet for $7.99) and it's inspirational. I
<a href="http://t.co/rdADtHa">recommend it</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Android Review]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/05/08/learning-android-review"/>
    <updated>2011-05-08T22:10:19-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/05/08/learning-android-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://amzn.to/m8SK61"><img class="inset right" src="https://www.kurup.org/images/learning-android.jpg" /></a></p>

<p>I recently finished reading <a href="http://amzn.to/m8SK61">Learning
Android</a>. I have a Droid X, Mala has a Droid
Eris, and I just bought a Viewsonic g-tablet, so I have plenty of
Android devices. While I still have trouble with the idea of typing on
a touchscreen, I know that we are moving towards a future where mobile
devices are our primary computers. This is not earth
shattering. <a href="http://philip.greenspun.com/business/mobile-phone-as-home-computer">Philip Greenspun mentioned it 5 years
ago</a>. Android
will be <a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/04/25/Mobility">one of the more prominent mobile
OS's</a>
along with iOS, so I want to learn how to program it.</p>

<p>I came into this book having browsed some of the example code on the
<a href="http://developer.android.com/">developer.android.com</a> website. It is
great for an overview, and there is a lot of in-depth information on
APIs, etc., but I still didn't quite understand how to go about
starting an app.</p>

<p>In March, O'Reilly had a sale on e-books, so I bought <a href="http://amzn.to/m8SK61">Learning
Android</a>. It is a reasonable introduction to
Android programming. It's beings gently, explaining the history of
Android and providing a general overview of how the Android stack
works. It's explains how to use the Eclipse IDE, but as a fervent
emacs fan, I was easily able to adjust to using emacs (with
<a href="https://github.com/remvee/android-mode">android-mode.el</a>) for all of
my development. There were typos and minor errors, but fortunately
<a href="http://oreilly.com/catalog/errataunconfirmed.csp?isbn=0636920010883">O'Reilly has an errata
page</a>
where people can post fixes and suggestions. Keep that page open while
you're reading this book. There were a couple areas where the ordering
of the discussion could have been improved. If I didn't have that
errata page at hand, I would have been completely
frustrated. Especially at the beginning, the instructions were not
detailed enough. For example, we are instructed on how to create a
program and how to start the emulator, but there is no clear
explanation on how to run the program on the emulator. A little more
step-by-step hand-holding would have been nice.</p>

<p>In case you ignored my advice to check out that errata page, at least
make sure that you have the updated version of the <a href="http://examples.oreilly.com/0636920010883/README-JTwitter-Library.txt">jTwitter
library</a>,
or else you'll never get the sample programs to run without errors.</p>

<p>I haven't used Java in a while, so I forgot how verbose Java
is. Writing Tcl, Ruby and Python has spoiled me. It takes so long to
do something simple in Java. I know that this is usually offset by
code generators and IDEs, but it still just seems so clunky to read
and write. There is a <a href="http://code.google.com/p/android-scripting/">scripting language project for Android
(SL4A)</a>. I haven't tried
it, but it involves bundling the scripting environment with your app
if you want to distribute it to others. I'm also not certain that it
provides access to all of the functionality provided in the Java SDK.
Someday, I hope that a scripting language SDK is provided. It seems
like a natural progression.</p>

<p>All in all, I think Learning Android is perfect for someone who wants
to get started in Android programming. It gives a nice gentle
introduction to all of the basics of how the platform works. Most of
this information is available on the web in various places, but it's
nice to have it all in one place, and I still think there's value to
having one book that takes you from step zero to a working app. I
think I'll now be able to use the online docs to get me moving. I was
often frustrated by the typos, minor technical errors and
inconsistencies, but I suspect the book was under a lot of time
pressure, given how hot mobile programming is these days. It just felt
like it was written on a rushed deadline. It's also not the most
entertaining book in the world, which is OK for a technical book. I'd
always rather have a boring technical book, than an <em>attempt</em> at an
entertaining one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Growing a Business]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/11/07/growing-a-business"/>
    <updated>2010-11-07T20:31:19-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/11/07/growing-a-business</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read this book in 2005, but never posted this review. So here it
is...</p>

<h2><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0671671642?ie=UTF8&tag=vinodkurupshomep&linkCode=as2&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=0671671642">Growing a Business</a> by Paul Hawken</h2>

<p>This is an honest and practical guide to running a business. I don't
remember where I first heard about this book. Maybe <a href="http://pinds.com">Lars</a>?</p>

<p>It was written in 1987. Hawken talks about building a business. It's
often portrayed as a heroic or glamorous endeavor, but really it's
not. It's a lot of hard work, but also a lot of common sense. He spends a
chapter talking about a quality that you need to be successful in your own
business. He calls it Tradeskill.</p>

<p>It's like intuition, for business. He says its something you can't acquire
easily, except perhaps in childhood. People that were drawn into business
activities at a young age have it. Those that weren't, don't. And no amount
of book-smarts can make up for the lack of Tradeskill. If you're not
comfortable haggling in a flea market, you should think twice about going
into business. Instead, he recommends dipping your feet in the water,
without starting a business yourself. Take a part time job in a business
that you're interested in and try to take on as many roles as possible in
that business.</p>

<p>Another theme in his book is the wisdom of growing slowly. Having too much
money while starting a business is worse than no having enough. It's
something I read a lot now (Arsdigita, Paul Graham, 37Signals), but it's
interesting to see it written way back when as well.</p>

<h3>Things I learned from this book</h3>

<h2>It's probably not for me</h2>

<p>Starting your own business is not for everyone. It takes a temperament that
isn't easily learned. I don't think I have Tradeskill. I'm not going to let
that stop me from learning about business, but I'm going to be a little
more thorough in my planning and preparation if I ever do it.</p>

<h2>The 5-15 report is a good idea</h2>

<p>He mentions something called a 5-15 report. it's a report that every
employee in a company should have to write <strong>every</strong> week. It should take
less than 15 minutes to write and less than 5 minutes to read. Part I is a
progress report for the week, Part II is a report on the morale of the
department and Part III is one idea to make the company better. I like the
idea of a weekly low-commitment progress report.</p>

<h2>Overstaffing is the root of all evil</h2>

<p>A major problem of big business is over-staffing. Once an employee
learns that their work is redundant, or requires little effort, they
realize their job is expendable and that they must spend all their
time preserving their job - through hijacking credit, office politics,
etc. The basic result is that <strong>people hoard information</strong>. Information
that, if freely disseminated, would allow the company to function
better. If I have useful information that other employees don't have,
then I am valuable. Understaffed companies (start-ups) work in the
opposite way. I have enough work as it is, so I'm happy to share
information with you, because perhaps it will allow you to help me out
with my workload. The company becomes more efficient. I see this
effect of over-staffing where I work (although I didn't recognize it
as such until reading this book)</p>

<h3>random quotes / concepts from the book</h3>

<p>Flat management/employee structures are good. Trust the people you work with and
give them wide latitude.</p>

<p>Problems are opportunities - dive into them.</p>

<p>"A good business has interesting problems. A bad business has boring ones." (p. 39)</p>

<p>Have a partner. You shouldn't ever think of going it alone.</p>

<p>"Being in business is not about making money. It is a way to become who you are." (p. 19)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
