<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>postgresql on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/postgresql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in postgresql on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 21:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/postgresql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Autovacuum not running</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/05/30/autovacuum-not-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/05/30/autovacuum-not-running/</guid>
      <description>OK, this is a debug session in progress, so don&amp;rsquo;t expect a nice solution at the end. We&amp;rsquo;re working on a project that does analysis of some public voter registration data. The DB is hosted on Amazon RDS and I&amp;rsquo;ve been perplexed by how poorly queries are performing there, despite the tables only have about 10 million rows. Simple queries are taking many minutes, which is orders of magnitude slower than my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PG 7.2 to 7.3</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/24/pg-7.2-to-7.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/24/pg-7.2-to-7.3/</guid>
      <description>Not all of OpenACS is Postgres 7.3 compliant yet. OpenACS 5 is compliant and the core packages in OpenACS 4.6 are compliant, but some non-core packages haven&amp;rsquo;t been fixed yet. Noncompliant packages will complain:
[24/Jun/2003:15:21:36][26623.196621][-conn:kurup::4] Error: Ns_PgExec: result status: 7 message: ERROR: Function pa_collection__new(&amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;, timestamp with time zone, &amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;) does not exist Unable to identify a function that satisfies the given argument types You may need to add explicit typecasts  It is looking for a function with timestamp with time zone as one of its parameters, but most OpenACS pl/pgsql functions were defined as accepting timestamp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psql doesn&#39;t like tabs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/24/psql-doesnt-like-tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/24/psql-doesnt-like-tabs/</guid>
      <description>psql doesn&amp;rsquo;t deal well with tabs. If you feed it a function that has tabs in it, and then call that function, you&amp;rsquo;ll often get this: ERROR: parser: parse error at or near &amp;quot;for&amp;quot; at character 15. Thus, if you ever see this in your error log, it&amp;rsquo;s time to M-x untabify.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>