<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quarterly on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/quarterly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in quarterly on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/quarterly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Belated Investment Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/03/belated-investment-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/03/belated-investment-update/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s also get caught up with my investments. I last updated in May 2006 when I bought STS, JAX, EEI, KEYN and RSC.
At my next quarterly evaluation in August 2006, I sold DSWL at a loss of 16.7% because I had held it for 2 years and it no longer met my criteria for a stock I would want to buy. I bought SYPR and BSET.
In November 2006, I sold SEMI because it reported a negative quarter on top of negative trailing 12 month earnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update - May 2006</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/11/investment-update-may-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/11/investment-update-may-2006/</guid>
      <description>I sold 3 stocks (OUTL, MRINA.PK and KBALB) and bought 5 (RSC, JAX, EEI, KEYN and STS).
 Sold stocks Purchased Total Return Reason for sell  Outlook Group ([OUTL](http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=OUTL)) Feb 2005 67.65% OUTL is being acquired and taken private at $13.50 per share in a transaction scheduled to close sometime this summer. I decided to sell now at $13.20 rather than wait a few months for an extra 30 cents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing nothing</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/08/doing-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/08/doing-nothing/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time for my quarterly investment update. Every 3 months, I look at my portfolio and sell stocks that I don&amp;rsquo;t like and then buy ones that I do. This quarter, I&amp;rsquo;m doing nothing.
This is one of the hardest things for me to do. I like to trade. Sell a stock here, buy a new one here. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting. Especially when you sell a stock that&amp;rsquo;s been down for a while because then you no longer have to look at that red smirch on your portfolio every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investments: Quarterly Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/01/investments-quarterly-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/01/investments-quarterly-update/</guid>
      <description>DUCK lost money both in its most recent quarter and over the past 12 months, so I sold it. I wish I&amp;rsquo;d been smarter about the way I sold it. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t decided which new stocks to buy yet, so instead of just selling DUCK and sitting in cash, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d using a trailing-stop order. With a regular stop, you tell your broker to sell the stock once the price drops below a certain point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarterly Sells</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/01/quarterly-sells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/01/quarterly-sells/</guid>
      <description>I try to do my portfolio cleanup every 3 months, selling any companies that don&amp;rsquo;t fit my strategy and buying new ones that do. So, I&amp;rsquo;m selling 5 stocks. I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided on my buys yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m looking at BAMM, BZ, CALM, ESP, PWX, SCX and SRT (among others).
   Stock Purchase Date Total Return Reason for sell     Ameron (AMN) 7/7/2004 11.27% No improvement in the financial results over the past year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>