<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blog | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-02T21:54:10-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook is killing blogging]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/08/19/facebook-is-killing-blogging"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T07:58:31-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/08/19/facebook-is-killing-blogging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looks like August 18th was
International-Prominent-Bloggers-Complain-About-Facebook-Killing-Blogging
Day. I was just <a href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/08/03/blogging-again/">two weeks too early</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li>Tim Bray: <a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2012/08/18/Blogodammerung">Blogodammerung</a></li>
<li>Scott Hanselman: <a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/YourWordsAreWasted.aspx">Your words are wasted</a></li>
<li>Jon Udell: <a href="http://blog.jonudell.net/2012/08/10/where-have-all-the-bloggers-gone/">Where have all the bloggers gone?</a></li>
</ul>


<p>On a side note, I'm really enjoying Scott Hanselman's podcast <a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com/">This
Developer's Life</a>. It's an homage to
the awesome <a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org">This American Life</a>, but
focused on programming issues. They interview interesting programmers,
but they carefully edit the interviews to focus on the parts that are
the most interesting, interspersing them with music and effects. It's
really well done.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blogging Again]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/08/03/blogging-again"/>
    <updated>2012-08-03T14:50:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/08/03/blogging-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm going to start blogging more. I know I've said that before, so
take it for what it's worth. I think there is value in blogging. I've
been thinking about my life a lot lately, trying to find what makes me
tick. One of those things that gets me excited is programming. I
started thinking about that and remembered this meme that had passed
around the blog world a few years back. It was a list of questions
related to how you got started programming. I remember it especially
because I remember reading MarkD's version and thinking how similar it
was to my own beginnings. Then, because I love going off on tangents,
I googled for 'How I got started in programming' to read other
responses. Many of the posts I found were on abandoned blogs. And now,
for the 'causal relationship not supported by data' statement. This is
because of Facebook and Twitter. OK, maybe it's just the natural decay
of blogs. But I am concerned about the fact that most people write in
forums that are controlled by other people rather in their own forum.
That was one of the cool promises of the web. A little place of your
own that you controlled. Facebook and Twitter and Google+ are all cool
services, but the more time I spend on them, the less time I spend
here. I'm sure other people have written about this with more
eloquence than I could, but the bottom line is that I want to keep
writing. I want to learn more about myself, I want to teach others
what little I know, and I want to learn from others. I've been
journalling a lot lately and that has been useful, but the act of
hitting 'publish' will make my writing better. That's what this blog
is for and I'm going to start using it again.</p>

<p>Maybe one of these days, I'll even put up my own answers to 'How I Got
Started in Programming', but in the meantime, go read
<a href="http://borkwarellc.wordpress.com/2008/07/01/how-i-got-started-in-programming/">MarkD's</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switching to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/14/switching-to-octopress"/>
    <updated>2011-08-14T13:06:04-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/14/switching-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may have noticed that I've rearranged the furniture a little. It's
been almost 2 years since I last redesigned my blog, so I'm way
overdue for a pointless redesign. I'm now using
<a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> which basically takes
<a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> and adds nice HTML5
templates, cross-browser stylesheets, jekyll plugins, and a few build
scripts to automate common tasks.</p>

<p>Enjoy my new site and let me know if you find any issues. The <a href="https://github.com/vkurup/kurup.org">source
code for my site</a>, as always, is
at github. Please let me know if you have questions about it. I'm also
taking bets on how long this design lasts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Anti-Writing Cycle]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/07/27/my-anti-writing-cycle"/>
    <updated>2010-07-27T21:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/07/27/writers-block</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I blogged daily for a 6 day stretch a couple weeks ago, which is the
longest continuous stretch I've ever done. It was stimulating and stressful
at the same time. I haven't heard from the Pulitzer committee about any of
the posts yet, but it's not the quality that matters. Writing is more about
the process than the product, and I know from experience that writing helps
me think. And while most of the posts were written for my own benefit, I
really enjoyed the response that I got from family and friends about
<a href="/blog/2010/07/15/playdoh">Playdoh</a>. I think I've read that post 100 times
and I still laugh out loud at the end of it. That's the post that started
the stretch off. As soon as I had put Kavi to bed, I knew that I wanted to
share that story. I wrote it down quickly, so I wouldn't forget it. That
writing process stimulated me to want to write more, so I made it an
internal goal to write a post daily.</p>

<p>Then I had two night shifts and the streak was broken. I've had a few days
off, but I still haven't written anything. I'm still learning clojure, but
I fear writing about something that I know nothing about. Even though I've
heard others say that this is the best time to write about a topic. I've
also constructed a vicious cycle in my head. I want to learn clojure. I
want to write about what I learn. I start doing so, but then I skip a day
or so. Now, when I have free time, I think about learning clojure, but then
I also think about the fact that I should write about it. And since I'm
already behind, I don't want to get further behind, so maybe I shouldn't
read that interesting tutorial until I've caught up on writing about what
I've learned. Next thing I know, I'm monitoring Twitter streams
second-by-second for <a href="http://imgur.com">imgur</a> links.</p>

<p>I'm hoping that writing about my mental blocks will help me overcome
them. I plan to write more frequently, mostly for my own benefit, but I'm
not going to let it get in the way of learning cool, interesting stuff. If
my writing is disjointed, so be it. I can fill in the gaps later if anyone
cares.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bye Bye Wordpress]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2009/09/19/bye-bye-wordpress"/>
    <updated>2009-09-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2009/09/19/bye-bye-wordpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This site has undergone another transformation. I've ditched <a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> and am now using a tool called <a href="http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a>. It's a program that runs on my laptop and generates static files from a bunch of templates. I then upload the static files to my server. Wordpress, like any dynamic software, has security risks. Especially since it's such a popular blog app, it's always under attack. I don't have the time or interest to keep up with updates, especially since my blogging is so low-profile. It's just something I do for fun.</p>

<p>Static files have none of those security risks. There are a lot of static file generators out there, but I chose Jekyll because it seemed intuitive and it's run by the <a href="http://github.com">GitHub</a> folks. I've started using git and GitHub and am impressed by their power so far.</p>

<p>This takes me full circle to my post-geocities days when I was generating static pages using <a href="http://frontier.userland.com/">Userland Frontier</a>. This still doesn't feel as satisfying as that did, but maybe that's only because it was such a new thing back then. I must admit that writing posts in emacs sure does feel nice.</p>

<p>Anyway, the design is completely ripped off from <a href="http://mark.reid.name">Mark Reid</a>. My design skills suck, and his rock. Of course, I am a tweaker, so I'll probably end up ruining his beauty at some point.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
