<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: india | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/india/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-09T08:22:17-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[History of Indian Civilization]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2018/05/31/indian-civilization"/>
    <updated>2018-05-31T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2018/05/31/indian-civilization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I briefly mentioned finding the 2012 UCLA lecture series,
"<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93JMjX1XECo&amp;list=PLy3KRgc0HE8B4neta_B8LPM0G9UWy-Cqe">History of Indian Civilization</a>",
a <a href="/blog/2018/05/29/renaissance-man">couple days ago</a>. I'm about halfway through
and have found it thorougly illuminating. I learned a lot about India growing
up, but never in a formal way, so it's nice to have someone as skilled as Vinay
Lal connect all the loose threads into a coherent history. One of the things
that surprises me is that aside from the fact that classes are being streamed
over the internet, there is nothing different than the lectures I skipped (I
mean religiously attended!) about 20 years ago. It's a large auditorium of
students watching a very charismatic, knowledgeable speaker pacing at the front
of the class, occasionally making mostly-legible markings on a chalkboard. Not
that there's anything wrong with that. I learned a lot back in college and I'm
enjoying these lectures immensely. It just seems strange that so little has
changed in the university clasroom (at least this one from 2012) when so much
has changed in the world at large.</p>

<p>Actually, I find it reassuring that little has changed, at least in some
classes. There was a time when the ability to download the audio of any
university class was absolutely new. For me, that was around 2002 or so. I
listened to CS61A (UC Berkley's intro to CS course) and a few other similar
courses back then. The limitations of internet bandwidth and storage made
anything more than audio difficult back then. But now with those barriers
crushed, I was afraid that everything would be "multimedia", and not amenable to
listening while I commute to work. So, it's reassuring to find that audio-only
dissemination of knowledge is still a thing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[India Trip 2006]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/india-trip-2006"/>
    <updated>2006-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/india-trip-2006</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/vaishnodevi.jpg" alt="vaishnodevi" />{: .inset width=580}</p>

<p>I was fortunate to take a <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album%5fid=80449">trip with my in-laws to India</a> last month. I've finally gotten around to uploading the pics, but as I look at them now, they don't quite capture the amount of amazing stuff that we saw. I took about 400 pictures and uploaded 187 here. You'd think 400 pics would adequately capture a trip, but not for a trip to India.</p>

<p>Here are some interesting ones in case you don't want to wade through 15 pages of pics.</p>

<p><img src="/images/jaipur-street.jpg" alt="jaipur street" />{: .inset width=270} <img src="/images/jaipur-dancers.jpg" alt="traditional jaipur dance" />{: .inset width=270} <img src="/images/golden-temple-1.jpg" alt="mom and dad" />{: .inset width=270} <img src="/images/golden-temple-me.jpg" alt="me at golden temple" />{: .inset width=270} <img src="/images/golden-temple-2.jpg" alt="golden temple" />{: .inset width=270} <img src="/images/golden-temple-3.jpg" alt="golden temple at night" />{: .inset width=270} <img src="/images/jallianwala.jpg" alt="jallianwala bagh" />{: .inset width=270} <img src="/images/indopak-border.jpg" alt="india pakistan border" />{: .inset width=270} <img src="/images/indopak-ceremony.jpg" alt="border ceremony" />{: .inset width=270} <img src="/images/ethan-vaishnodevi.jpg" alt="Ethan at Vaishno Devi" />{: .inset width=270}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pics Pics Pics]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/03/23/pics-pics-pics"/>
    <updated>2005-03-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/03/23/pics-pics-pics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been planning to write about my trip to India, but since I'm the biggest procastinator in the world, I have a feeling that might not happen. Suffice it to say that Mala and I had a blast visiting our families and taking in some amazing sights. Thanks to everyone there for taking such great care of us. Without further delay, go look at some photos:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=17859">The India Trip</a></li>
<li><a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=19975">Layover in Amsterdam</a></li>
<li>We got back just in time for the last day of <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=20098">The Gates</a> exhibition</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Israel, a Ban on Indian Wigs; In Brooklyn, a Rush to Comply]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2004/05/14/in-israel-a-ban-on-indian-wigs-in-brooklyn-a-rush-to-comply"/>
    <updated>2004-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2004/05/14/in-israel-a-ban-on-indian-wigs-in-brooklyn-a-rush-to-comply</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Reported in the New York Times: (free registration required)</p>

<blockquote><p>One of the most respected Jewish authorities in the ultra-Orthodox world, Rabbi Yosef Shalom Elyashiv, issued the Indian hair ban from Israel on Wednesday, prompting some people in Israel to create lists of stores selling banned wigs and to burn Indian wigs in bonfires, according to Ha'aretz, an Israeli newspaper.</p></blockquote>

<p>This sounds like a story from the <a href="http://www.theonion.com/">The Onion</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Indian Elections]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2004/05/13/indian-elections"/>
    <updated>2004-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2004/05/13/indian-elections</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>India offshores the prime ministership (link broken).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
