<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: medicine | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/medicine/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-08T22:40:46-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peanut Allergy, a personal clinical review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/21/peanut-allergy-a-personal-clinical-review"/>
    <updated>2013-01-21T07:49:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/21/peanut-allergy-a-personal-clinical-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>A Vignette</h2>

<p>A 22-month-old previously healthy girl was brought to the emergency
room in respiratory distress. She had been well until the day of
presentation. Shortly after disembarking from an airline flight, she
developed cough with one episode of emesis. En route to the emergency
room, her breathing became labored and she developed hives. She was
diagnosed as having an allergic reaction and treated aggressively with
IV methylprednisolone, IV diphenhydramine, inhaled albuterol, and
oxygen. Mechanical ventilation was not required and her symptoms
improved rapidly. She was monitored in the emergency room for an
extended period and discharged in stable condition with a prescription
for diphenhydramine and methylprednisolone solutions. No specific
allergen was identified. She was seen by a pediatric allergist where
she was found to have a 6 mm response to peanut on skin prick testing,
and a peanut-specific IgE level of 52 kU/L. She was diagnosed as
having severe peanut allergy and avoidance was strongly recommended.</p>

<h2>Discussion</h2>

<p>Peanut allergy affects between 0.4 and 2.0% of children. Prevalence
has been increasing in recent years, but the reason for this increase
is not well understood. If reactions are identified immediately,
treatment is usually effective. Despite this, about 200 people die
each year from peanut reactions. Biphasic reactions, in which the
initial reaction subsides, but then recurs within a few hours, are
common. The second portion of a biphasic reaction is often less
treatable. Because of this risk, patients should be monitored for at
least 4 hours after a reaction. Patients who successfully treat their
own reactions with subcutaneous epinephrine should still seek medical
attention, again to monitor for biphasic reactions.</p>

<p>The gold standard for diagnosis is a double blind placebo controlled
food challenge (DBPCFC), but this is rarely done. A diagnosis can
usually be reliably made with clinical history, skin prick testing and
a peanut-specific IgE blood test (psIgE). A skin prick test involves
pricking the skin with a needle that is exposed to peanut extract and
measuring the allergic rash that develops. The psIgE blood test
measures the amount of antibody against peanut proteins. The higher it
is, the more allergic the patient is. A positive skin test or psIgE is
not sufficient for the diagnosis. Some type of reaction to peanuts is
required (either spontaneous, or via monitored food challenge).</p>

<p>Peanut allergy was previously felt to be permanent, but recent
evidence documents that 20% of children outgrow their allergy. More
than 60% of patients with an psIgE level of less than 5 passed a food
challenge. IgE levels correlate inversely with likelihood of
resolution, but this correlation is by no means perfect. Some patients
with undetectable psIgE levels will fail a challenge, while some
patients with very high psIgE levels will pass. One expert recommends
waiting until the age of 4 to consider a challenge, and to use a
cutoff psIgE level of less than 5 kU/L in most patients. Recurrence
of peanut allergy after resolution is rare, but is associated with the
lack of regular peanut intake after resolution of the allergy.</p>

<p>Controversy exists regarding risk factors for developing peanut
allergy. The AAP initially recommended that peanut not be introduced
early in a child's life, but rescinded that advice given the lack of
evidence behind it. This leaves a void for parents as there is no
recommendation to withold or introduce peanuts to toddlers. It is also
not clear if maternal peanut intake during pregnancy or breast feeding
increases the risk of developing peanut allergy in children. Studies
have been conflicting, so more definitive studies are underway. No
evidence-based advice can be given one way or the other to pregnant or
breastfeeding women, but at the minimum, there is no good evidence to
support avoiding peanuts.</p>

<p>The mainstay of treatment is education. Parents should be taught not
only how to identify peanuts in foods, but to identify situations
which are high-risk for exposure to peanuts. Avoidance of buffets,
ice-cream parlors, and bakeries is recommended because the risk of
cross-contamination in those setting is high. Religious reading of
food labels is important. Patients who are allergic to peanuts are
often also allergic to tree nuts, despite the dissimilarity in those
food types. Highly refined peanut oil is usually <em>NOT</em> a risk, but
cold-pressed peanut oil is not safe.</p>

<p>Most importantly, an epi-pen should be carried at all times and extra
doses should be left at daycare facilities and schools. All caregivers
should be comfortable giving an epi-pen injection and this should be
provided at the first sign of a systemic allergic reaction. Waiting to
give diphenhydramine or other therapies a "chance to work" can be
dangerous. Follow a <a href="http://www.foodallergy.org/files/media/food-allergy-action-plan/FAAP.pdf">Food Allergy Action
Plan</a>
Over 80% of people who died from allergic reactions were not given
appropriate instructions on how to prevent future reactions. Most
mortality occurs because of late treatment. If you take one thing away
from this long post, keep an epi-pen handy and use it liberally.</p>

<p>Trials are underway investigating various oral-based immunotherapies,
but none are strongly recommended at this point. Injection
immunotherapy has not been found to be useful.</p>

<h2>Personal Comment</h2>

<p>So, the 22 month old above is Anika and she gave us the scare of our
life a couple years ago. The scary part now is that we never saw her
actually eat a peanut, so we're especially vigilant now. Fortunately,
Anika seems to understand the importance of avoiding peanuts. When she
was diagnosed, I did some research but never documented my notes. She
recently had another allergist appointment, so I reviewed those notes
and any new data. I figured I should write up my notes so I wouldn't
have to review this again from scratch every year. I didn't intend it
to come out so 'medical-speaky', but there it is. Anika and Kavi are
sitting next to me as I write this and they want to give some
information to you, too.</p>

<p>Kavi says:</p>

<blockquote><p>"Always ask at the restaurant if things have peanuts and make foods
at home that do not have peanuts. Always check if there are peanuts in
every food you eat."</p></blockquote>

<p>Anika says:</p>

<blockquote><p>"We might have to go to the doctor if we eat peanuts. If I eat
peanuts by accident, my teacher will give me a Happy-Pen (epi-pen)."</p></blockquote>

<h2>References</h2>

<ol>
<li>Sampson HA. Peanut Allergy. N Engl J Med, 2002;346;1294-8.
http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMcp012667</li>
<li>Fleischer DM, et. al. The natural progression of peanut allergy:
Resolution and the possibility of recurrence. J Allergy Clin
Immunol, 2003;112;183-9.
http://www.jacionline.org/article/S0091-6749(03)01251-X/abstract</li>
<li>O'B Hourihane J. Peanut Allergy. Pediatr Clin N Am, 2011;58;445-57.
http://www.pediatric.theclinics.com/article/S0031-3955(11)00006-X/abstract</li>
<li>Rinaldi M, et. al. Peanut allergy diagnoses among children
residing in Olmstead County, Minnesota. J Allergy Clin Immunol, 2012:130:945-50.</li>
<li>Burks AW. Early peanut consumption: postpone or promote? J Allergy
Clin Immunol. 2009:123:417-423.
http://www.jacionline.org/article/S0091-6749(08)02436-6/fulltext</li>
</ol>


<h2>RSS URL:</h2>

<p>Here's a
<a href="http://eutils.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/eutils/erss.cgi?rss_guid=1t7jLQ--MCbUSbgzXRNqEMLPWIMWlZiqoEMdLvUTNUIFZ-UsA4">medline feed URL</a>
that I monitor which should show new studies or reviews related to
this topic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SHM 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/05/13/shm-2011"/>
    <updated>2011-05-13T05:35:21-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/05/13/shm-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are some (unorganized) thoughts about my experience at the
Society of Hospital Medicine (SHM) 2011 conference in Dallas, TX.</p>

<h3>Opening Plenary</h3>

<p>The initial presentation dissected the SHM Annual Compensation survey,
discussing regional variations in pay and work effort over time. I
understand the importance of that stuff, but ever since I got my first
$638.36 paycheck as an intern, money hasn't been an issue for me.</p>

<p>The second talk was by <a href="http://www.whorunsgov.com/Profiles/Robert_Kocher">Bob
Kocher</a>, an Obama
insider during the recent healthcare reformd. Gerry would have loved
this one. He briefly described how a bill becomes a law... it
apparently doesn't follow the Schoolhouse Rock model anymore. At one
point, reform looked dead, when the Catholic Nuns came out in favor of
the legislation allowing multiple congress members to change their
vote to "Yes". As Kocher put it (paraphrasing), "When the Nuns broke
with the Bishops, healthcare reform could move forward." Doesn't that
seem like a statement that should be in a history book about medieval
times, rather than a statement about 2010 United States politics?
Maybe it's just me...</p>

<h3>Neurologic emergencies</h3>

<p>The Neurologic emergencies talk was entertaining, though maybe more
useful to an intensivist. David Likosky is hilarious in a geeky kind
of way. A few things I learned:</p>

<p>Always maintain a good differential diagnosis and don't jump to a
conclusion too quickly. He described a case of an alcoholic who
presented in coma and had dynamic pupils making a brainstem stroke the
most likely diagnosis. A lot of time was spent to rule that out, and
then his labs came back with a sugar of 13, indicating that the
diagnosis of hypoglycemia was missed. He described some of the reasons
that happened and I can see them happening to me. Never get fixated on
a diagnosis, especially before you've made the proper initial
evaluaation. A fingerstick glucose should always be done in a coma
workup.</p>

<p>A few points on status epilepticus (SE)</p>

<ul>
<li>Convulsive SE is a seizure that lasts more than 5 minutes, and is a medical
emergency.</li>
<li>Lorazepam is probably better than Diazepam and don't be
afraid to use high doses (Start at 4 IV). We commonly underdose and
underdosing hurts.</li>
<li>Nonconvulsive SE is considered as a medical urgency. A lot of
patients have SE on EEG after convulsions have stopped and many have
persistent subclinical seizures after SE is controlled. So, repeat the
EEG, and consider transfer to a center that can do continuous EEG monitoring.</li>
<li>Absence seizures is really a diagnosis of children. (Not really
about SE, but interesting)</li>
</ul>


<p>Things to make you think that a CVA may be posterior circulation: Loss
of consciousness, pupillary abnormalities, superhigh BP. Allow it to
stay superhigh and keep the patient flat. Because posterior
circulation strokes have such bad outcomes, it's OK to intervene after
the normal time window if there doesn't seem to be any other hope.</p>

<h3>Dermatology images (Paul Aronowitz)</h3>

<p>When approaching a rash, ask 3 questions: Did the patient cause this
rash? Did we do that to the patient? (Ask this twice). Is this rash a
manifestation of some other disease? We often jump to the third
question, but should consider the first two.</p>

<p>The snake bite risk factors are pretty interesting:
- Male
- Age 17-27
- Deliberate attempt to handle, harm or kill snake
- Summer months
- Alcohol intoxication
- Tattoos</p>

<p>DRESS (Drug reaction with eosinophilia and systemic symptoms) usually
occurs 2-6 weeks after the drug is started, but occurs quicker after
rechallenge with the drug.</p>

<p>Reactive arthritis can be seen after Clostridium difficile infections.</p>

<p>20% of cases of Neisseria meningitidis do not have meningitis.</p>

<h3>Poster presentations</h3>

<p>The poster presentations are always fun to read, though if I see one
more poster about the readmission problem, I will vomit.</p>

<h3>Research Abstract Awards</h3>

<p>The winning research abstracts were very interesting.</p>

<ul>
<li>UCSF described changes that they made to meet new ACGME requirements
while decreasing costs and improving certain quality measures.</li>
<li><p>Johns Hopkins hospitalists modified their CPOE system to show the
costs of specific lab tests, hoping to change provider behavior. They
were able to show that providers ordered less tests when they saw the
cost. Duh, you say, but there is so little cost information available
to providers, so this is innovative if only for that reason.</p></li>
<li><p>Hospitalists (in Colorado, I think?) used the Toyota Production
System to model problems with current intern work schedules. They then
reworked the schedule to minimize waste of resident resources, while
improving continuity and resident satisfaction. They were able to
basically eliminate moonlighter and jeopardy use. I didn't understand
the schedule because it was presented quickly, but I like the idea of
taking a nonmedical thought approach and applying it to medicine. I
also like that they optimized for continuity of care, so that after
the intervention there was a huge increase in the amount of patients
that were seen only by 1 intern during their stay. Very interesting!</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>SHM promotion</h3>

<p>My attention faded during the award presentations and SHM motivational
speeches, but Joseph Li, the incoming SHM president, did come clean
and acknowledge that he was born outside the U.S., despite his lack of
an accent. The birthers were right!</p>

<h3>Geographic rounding</h3>

<p>Emory Hospitalists then presented a talk which was titled 'Utilizing
Technology to Improve Clinical and Operational Performance of
Hospitalists' but it should really have been titled "Geographic
Bedside Rounds: Just Do It!". They did mention the IT improvements
they've made to support geographic rounding, but the value of the talk
was in describing how they implemented geographic rounding and how it
has been received by the involved parties. Moving to geographic
rounding helps providers the least. It's basically an addition to our
workload. On the other hand, patients, nurses, and social workers get
a lot of benefit and obviously, the patients are the most important
factor here. We will have to see the patient more than once and our
workflow will have to change, but it seems that the benefits outweigh
the extra costs to the individual provider. Paraphrased, "Nurses and
social workers would riot if we stopped this system, but even
hospitalists wouldn't want to go back to the old way, if put to a
referendum." Something that only came out in the post-talk questions
was how this has improved overall teamwork. They used to have a
complicated system about how new admissions were assigned, taking into
account census numbers, discharge numbers, and other factors. Now,
with the new system, there are days that one hospitalist will have
completely unequal numbers or new patients than another hospitalist,
but it is understood that things will even out over time. That has
encouraged hospitalists to stop focusing on numbers and instead to
focus on making things run better, so hospitalists who were previously
"anti-teamwork" are now offering to help out when they're done with
their work. Anecdotal, but I like stories like that.</p>

<p>They also mentioned that they created a video dramatization of their
bedside rounds. If I can find it, I will link to it.</p>

<h3>Updates in Hospital Medicine</h3>

<ul>
<li>Oral prednisone 60 mg daily as good as 600 mg IV for COPD
exacerbation (Presented at DRH Journal club)</li>
<li>OK to extend peripheral IVs rather than change routinely (Emailed to
me by DRH Hospitalist)</li>
<li>Getting appts for COPD exacerbation pts within 30 days may decrease
rehospitalization (duh!)</li>
<li>Benefit for tPA in stroke up to 4.5 hours, but earlier is better
(DRH Journal club)</li>
<li>Gurgling sounds predict pneumonia and ICU transfer (duh)</li>
<li>Routine ID consultation in Staph aureus bacteremia significantly
improves mortality (HR 0.44) (NEW TO ME)</li>
<li>Coagulopathy in liver disease doesn't protect against VTE (duh)</li>
<li>Metformin does not cause lactic acidosis (old news, but nice to be
data-supported now)</li>
<li>Enteral nutrition better than TPN in pancreatitis (DRH email/conversations)</li>
<li>In ICU palliative care situations, only 47% of family members based
their survival estimates on MD's prognosis advice.</li>
</ul>


<p>I skipped the ICU stuff. Only one of these updates was new to me
(listed as NEW in the list above). I attribute that to my colleagues
at Durham Regional who have been sharing the knowledge that they've
been collecting from various meetings and readings this year.</p>

<h3>Careers in Academic Medicine</h3>

<p>This was a workshop on how to pursue your ideal life in academic
medicine. I loved the energy and enthusiasm of the instructors. This
probably would've benefited from being a longer course with fewer,
more involved participants. The basic premise was to document what
exactly you are doing now, what you're getting paid to do, and what
you enjoy doing. Reconcile the differences in those 3 lists and try to
identify how to make them match.</p>

<h3>No wireless</h3>

<p>This would have been posted a lot earlier if I could ever get on the
SHM wireless network at the Gaylord Convention Center. "Please
wait. You will be redirected to the authentication page in 5 seconds."
You lie!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medical Student Oral Presentations]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/18/medical-student-oral-presentations"/>
    <updated>2011-02-18T14:57:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/18/medical-student-oral-presentations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I enjoyed
<a href="http://twitter.com/FutureDocs/status/38428516961751040">@FutureDocs</a>'
<a href="http://futuredocsblog.com/2010/10/20/preparing-for-attending-rounds-some-things-don%E2%80%99t-change/">guide to medical student oral
presentations</a>,
so I thought I'd share the cheat sheet that I give to the medical
students and PA students when I start each teaching block. As she
mentioned, presentations always have to be tailored to the listener,
and each attending is different, so you'll see minor differences in
what I recommend.</p>

<p>To me, the most important aspects are organization and preparation. I
don't like to have the sense that the student is "winging it". Prepare
for each presentation like you are preparing to give a talk to a
roomful of people. For me, that meant practicing the presentation at
home and with the residents before I presented to an attending.</p>

<p>I also give each student a printed copy of the <a href="https://depts.washington.edu/medclerk/drupal/pages/Oral-Presentation-Guidelines">guidelines posted at
the University of Washington's medical education
site</a>. It
goes into more detail about all of these issues. My favorite portion
is the graph that they present, which I'll reproduce here:</p>

<p><img src="/images/uwash-med-student-presentation.png" title="Skip
 the Boring Stuff" alt="Listener Attention" /></p>

<p>Here's a <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/pub?id=1XjKZsHu_Q54rL9EwtPtS9via-hEs67H2fRDEs8eHAZc">printable copy of my cheat sheet</a>.</p>

<h3>Initial Presentation:</h3>

<p><strong>CC/ID</strong></p>

<p>Be Brief. Gets the listener primed for what type of case is going to be presented.</p>

<blockquote><p>This is a 33 year old male with a history of asthma who presents with a chief complaint of dyspnea.</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>HPI</strong></p>

<p>This is the meat of the presentation. Pretend that you're telling the
patient's story to a friend. How much information would they need to
really understand what the patient is going through? Think about it
from the patient's perspective. What was the tipping point that made
them seek medical attention? What have they tried to make things
better? Stay consistent in your timeline. I like to start at the last
point that the patient was completely well. In patients with chronic
illness, that is hard, so you may have to start at the last time that
they were "relatively" well.</p>

<blockquote><p>He was completely well (or "in his usual state of health" for chronically ill patients) until 5 days ago, when he noticed feeling short of breath after walking 300 feet to his mailbox. Over the course of the next 5 days, his dyspnea worsened to the point that he was short of breath at rest. He tried taking his albuterol inhaler, but felt no relief. Etc…</p></blockquote>

<p>It's also useful to split the HPI into 2 distinct sections. The first
part is the patient's story, as described above. In the second part,
you take that story and decide what a reasonable differential
diagnosis list would be after listening to the first part. Then
provide the listener with appropriate ROS and PMH items to help them
rule those other diagnoses out.</p>

<p><strong>PMH</strong></p>

<p>You may have mentioned a few of these in the CC, but repeat them
here. For most conditions, just list the diagnosis, but if it has
particular pertinence to the HPI, then provide more detail. Also, try
to give some indication of the severity of the condition for certain
conditions: CHF (EF), DM (A1C), COPD (FEV1).</p>

<blockquote><p>Past medical history includes Asthma. He has been hospitalized twice in the past year, and required mechanical ventilation in April. He also has hypertension and allergic rhinitis.</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Meds</strong></p>

<p>List meds like a robot :-) Include doses if they are important. You'll
learn the importance of doses with experience. In general, if the med
is related to the HPI, I want to know the dose. You can't go wrong by
just giving me the dose on each med. Just run through them quickly</p>

<p><strong>FH/SH/ROS</strong></p>

<p>You should obviously have done these portions of the interview, but if
 they were important, I would have wanted to hear about it in the
 HPI. (Pt lives in a nursing home… Pt smokes… etc.) It's OK to go over
 it quickly, but probably better to say:</p>

<blockquote><p>FH/SH/ROS is unremarkable aside from what was presented in HPI</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Exam</strong></p>

<p>List the VS: Temp/HR/BP/RR/O2 sat. Then provide an overall impression:</p>

<blockquote><p>In general, the patient appears tired and seemed to be in mild respiratory distress.</p></blockquote>

<p>Pertinent negatives and significant positives only:</p>

<blockquote><p>Lung exam was remarkable for diffuse expiratory wheezes with accessory muscle use. Cardiac exam confirmed tachycardia. There was no lower extremity edema and the remainder of the complete physical exam was normal.</p></blockquote>

<p>Be completely objective. Avoid downplaying your exam skills. It's OK
to get things wrong – it's often the best way to learn. Avoid patient
interpretations here.</p>

<p><strong>Labs/Xray/EKG/Procedures</strong></p>

<p>If it's all normal, OK to say it's all normal, but if any are
abnormal, I like to hear each value in that group.</p>

<p><strong>ER course</strong></p>

<p>Brief sentence on what happened in the ER before you saw the patient.</p>

<p><strong>Assessment/Plan</strong></p>

<p>Second juicy part of the presentation. Identify each problem and go
one by one. Put the most pressing issue first. If the diagnosis is in
question, give me a differential diagnosis and let me know what we're
doing to rule out items on the differential. If the diagnosis is
relatively certain, present me with various therapeutic options and
the reason why you chose the one you did.</p>

<p>Think about "goals of care", if appropriate</p>

<p>Always mention disposition. What are we looking for before the patient
can be discharged? In some cases, this will be nebulous, but at least
mention it. "Disposition is unclear at this point because of X"</p>

<p><strong>Overnight course</strong></p>

<p>What happened after you put your plan in place? Brief status report on
how patient is doing today.</p>

<h3>Subsequent Day Presentations:</h3>

<p><strong>1 line about patient</strong>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Ms Jones is our 87 year old woman here with an aspiration pneumonia</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Overnight course</strong>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Since yesterday's rounds, she has had a speech evaluation and they recommended a video swallow study. She had one temperature spike to 38.5 degrees and blood cultures were drawn. She appears to more comfortable this morning, though she is still confused.</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Exam</strong>: Vitals, superquick exam describing pertinents only</p>

<p><strong>Labs</strong>: Any new labs that came back since we met for rounds yesterday.</p>

<p><strong>Plan for today</strong>: Go by problem again.</p>

<blockquote><p>Problem 1: aspiration pneumonia, she's on D3 of Zosyn and we will continue to followup cultures. Overall she seems improved, but we'll have to continue to monitor her mental status and oxygenation for further improvement. Problem 2: Altered mental status: This is almost certainly due to her pneumonia, but if it does not improve by tomorrow, we may consider other etiologies. At that point, repeat labs, EKG, and head CT may be indicated.  ... Problem 53: Disposition ...</p></blockquote>

<p>Be prepared to answer questions if you have been appropiately brief!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr. Watson]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/17/dr.-watson"/>
    <updated>2011-02-17T19:18:18-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/17/dr.-watson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All I could think of while watching the news about the supercomputer
<a href="http://www-943.ibm.com/innovation/us/watson/">Watson</a> beating humans
at Jeopardy was how this could be used in medicine. Looks like <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/blog/post.cfm?id=paging-dr-watson-ibm-to-apply-jeopa-2011-02-17">I'm
not
alone</a>.</p>

<p>Time to start looking for a new job?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aspirin for everyone]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/16/aspirin-for-everyone"/>
    <updated>2011-02-16T21:17:23-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/16/aspirin-for-everyone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aspirin is one of those wonder drugs - simple, cheap and effective
versus so many deadly diseases. We know that aspirin prevents heart
attacks and strokes, especially if you've had one before. There is
also some data that it prevents colon cancers, but it was thought that
this effect was only seen when using high doses of aspirin. The
downside of aspirin is that it increases your risk of bleeding,
especially gastrointestinal bleeding (usually from stomach
ulcers). Using <em>high</em> doses of aspirin tends to increase the bleeding
risk so much that it offsets any benefits.</p>

<p>When someone has had a stroke or heart attack, using aspirin is a
no-brainer (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coronary_artery_disease#Secondary_prevention">secondary
prevention</a>). The
question is when to start aspirin in patients who have never had a bad
event (<a href="http://www.enotes.com/public-health-encyclopedia/primary-prevention">primary
prevention</a>). We
used to be much more liberal about recommending aspirin for primary
prevention, but there haven't been many studies which have supported
the practice. The current guidelines state to consider starting
aspirin for primary prevention in men at age 45 and women at age 55,
if their risk of vascular disease outweighs their risk of
gastrointestinal bleeding. That's a wishy-washy way of saying "Leave
it up to your gut." (No pun intended)</p>

<p>I decided to write about this because I saw a recent <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21144578?dopt=Abstract">study showing
decreased deaths from cancer in aspirin
users</a>,
even at <strong>low</strong> doses. Overall cancer rates were 20% lower and
gastrointestinal cancer rates were 35% lower than in people who didn't
use aspirin. These data come from 2 meta-analyses of retrospective
studies, which tend to be a relatively weak type of study. Prospective
studies are much better, but these numbers strike me as significant.</p>

<p>Given this new data, I would strongly favor using aspirin in most
people once they hit those age cutoffs (45 &amp; 55), which for me is
pretty soon. Calculate your <a href="http://hp2010.nhlbihin.net/atpiii/calculator.asp">cardiovascular
risk</a>. If your risk
is any more than 10% or so, I would recommend taking an aspirin daily,
possibly even if it's lower. The reasons that I would recommend not
taking an aspirin are if you have frequent stomach ulcers, previous
severe bleeding, or if you're taking blood thinners or high doses of
NSAIDs (ibuprofen, naproxen). Here's a nice <a href="http://www.ahrq.gov/clinic/cvd/aspprovider.htm">fact
sheet</a> that summarizes
what I've just rambled about (Wish I had seen that before I wrote all
this!)</p>

<p>Disclaimer: Don't take medical advice from the internet. Show this to
your doctor so they can tell you what a quack I am.</p>

<p>References:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://general-medicine.jwatch.org/cgi/content/full/2011/113/2">Journal Watch
reference</a></li>
<li><a href="http://guidelines.gov/content.aspx?id=14243#Section420">USPSTF Aspirin guideline</a></li>
<li><a href="http://circ.ahajournals.org/cgi/content/full/121/24/2694">2010 AHA revision of their Aspirin
guideline</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
