<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wedding on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/wedding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wedding on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/wedding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3 weddings, 5 babies, 2 graduations and a dog</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog/</guid>
      <description>I love taking pictures with my trusty old Canon S200. It takes great pics and I get to take the credit. I&amp;rsquo;m just horrible about getting them off my camera and onto my website. I finally uploaded a whole bunch today, dating back to early May when we went to Philadelphia for Kevin and Joanne&amp;rsquo;s wedding. The next group is from Brooklyn and Staten Island for Mary Ann and Benjeil&amp;rsquo;s wedding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Update: The Honeymoon</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon/</guid>
      <description>Amazing etched door  We honeymooned in California Wine Country. We stayed at the Hilton in Santa Rosa, about halfway between Napa and Sonoma. In Napa, we visited Sterling, Peju, V. Sattui and Artesa. I enjoy wine, but not to the point that I can tell the difference between a good wine and a great one. So, I grade vineyards on different criteria. Go to Sterling for the view and the self-guided tour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re married!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married/</guid>
      <description>Mala and Vinod  Life update time. If you&amp;rsquo;re a keen follower of this site, you&amp;rsquo;ll have noticed the little box in the upper left hand corner announcing my wedding to Mala. We got married a few months back and it was documented in photos by friends, family and even an official photographer. (Time wasting warning: There are 500 pictures from friends and family, 1200+ proofs from our photographer).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>