<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>clamz to the rescue</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/04/clamz-to-the-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/04/clamz-to-the-rescue/</guid>
      <description>Kottke linked to some great deals on classical music at amazon. In order to download them, you need to have the amazon mp3 downloader installed. They now offer a Debian (linux) version, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it working. It&amp;rsquo;s meant for an older version of Debian, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize the newer versions of the libraries installed on my system. I thought about doing some fancy apt-getting to try to get the right versions, but just thinking about that made my head throb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Songflower Man</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/12/mr.-songflower-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/12/mr.-songflower-man/</guid>
      <description>This story about a creative music teacher in Syracuse, NY made me smile out loud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dan Bern</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/29/dan-bern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/29/dan-bern/</guid>
      <description>Dan Bern has quickly become one of my favorite musicians. I saw him a while back at the (now defunct) Bottom Line and then again tonight at Joe&amp;rsquo;s Pub (within spitting distance!). He&amp;rsquo;s been compared to Bob Dylan, although, unlike Dylan, I can understand what he&amp;rsquo;s saying. His music is simple and catchy, and the lyrics can go from hilarious to poignant in one song.
He played a couple songs tonight that I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find on CDs anywhere - one called &amp;ldquo;One More Light&amp;rdquo; and one about 9&amp;frasl;11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Music Download</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/05/legal-music-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/05/legal-music-download/</guid>
      <description>Legal Music Downloads and some great background information. I&amp;rsquo;m gonna give iRATE a try.
Comments from old site Directory of Legal Music Downloads
 Check out this site for a comprehensive listing of legal music download sites.
Directory of Legal Music Downloads Joel Erenberg 2004-04-11 19:18:06</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t get sued</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/30/dont-get-sued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/30/dont-get-sued/</guid>
      <description>The topic of music sharing and its legality came up during our annual cousins trip in Seattle. Here&amp;rsquo;s an important article on How Not to Get Sued by the RIAA. The most important thing is the last line in the article:
 Join EFF and support our efforts to protect file-sharing.
 I don&amp;rsquo;t use P2P music-sharing apps anymore. While I love the idea of being able to access an unending library of music, I don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of getting it for free.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>