<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cousins-trip | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/cousins-trip/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-09T07:01:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[6th Annual Cousins Trip]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/07/06/6th-annual-cousins-trip"/>
    <updated>2005-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/07/06/6th-annual-cousins-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/girish-water.jpg" width="500" class="inset" alt="Walking on water (Lake George)"/></p>

<p>Cousins Trip 2005 (<a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=20907">photos</a>) was in Lake George, NY this year. The weather didn't quite cooperate this time. It was cloudy and rainy all week. Still, we were able to get in a <a href="/images/lake-george-hike.jpg">great hike</a>, <a href="/images/lake-george-bowling.jpg">some competitive bowling</a>, <a href="/images/bball.jpg">basketball</a> and mini-golf, not to mention enjoying the <a href="/images/elvis.jpg">2nd annual Elvis Festival</a>. While we didn't run into any bears, we did see <a href="/images/caterpillar.jpg">plenty</a> <a href="/images/gecko.jpg">of</a> <a href="/images/snake.jpg">wildlife</a>. Of course, I would be a rumpcake if I were to forget to mention our late-night Taboo contests, the highlight of the trip.</p>

<p>Previous Trips:</p>

<ol>
<li>2000 Youghiogheny Rafting</li>
<li>2001 Sea Kayaking North Carolina Outer Banks</li>
<li>2002 <a href="/blog/2002/07/22/grand-canyon-update/">Grand Canyon</a></li>
<li>2003 <a href="/blog/2003/07/31/4th-annual-cousins-reunion/">Seattle</a></li>
<li>2004 <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=14824">Lake Tahoe</a></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wall of water]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2004/08/11/wall-of-water"/>
    <updated>2004-08-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2004/08/11/wall-of-water</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>http://www.cnn.com/2004/US/West/08/05/wallofwater.ap/index.html (link now broken)</p>

<blockquote><p>The sudden release of water from Ralston Reservoir south of Auburn sent a "wall of water three to four-feet high" down the Middle Fork of the American River, said California Highway Patrol spokesman Tom Marshall.</p></blockquote>

<p>That's the river that we rafted down a couple weeks ago during our <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=14824">5th Annual Cousins Trip</a>. If it had happened during our trip, I still probably would've been the first one to fall in.</p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>Oregon's walls of water</b></p>
<p>
Oregon has its share of huge walls of water. One was <a href="http://www.wrh.noaa.gov/Portland/history.html">40 feet high</a>, in 1903, and there is a prehistorical record of a <a href="http://www.fs.fed.us/r6/columbia/missoula.htm">2000 foot wall of water</a> that carved out much of the geological formations now present in the Northwest!
</p>
<p>
Not trying to outdo you, just thought that was a pretty interesting
tidbit.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Jade Rubick</span>
<span class="date">2004-08-10 23:00:13</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="my-comment">
<p><b>Wall of water</b></p>
<p>
Cool! Don't worry about outdoing me. I'm sure that someday the rapids that we ran will be about 2000 feet high in my stories to my grandkids :-)
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Vinod Kurup</span>
<span class="date">2004-08-11 17:13:58</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Seattle]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/08/14/more-seattle"/>
    <updated>2003-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/08/14/more-seattle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Girish has put up some pics from the <a href="http://f2.pg.photos.yahoo.com/girishvnair02">Seattle trip and other family events</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[4th Annual Cousins Reunion]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/07/31/4th-annual-cousins-reunion"/>
    <updated>2003-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/07/31/4th-annual-cousins-reunion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We went whitewater rafting in Pennsylvania in 2000, sea-kayaking in North Carolina in 2001, and <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=5317">death-marching (er... hiking) in the Grand Canyon in 2002</a>. This year, we chose <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=5564">kayaking and hiking in Seattle</a>.</p>

<p>We went kayaking near the <a href="http://www.guidetosanjuans.com/">San Juan Islands</a> on Thursday. It was a great upper body workout and our guide <a href="http://sea-quest-kayak.com/sea-kayaking-guides.htm">Martine</a> was a fountain of information. We saw some harbor seals close up and a bald eagle from afar. We (well some of us) were really hoping to see whales, but unfortunately, they didn't cooperate.</p>

<p>On Friday, we drove south to <a href="http://www.mount.rainier.national-park.com/">Mt. Rainier</a>. The skies were overcast in Seattle but they conveniently cleared up just as we neared the park. The views were breath-taking (or was that the hiking?). We trekked around Paradise (yup that's what it's called) along a path that Manu picked out. It was challenging, but we wouldn't have it any other way. One of the climbs took us to the top of the cliff where Manu warned Noel, "If you fall, Anita won't let you join us next year!" After a quick well-deserved soak in the hotel's outdoor jacuzzi, we finished the night with some amazing sushi at Shiro. Everything was great but I could've done without the Uni (sea urchin) - those who didn't eat it seemed to enjoy it the most.</p>

<p>On Saturday morning, we played our annual basketball game. Because of some logistical details, I had the fortune of playing on the young-guys team in game 1 and the old-guys team in game 2. My team lost both games, thus graciously providing both the oldies and the kiddies with bragging rights. I took a few movies - <a href="http://kurup.org/files/MVI_1618.AVI">Harish making a shot</a>, <a href="http://kurup.org/files/MVI_1620.AVI">Girish with a tough shot</a>, and <a href="http://kurup.org/files/MVI_1621.AVI">Dilu with some fancy dribbling</a>.</p>

<p>After basketball, we ate brunch at the Space Needle and took in the great views of Seattle and Mt. Rainier in the background. Saturday was a day to relax and take in the city without exercising too many muscles.</p>

<p>I'm skipping over a lot of details, but the bottom line is that I had an amazing time. It's always more fun than I imagine it could ever be. I can't wait til next year.</p>

<p>See <a href="http://kurup.net/seattle.htm">Manu's site</a> for some more pictures.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Grand Canyon]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2002/08/26/more-grand-canyon"/>
    <updated>2002-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2002/08/26/more-grand-canyon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Manu sent me the pics that he took during our <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=5317&amp;amp;page=6">Grand Canyon trip</a>. Thanks Manu!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
