<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: babies | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/babies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-09T08:22:17-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 weddings, 5 babies, 2 graduations and a dog]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog"/>
    <updated>2006-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/mala-nyc.jpg" width="500" alt="IMG_5830.JPG" /></p>

<p>I love taking pictures with my trusty old Canon S200. It takes great pics and I get to take the credit. I'm just horrible about getting them off my camera and onto my website. I finally uploaded a <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/?folder_id=61013">whole bunch</a> today, dating back to early May when we went to <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71973">Philadelphia for Kevin and Joanne's wedding</a>. The next group is from <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71975">Brooklyn and Staten Island for Mary Ann and Benjeil's wedding</a>. We interrupted wedding season to watch <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71979">Ethan graduate from law school</a> in Minneapolis. While in the Twin Cities, we got to spend a few minutes with <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=73510">Ajay</a>. Back home, we started <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71981">Memorial Day in the Cloisters</a>, had lunch in the city (photo above), and finished the day by meeting a cute girl named <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=73401">Amalie</a> (of Amalie &amp; Ivory fame!). A week later we were back in the Midwest for <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71983">Sivan's cozy high school graduation</a>. Nothing like watching your nephew graduate from high school to make you feel old. <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=74486">Mike and Susan threw a barbecue in Long Island</a> to celebrate their farewell. <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=74502">Asha</a> was there too! Next up on the wedding circuit were <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71985">Russ and Michelle</a>. They were nice enough to get married in DC, so we were able to stay with Puja and meet <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=74305">Loki</a>. <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71987">Mala interviewed in Norfolk</a> where we were introduced to <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=74063">Kylee</a> for the first time.</p>

<p>And if that's not enough for you, here are some <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71977">random pics from the Bronx</a>. I'm sad to say that I've yet to take any photos of <a href="http://kurup.org/dave/photo/photo?photo_id=71894">Hunter June</a>, so I'll point you instead to <a href="http://kurup.org/dave/photo/album?album_id=67042">her parents' photos</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
