<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: writing | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-08T21:26:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing paralysis]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/15/writing-paralysis"/>
    <updated>2013-01-15T14:45:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/15/writing-paralysis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think twitter and facebook stunt my writing. The more that I read
tweets, the more self-conscious I get when I write. Not that my
writing is all that original, but I still feel that it is something
that comes from me. I worry so much about presenting ideas of others
as my own without even remembering that I had seen the ideas before.
In the old days, the things that I read were long form. Books,
articles, maybe blog posts. They each left an impression on me, maybe
good, maybe bad, but I had a sense where they were coming from. When I
wrote I could reliably say where the inspiration for my idea had come
from. Now with twitter, I see all these ideas and thoughts, some of
which are interesting, but few of which leave a lasting impression on
me. So now I have this fear that the things that I am considering my
own ideas are actually the ideas of others, improperly attributed. Of
course, that's silly. No idea is original, but it's just serious
enough to stifle my writing. Because, as a writer, I am the
scaredy-cat of all scaredy-cats and any criticism of my writing bites
deep to the heart. I also know that this is something that I just need
to get over. You cannot express ideas without inviting criticism.
I also don't just want to let criticism fall off me. I want to learn
from critics. But saying all that doesn't necessarily make it any
easier. Even writing this post, I feel like a fraud. I've said that
I'm a writer a couple times up there, but what evidence do I have to
support that claim? Most of my blog posts are so simple or technical
or repetitive. Nothing that would strike me as an 'original idea'.
This whole post makes it seem like I am more important or better than
I really am.</p>

<p>What is my point with all this? I want to be able to write. I know
that there are people out there who could benefit from things in my
brain (maybe not a lot). I know that there are people out there who
can help me (in ways that I can't even expect). So, I want to write
and I want it to be freely flowing and I don't want to force myself to
feel that what I am writing is useful or authoritative or perfect. I
apologize to you, Vinod, my biggest critic. I know that you are
cringing inside because you're thinking that anyone who reads this
will think that you are so full of yourself for even considering
yourself a writer. But, this is my first step in letting my guard down
to get this blog flowing. Because I do believe that writing is healthy
and will make me a better person.</p>

<p>In addition to committing to blogging more frequently, I'm also going
to try a twitter hiatus for a week and see what happens.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blogging Again]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/08/03/blogging-again"/>
    <updated>2012-08-03T14:50:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/08/03/blogging-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm going to start blogging more. I know I've said that before, so
take it for what it's worth. I think there is value in blogging. I've
been thinking about my life a lot lately, trying to find what makes me
tick. One of those things that gets me excited is programming. I
started thinking about that and remembered this meme that had passed
around the blog world a few years back. It was a list of questions
related to how you got started programming. I remember it especially
because I remember reading MarkD's version and thinking how similar it
was to my own beginnings. Then, because I love going off on tangents,
I googled for 'How I got started in programming' to read other
responses. Many of the posts I found were on abandoned blogs. And now,
for the 'causal relationship not supported by data' statement. This is
because of Facebook and Twitter. OK, maybe it's just the natural decay
of blogs. But I am concerned about the fact that most people write in
forums that are controlled by other people rather in their own forum.
That was one of the cool promises of the web. A little place of your
own that you controlled. Facebook and Twitter and Google+ are all cool
services, but the more time I spend on them, the less time I spend
here. I'm sure other people have written about this with more
eloquence than I could, but the bottom line is that I want to keep
writing. I want to learn more about myself, I want to teach others
what little I know, and I want to learn from others. I've been
journalling a lot lately and that has been useful, but the act of
hitting 'publish' will make my writing better. That's what this blog
is for and I'm going to start using it again.</p>

<p>Maybe one of these days, I'll even put up my own answers to 'How I Got
Started in Programming', but in the meantime, go read
<a href="http://borkwarellc.wordpress.com/2008/07/01/how-i-got-started-in-programming/">MarkD's</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running as a metaphor for life]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/09/running-as-a-metaphor-for-life"/>
    <updated>2011-08-09T20:41:02-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/09/running-as-a-metaphor-for-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was thinking the other day, on a run, of course, about the many ways
that running is a metaphor for life. I've <a href="/blog/2003/10/28/the-wall-is-not-a-myth/">discussed some of this
before with my cousins Dilu and
Harish</a> before.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>... two roads diverged in a wood, and I --<br/>I took the one less traveled by,<br/>And that has made all the difference.</p><footer><strong>Robert Frost</strong> <cite><a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Road_Not_Taken_(poem)'>en.wikipedia.org/wiki/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>While trail running, I have come to the realization that you never
have to worry about the fork in the road, nor the decision associated
with it. During my first trail run in the forest near our home, I was
amazed by the number of single track trailheads that I saw. I didn't
take any of them that first day, content to just take the wide dirt
path along the creek. After a few runs though, I started to take some
of the single track trails and found myself amongst even more
beautiful nature. I found more forks in the trails and I agonized a
bit about taking the right one, mainly so I wouldn't get lost. Now
that I've run in the woods dozens of times, I don't worry about the
fork in the road. I know that I can take one fork today and the other
fork tomorrow.</p>

<p>Life is like that too. Every decision point seems so important. Making
the wrong decision seems like it will doom me forever. But, I've found
so far that there are very few decisions that are not
reversible. Certainly some are, but even the important ones like
career and family don't have to be set in stone. I wish I had come to
this realization earlier. Every decision seems so final at the time
that I'm making it, but when you look back it seems obvious that there
are plenty of options available, no matter which path you chose. Even
knowing that bias, it's hard to remember that when a new decision has
to be made.</p>

<p>Some of the single track trails have pathmarkers to help keep you on
the right trail. They are little numbered plastic circles nailed to a
tree. They are few and far between. Occasionally, you'll come to a
fork in the trail and there won't be an obvious pathmarker around, so
you have to make a decision. That can be somewhat stressful, so you
keep your eyes peeled for pathmarkers as you're running to see if you
made the right decision. At some point, you've gone so far without
seeing a marker that you're almost certain that you've gone the wrong
way. Either you keep the faith and keep going, or you turn around and
try the other fork. There is no right answer.</p>

<p>Life is sometimes like that. We have signposts and decision trees that
are easy to follow in many cases. But inevitably, there will be a
point where we have to make a decision without all of the evidence or
without all of the data or without a clear idea of where we're
going. Not until you take that leap of faith will you get the signal
that you've made the right decision. And sometimes that signal won't
come for a long time. I'm not sure what the point of this is, but it
seemed very profound at the time while I was running in the woods,
about to give up, thinking that I had gone down the wrong path, when I
suddenly saw the elusive pathmarker that confirmed that I was not
lost. Trail running is like that... everything is not set in stone and
predefined. You have to develop your faith and intuition, and if that
fails, accept that maybe you'll do better next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advice on writing]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/11/04/writing-marshall"/>
    <updated>2010-11-04T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/11/04/writing-marshall</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just found this <a href="http://www.sebastianmarshall.com/?p=195">great article on
writing</a> by Sebastian
Marshall. His basic advice boils down to "just do it!", but he makes
some interesting points along the way. I had never heard of the
Equal-Odds rule. Read more details at his blog, but basically, in
order to do great work, you have to do a lot of "not-great" work. No
one just does great work. So, let go and just write. The great stuff
will float to the top.</p>

<p>Commit to doing it every day, no matter what. I don't know how many
times I've heard this, yet I still don't do it. I guess it's like I
tell my smokers who tell me they've tried to quit so many times. Each
quit attempt is preparation for the time that you really quit. You
never know when it's going to stick, so just keep trying.</p>

<p>"<em>I accepted that I'm going to be judged. I don't love it, but I
accepted it.</em>" This is the hardest part for me. My ego is fragile, but
oh well. The benefits are worth the risks.</p>

<p>"<em>Try to think of each visitor as an honored guest.</em>" I like that. My
site gets minimal traffic, but that's not zero. And I actually know
some of the people that read ... don't worry, I won't embarrass them
by naming names. The bottom line is that my whole purpose is to
improve the lives of others, in whatever small way possible. To think
that <strong>anyone</strong> is spending their precious time reading this is an honor
to me.</p>

<p>I may never be the prolific writer that I envision myself being, but
it can't hurt to keep trying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Anti-Writing Cycle]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/07/27/my-anti-writing-cycle"/>
    <updated>2010-07-27T21:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/07/27/writers-block</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I blogged daily for a 6 day stretch a couple weeks ago, which is the
longest continuous stretch I've ever done. It was stimulating and stressful
at the same time. I haven't heard from the Pulitzer committee about any of
the posts yet, but it's not the quality that matters. Writing is more about
the process than the product, and I know from experience that writing helps
me think. And while most of the posts were written for my own benefit, I
really enjoyed the response that I got from family and friends about
<a href="/blog/2010/07/15/playdoh">Playdoh</a>. I think I've read that post 100 times
and I still laugh out loud at the end of it. That's the post that started
the stretch off. As soon as I had put Kavi to bed, I knew that I wanted to
share that story. I wrote it down quickly, so I wouldn't forget it. That
writing process stimulated me to want to write more, so I made it an
internal goal to write a post daily.</p>

<p>Then I had two night shifts and the streak was broken. I've had a few days
off, but I still haven't written anything. I'm still learning clojure, but
I fear writing about something that I know nothing about. Even though I've
heard others say that this is the best time to write about a topic. I've
also constructed a vicious cycle in my head. I want to learn clojure. I
want to write about what I learn. I start doing so, but then I skip a day
or so. Now, when I have free time, I think about learning clojure, but then
I also think about the fact that I should write about it. And since I'm
already behind, I don't want to get further behind, so maybe I shouldn't
read that interesting tutorial until I've caught up on writing about what
I've learned. Next thing I know, I'm monitoring Twitter streams
second-by-second for <a href="http://imgur.com">imgur</a> links.</p>

<p>I'm hoping that writing about my mental blocks will help me overcome
them. I plan to write more frequently, mostly for my own benefit, but I'm
not going to let it get in the way of learning cool, interesting stuff. If
my writing is disjointed, so be it. I can fill in the gaps later if anyone
cares.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
