<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>baby on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/baby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in baby on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/baby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anika Puri Kurup</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/23/anika-puri-kurup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/23/anika-puri-kurup/</guid>
      <description>Kavi, Mala and I are so happy to announce the arrival of Anika Puri Kurup. She was born on June 22nd, 2009 at 11:07 PM after a happily uneventful labor and delivery. Mom and Baby are doing well. Here is a quick video, with of course more to follow soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great weekend</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/13/great-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/13/great-weekend/</guid>
      <description>I can barely believe it, but Kavi is 2 years old now. This is such a great age. I remember saying that a year ago, but he&amp;rsquo;s even more enjoyable now. He&amp;rsquo;s excited about everything new. He&amp;rsquo;s running nonstop, singing out loud, and dancing up a storm.
Mala organized a great birthday party for him at a local park. He got a lot of great gifts from all his friends, some of which we&amp;rsquo;re saving so that he can open when the new baby is getting a lot of attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon there will be two</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/17/soon-there-will-be-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/17/soon-there-will-be-two/</guid>
      <description>Kavi has been getting bored being surrounded by adults all the time. He is very happy to announce that a sibling is on its way. We&amp;rsquo;re calling it blueberry. If things go on schedule, blueberry will be born sometime in June, so we&amp;rsquo;ll have 2 June babies, a couple years apart.
Pregnancy has been uneventful, unless you count those recurrent waves of nausea and vomiting that Mala&amp;rsquo;s been experiencing. Hopefully that will get better as we move into the second trimester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Soon!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been hard to keep this news from friends and family, but we wanted to be sure. So, without further delay, we are immensely happy to present:
Kidney Bean  Comments from old site dude
 Dude! This is one hell (heck) of an announcement. You go public, boy-eee! Unregistered Visitor 2006-12-08 13:55:07   Awesome dude
 Congrats and all the best :) Mark Aufflick 2006-12-11 21:40:16   Congratulations</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>