<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: web | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/web/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-29T21:34:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steal My Web App Idea]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/09/steal-my-web-app-idea"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T22:00:01-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/09/steal-my-web-app-idea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that we have 3 kids, I'm always internally comparing one to the
other. Sure that's not healthy and will probably breed resentment in
them during their teenage years, but what's a bad parent to do?</p>

<p>I need an app that takes 2 kids' birthdays and then shows me what day
it was when the older kid was the age that the younger kid is now.
Wow, that's a confusing sentence. In simpler terms, if I have a
3-year-old and a 1-year-old, then the app would show me the day that
the 3-year-old was 1.</p>

<p>Then, I want the app to take that date and go through all of my
personal files (photos, notes, twitter stream, facebook stream, etc.)
and show me what was happening in our life around that day.</p>

<p>In short, it would show a snapshot of what our life was like when the
older kid was the age that the younger kid is now. I'd call it
WhenIWasYourAge or something catchy like that.</p>

<p>Seems simple enough to build, but I don't see myself getting to it
anytime soon. Smart people say to set your ideas free and if they love
you they'll come back. (Wait, I think I'm mixing metaphors here).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Letter Sweep]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/03/04/letter-sweep"/>
    <updated>2011-03-04T06:23:58-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/03/04/letter-sweep</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/03/03/ABC">Tim Bray posted the links that his browser
displays</a> when
he types each letter of the alphabet. Here's mine:</p>

<p><a href="http://adsense.com">[A]dSense</a>. I spend too much time watching the
zero's pile up.</p>

<p><a href="http://borkware.com">[B]orkware</a>. Always good for a
<a href="http://borkware.com/quickies/">quickie</a>. Wait... that didn't sound right.</p>

<p><a href="http://citeulike.com">[C]ite-U-Like</a>. I've started to use this site
to keep track of journal articles that I read.</p>

<p><a href="http://docs.google.com">[D]ocs (Google)</a>. I store my Habits
spreadsheet, my weight spreadsheet, our address book spreadsheet
(because Google contacts aren't shareable) and other random documents.</p>

<p><a href="http://evernote.com">[E]vernote</a>. I've been trying to use this more
to keep a central repository of notes, but it hasn't stuck yet.</p>

<p><a href="http://facebook.com">[F]acebook</a>. I don't know why this is there. I
never use facebook.</p>

<p><a href="http://gqueues.com">[G]queues</a>. I'm surprised that Google lost this
one. I'm using Gqueues to keep track of my todos. It's pretty nice. My
main complaint is that it's a little slow and there's no Android client.</p>

<p><a href="http://facebook.com">[H]ttp://facebook.com</a>. Oh, how
embarrassing. OK, my name is Vinod Kurup and I'm a facebook addict.</p>

<p><a href="http://instapaper.com">[I]nstapaper</a>. I store longer articles here
for later reading. I use the <a href="http://market.android.com/search?q=instafetch">Instafetch</a> client on Android to read them.</p>

<p><a href="http://jwatch.org">[J]ournal Watch</a>. Phew! At least one site relevant
to my day job!</p>

<p><a href="http://kurup.org">[K]urup.org</a>. The most amazing site on the internet.</p>

<p><a href="http://lloogg.com">[L]loogg</a>. <code>tail -f access.log</code> for the web</p>

<p><a href="http://myfitnesspal.com">[M]yfitnesspal</a>. We're using this to track
our diet and exercise. We used to use <a href="http://fitday.com">Fitday</a>, but this
is so much easier and there's a social component that is
motivating. It's amazing how comprehensive their food database is.</p>

<p><a href="http://newegg.com">[N]ewegg.com</a>. Mostly for printer cartridges, but
occasionally for toys.</p>

<p><a href="http://owa.dm.duke.edu">Duke [O]utlook</a>. My new work webmail. Outlook
2010 == HIT's idea of modern.</p>

<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com">[P]icasaweb</a>. Pictures of the cutest
kids in the world.</p>

<p>[Q]. This space for rent.</p>

<p><a href="http://ruby-doc.org">[R]uby-doc.org</a>. I'm trying to learn ruby (the
right way)</p>

<p><a href="http://sports.yahoo.com">[S]ports.yahoo.com</a>. My University of
Wisconsin, Green Bay Packer and Milwaukee Bucks/Brewers addiction is
slow to die.</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com">[T]witter</a>. Yup, I still use twitter.com.</p>

<p>[U]. b<strong>U</strong>eller... b<strong>U</strong>eller...</p>

<p><a href="http://victoryvillage.org">[V]ictory Village</a>. Kid's daycare. Lots
of snow this winter meant lots of checks to see if daycare was open.</p>

<p><a href="http://webmail.duhs.duke.edu/owa">Old Duke [W]ebmail</a>. Lotus Notes,
then Outlook 2007, now defunct.</p>

<p><a href="http://xkcd.com/">[X]KCD</a>. The best comic strip in the world.</p>

<p><a href="http://youtube.com">[Y]outube</a>. Videos of the cutest kids in the
world. Plus I think there are some other videos there...</p>

<p>[Z]. This space left intentionally blank.</p>

<p>And had to add (because it's so heavily used):</p>

<p><a href="http://127.0.0.1:4000">[1]27.0.0.1:4000</a>. My local <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> server.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML5 Up and Running]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/08/25/html5-up-and-running"/>
    <updated>2010-08-25T14:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/08/25/html5-up-and-running</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I preordered Mark Pilgrim's <a href="http://www.amazon.com/HTML5-Up-Running-Mark-Pilgrim/dp/0596806027?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=diveintomark-20&amp;creativeASIN=0596806027">HTML5, Up and Running</a> from Amazon back in
March. It's available for free as <a href="http://diveintohtml5.org/">Dive into
HTML5</a>. I've been a fan of Mark's <a href="http://diveintomark.org">writing</a>
for a while, so buying the book was a way to thank him "with a
buck". Interestingly, the online book and paper book are not
identical. For starters, the titles are different. In addition, the
beautiful fonts and cutesy images of the online version are gone. The
paper book is your run-of-the-mill O'Reilly book. I'm not sure if
it'll make much of a difference in my enjoyment, but we'll see.</p>

<p>As I said, I preordered the book in March, so I had no idea when it
would be finished and delivered. It showed up on my doorstep this
morning, on my birthday! We're on our way to NYC tomorrow for our
first trip back there since we moved to North Carolina in 2007, so I
know have some light pleasure reading. Perfect Timing!</p>

<p>I've only read the first chapter so far, but I think I'm going to love
it. I've done a lot of web programming in my life, but only maintain
my own sites now. I'm reading this book like a programmer might read a
book on astronomy... purely for the love of it. The first chapter goes
into the details of how the <code>IMG</code> tag was invented. Marc Andreessen
mentioned it on a mailing list back in 1993, and after some back and
forth, shipped it in Mosaic, an early browser. Because it shipped and
because it was popular, it got included in the HTML standards.</p>

<p>I still remember when Mosaic came out. I got my first email address in
1992 (vkurup@macc.wisc.edu) and somehow was on a mailing list
announcing the impending release of Mosaic. I remember the text of the
email basically saying that "This will change the world." Once I saw
it, I thought it was cool, but way over-hyped. Who is going to want to
wait for pictures to download over a 14.4K modem? Ridiculous. This is
why you should not take my advice about new trends.</p>

<p>Anyway, the point of the <code>IMG</code> example is to show that HTML standards
have never been "pure", but have always been influenced by the
implementers and the users of the web. The way it should be. HTML5 is
an acknowledgment of that fact.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prettier permalinks]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/03/28/prettier-permalinks"/>
    <updated>2006-03-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/03/28/prettier-permalinks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Permalink stands for 'permanent link'. When you create a blog post, it gets added to the top of your blog, pushing older entries down. Eventually, posts get pushed off the front page, so it's important that you have a way to refer to old blog posts. A permalink is the link that will always point to a specific post.</p>

<p>OpenACS (lars-blogger) permalinks look like this:</p>

<pre><code>http://kurup.org/blog/one-entry?entry_id=58950
</code></pre>

<p>This works and it's really easy to code, but it doesn't give much information about the content or date of the post.</p>

<p>A lot of other blog packages use permalinks which look like this:</p>

<pre><code>http://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/01/tag-cloud
</code></pre>

<p>It's easy to tell how old the post is, and what it might be about. More importantly, it seems that search engines give URLs like this more weight. So, I've gone ahead and made the changes on my blog. Enjoy!</p>

<p>For the OpenACS geeks, here's <a href="http://kurup.org/acs/blog_permalink">the changes that I made</a>. It won't necessarily apply cleanly against OpenACS, but it will give you an idea of what to change. It includes an automated test to assure you that both the old and new permalinks work.</p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>Just don't use the same title twice in one day</b></p>
<p>
You'll end up with ambiguous urls. The util_text_to_url proc can
disambiguate a list of urls for you, and then you'd need to store the
new url in the db.
</p>
<p>
That would also avoid the whole list/loop shenanegins. It would also
be easy to write a little script to go through your existing db and
create the urls for existing blog entries.
</p>
<p>
But that might be considered hard work ;)
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Mark Aufflick</span>
<span class="date">2006-05-05 07:11:24</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="my-comment">
<p><b>Excellent point</b></p>
<p>
I thought about that briefly while I wrote this, but figured, "What
are the chances that I'd write 2 posts in the same day with the same
title?" In other words, I took the easy way out.
</p>
<p>
But adding the permalink to the DB does sound like the right thing to
do, so I'll work on it or head over to <a
href="http://mark.aufflick.com/blog/2006/05/05/friendly-blog-links">your
blog</a> and beg for your code :-)
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Vinod Kurup</span>
<span class="date">2006-05-05 16:35:41</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tag Cloud]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/03/01/tag-cloud"/>
    <updated>2006-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/03/01/tag-cloud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>And now I have a pretty tag cloud on the side of my blog (that I pretty much stole from <a href="http://del.icio.us">del.icio.us</a>)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
