<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 21:11:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Parenting Highs and Lows</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/03/parenting-highs-and-lows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 21:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/03/parenting-highs-and-lows/</guid>
      <description>Written a few weeks ago
I came home late today, so Anika and Kavi had already eaten dinner and taken their baths. As I drove down the driveway, I could see Kavi&amp;rsquo;s excited little head poking over the upstairs windowsill. I parked the car and opened the door into the house. I was immediately met a voice screaming, &amp;ldquo;Daddy, Daddy!&amp;rdquo; with pure joy in his voice. He ran down the stairs and gave me a huge hug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I retract my previous tweet</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/04/i-retract-my-previous-tweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 21:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/04/i-retract-my-previous-tweet/</guid>
      <description>I take it back. I was upset, OK? Never tweet when you&amp;rsquo;re upset. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog post to make up for it. See, a whole blog post. That definitely outweighs a tweet, right?
Last week, my 1996 Altima died. The starter seemed to be firing, but the engine never turned over. We tried jumping it, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t work. I called a tow truck and then tweeted about how upset I was with the universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/01/03/happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/01/03/happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a great year. I was working on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve. My shift was supposed to end at midnight, which meant that I would normally be home around 12:30 AM, but my colleague let me out early since the ER was unusually light. I got home at 11:55 PM, so I was able to kiss my beautiful wife as the new year began. If that&amp;rsquo;s not an auspicious start to a year, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what one would be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon there will be two</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/17/soon-there-will-be-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/17/soon-there-will-be-two/</guid>
      <description>Kavi has been getting bored being surrounded by adults all the time. He is very happy to announce that a sibling is on its way. We&amp;rsquo;re calling it blueberry. If things go on schedule, blueberry will be born sometime in June, so we&amp;rsquo;ll have 2 June babies, a couple years apart.
Pregnancy has been uneventful, unless you count those recurrent waves of nausea and vomiting that Mala&amp;rsquo;s been experiencing. Hopefully that will get better as we move into the second trimester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m alive</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/08/02/im-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/08/02/im-alive/</guid>
      <description>OK, I know it&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since I updated this blog, but rest assured that I&amp;rsquo;m still alive and kicking. The observant among you will notice that the design of the blog has changed. The even more observant will notice that huge swaths of content are now missing. Things like my photo albums, my running log, old comments, and Kavi&amp;rsquo;s little site are now gone. They may make a reappearance someday, especially if I get prodded sufficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update/</guid>
      <description>Once again, I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen behind on my life updates, so let&amp;rsquo;s get caught up.
 Mala&amp;rsquo;s pregnancy is going well, at least from the husband&amp;rsquo;s point of view. She&amp;rsquo;s due June 15th. We drove to Orlando for my CME conference because Delta cancelled our flight. It turned out to be a nice thing because we got to see Puja, Ethan and Loki on the way down and we got to stop in Charleston, SC on the way back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Update: The Honeymoon</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon/</guid>
      <description>Amazing etched door  We honeymooned in California Wine Country. We stayed at the Hilton in Santa Rosa, about halfway between Napa and Sonoma. In Napa, we visited Sterling, Peju, V. Sattui and Artesa. I enjoy wine, but not to the point that I can tell the difference between a good wine and a great one. So, I grade vineyards on different criteria. Go to Sterling for the view and the self-guided tour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re married!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married/</guid>
      <description>Mala and Vinod  Life update time. If you&amp;rsquo;re a keen follower of this site, you&amp;rsquo;ll have noticed the little box in the upper left hand corner announcing my wedding to Mala. We got married a few months back and it was documented in photos by friends, family and even an official photographer. (Time wasting warning: There are 500 pictures from friends and family, 1200+ proofs from our photographer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>She said YES!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/27/she-said-yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/27/she-said-yes/</guid>
      <description>And I&amp;rsquo;m so happy!
{: .inset width=500}
Comments from old site Congratulations
 :) Jade Rubick 2004-09-27 12:40:29   Nice
 May all your troubles be *little ones*. ;-) Carl Robert Blesius 2004-09-27 17:58:23   Congratulations
 Hey Vin that&#39;s great, you two make a great looking couple, I wish you many happy years together. Again Congratulations. Andy Drout 2004-09-27 18:18:54   Congratulations Dude
 I&#39;m excited that I&#39;m gonna have a brother :) Puja Puri 2004-09-29 20:46:14   Best wishes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let there be light!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/16/let-there-be-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/16/let-there-be-light/</guid>
      <description>The power finally came back on at around 7:20 PM tonight. I was sitting on my futon trying as hard as I could not to sweat, when I heard a loud cheer from the courtyard and saw that the lights had gone on in the apartments outside my window.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a weird couple of days. The power went out around 4:15 PM yesterday while I was looking up some labs in the preceptor&amp;rsquo;s room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India 2003</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/20/india-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/20/india-2003/</guid>
      <description>My parents and I went to India for 2 weeks. We spent a couple days in Delhi and then the rest of the time in Kerala. I thoroughly enjoyed myself and actually found the vacation relaxing. Kerala is more beautiful than I ever remember (somehow I seem to forget in between trips). It&amp;rsquo;s lush and green and the food is amazing. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to go back. Here are some pics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delay</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/06/20/delay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/06/20/delay/</guid>
      <description>OK, OK&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s been way too long since I&amp;rsquo;ve updated this page. I just moved to Manhattan to take a job as an internist at Metropolitan Hospital. I&amp;rsquo;ve got pics from a mini-residency-reunion as well as an awesome trip to the Grand Canyon that I need to put up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bunch of stuff</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/26/bunch-of-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/26/bunch-of-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Life has been moving too quickly for me to document my menial existence. Check back again soon when my existence is not so menial! In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a Cliff Note&amp;rsquo;s version (may Cliff rest in peace) of the past 5 months (in no particular order).
 I left medicalrecords.com I began doing freelance web development I finished a Palm-based interface for The Answer Page I began moonlighting at MIT&amp;rsquo;s After Hours Medical Center, thus getting in touch with my &amp;ldquo;medical&amp;rdquo; side again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerry &amp; Kim</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/09/06/gerry-kim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/09/06/gerry-kim/</guid>
      <description>My roommate Gerry has somehow tricked Kim into getting engaged! :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Massachusetts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/12/06/back-to-massachusetts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/12/06/back-to-massachusetts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started a new rotation in at a chronic rehab hospital in Waltham, Massachusetts. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a different pace from any other work I&amp;rsquo;ve done before. I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning a lot about bed sores and tube feeding!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night shifts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/09/14/night-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/09/14/night-shifts/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be here in Green Bay for a little while longer, probably until Thanksgiving. So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working mostly night shifts, bringing back vivid memories of &amp;lsquo;night float&amp;rsquo; during residency. Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying it. Everyone&amp;rsquo;s really nice and welcoming. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a change from residency when you&amp;rsquo;re the low man on the totem pole. The patient population is more primary care oriented. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen one transplant patient so far, wheras I used to see almost one-a-day in residency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to the homeland!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/08/06/going-to-the-homeland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/08/06/going-to-the-homeland/</guid>
      <description>I found out recently that I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending 3 weeks (maybe longer) in Green Bay, WI. I&amp;rsquo;ll be working as a hospitalist at St. Vincent&amp;rsquo;s Hospital (Prevea HealthCare). It&amp;rsquo;s a 580 bed hospital with 40 ICU beds and I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing 12 hour shifts - mostly day shifts, but a couple nights. It should be fun! I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to being back in Wisconsin, especially Green Bay, for football season. Go PACKERS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/15/waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/15/waiting/</guid>
      <description>Still waiting to hear where my first assignment will be. Possibilities include a VA Hospital in Maine, a hospitalist practice in Green Bay, WI, a practice in Racine, WI, or an outpatient practice in Minnesota. Details to follow&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Done with residency</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/02/done-with-residency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/02/done-with-residency/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally finished my internal medicine residency at New England Medical Center. WooHoo! I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to be a real doctor now&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m planning to spend the next year as a locum tenens physician. I&amp;rsquo;ll be travelling throughout the country, working for 1-2 months at a time. Hopefully, I will get a broad exposure to different types of primary care medicine, so that I can make an informed decision down the road.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>