<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: wedding | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/wedding/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-08T21:26:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 weddings, 5 babies, 2 graduations and a dog]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog"/>
    <updated>2006-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/mala-nyc.jpg" width="500" alt="IMG_5830.JPG" /></p>

<p>I love taking pictures with my trusty old Canon S200. It takes great pics and I get to take the credit. I'm just horrible about getting them off my camera and onto my website. I finally uploaded a <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/?folder_id=61013">whole bunch</a> today, dating back to early May when we went to <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71973">Philadelphia for Kevin and Joanne's wedding</a>. The next group is from <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71975">Brooklyn and Staten Island for Mary Ann and Benjeil's wedding</a>. We interrupted wedding season to watch <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71979">Ethan graduate from law school</a> in Minneapolis. While in the Twin Cities, we got to spend a few minutes with <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=73510">Ajay</a>. Back home, we started <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71981">Memorial Day in the Cloisters</a>, had lunch in the city (photo above), and finished the day by meeting a cute girl named <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=73401">Amalie</a> (of Amalie &amp; Ivory fame!). A week later we were back in the Midwest for <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71983">Sivan's cozy high school graduation</a>. Nothing like watching your nephew graduate from high school to make you feel old. <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=74486">Mike and Susan threw a barbecue in Long Island</a> to celebrate their farewell. <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=74502">Asha</a> was there too! Next up on the wedding circuit were <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71985">Russ and Michelle</a>. They were nice enough to get married in DC, so we were able to stay with Puja and meet <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=74305">Loki</a>. <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71987">Mala interviewed in Norfolk</a> where we were introduced to <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/photo?photo_id=74063">Kylee</a> for the first time.</p>

<p>And if that's not enough for you, here are some <a href="http://kurup.org/photo/album?album_id=71977">random pics from the Bronx</a>. I'm sad to say that I've yet to take any photos of <a href="http://kurup.org/dave/photo/photo?photo_id=71894">Hunter June</a>, so I'll point you instead to <a href="http://kurup.org/dave/photo/album?album_id=67042">her parents' photos</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Update: The Honeymoon]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon"/>
    <updated>2005-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/napa-etched-door.jpg" alt="Amazing etched door" />{: .inset .right height=150 width=113} We honeymooned in California Wine Country. We stayed at the <a href="http://www.winecountryhilton.com/">Hilton in Santa Rosa</a>, about halfway between Napa and Sonoma. In Napa, we visited <a href="http://www.sterlingvineyards.com/">Sterling</a>, <a href="http://www.peju.com/">Peju</a>, <a href="http://www.vsattui.com/">V. Sattui</a> and <a href="http://www.artesawinery.com/">Artesa</a>. I enjoy wine, but not to the point that I can tell the difference between a good wine and a great one. So, I grade vineyards on different criteria. Go to Sterling for the view and the self-guided tour. Go to Peju to see the stained glass and the etched door. Go to V. Sattui for the free wine tasting, the gourmet deli and the picnic area. Go to Artesa because, well, it's a nice stop on the way back to San Francisco.</p>

<p>I had my first-ever massage at the <a href="http://www.goldenhaven.com/">Golden Haven Hot Springs</a> in Calistoga. We also did the couples mud-bath and spa. They say the mud in Calistoga is therapeutic because of the hot springs. It seemed like regular old mud to me.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ribeye.jpg" alt="Mmmm Ribeye" />{: .inset .left height=150 width=113} <img src="/images/mirepoix.jpg" alt="Mirepoix" />{: .inset .left height=150 width=113} Our favorite meal was at <a href="http://www.aubergedusoleil.com/html/restaurant.shtml">Auberge du Soleil</a>. We had the tasting menu and every course was spectacular, especially the rib-eye. Get an outdoor table at sunset and you won't be disappointed. Thanks to Sarika for the recommendation. We found another quaint little place in Windsor called <a href="http://www.restaurantmirepoix.com/">Mirepoix</a>. The service was very friendly and the food was great. We were not as impressed with Greystone Restaurant - the Culinary Institute of America's restaurant. It was fine, but not as good as our other meals.</p>

<p>We liked hanging out at the vineyards in Sonoma better than Napa. It just seemed more relaxed and the wine tastings were cheaper. We tasted at <a href="http://www.ferrari-carano.com/">Ferrari Carano</a>, <a href="http://closdubois.com/">Clos du Bois</a> and <a href="http://www.simiwinery.com/">Simi</a>. Don't miss the meticulously manicured gardens at Ferrari Carano.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ferrari-carano.jpg" alt="Ferrari-Carano cellars" />{: .inset height=112 width=150} <img src="/images/mala-vinod-garden.jpg" alt="Beautiful garden" />{: .inset height=80 width=150} <img src="/images/fountain.jpg" alt="Peju fountain" />{: .inset height=112 width=150}</p>

<p><img src="/images/arch-rock.jpg" alt="Arch Rock" />{: .inset .left height=112 width=150} <img src="/images/tiny-mala.jpg" alt="Mala is tiny!" />{: .inset .right height=150 width=113} We had a bread, wine and cheese picnic in the <a href="http://www.russianrivertravel.com/parks-armstrong.htm">Armstrong Redwoods State Reserve</a>. We couldn't resist the draw of the Pacific Ocean, so we drove a couple hours west through some beautiful winding wooded roads. We declined the dip into the ocean because it was a bit chilly.</p>

<p><img src="/images/peter.jpg" alt="Sung &amp; Peter" />{: .inset .left height=150 width=113} We drove back to San Francisco, just in time, apparently, for the Ghirardelli Square Chocolate Festival. The crowds were huge. Who knew that <a href="/images/sf-chocolate.jpg">so many people loved chocolate</a>? Sung, Lei, Peter, Jay, Cody, Andy and Nicci celebrated our departure with some great Chinese food. What was the name of that place? The dumplings were amazing!</p>

<p>Our honeymoon was over, but our adventures aren't. Next in the series: Our trip to France! (This blog is getting exciting now, isn't it?)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We're married!]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married"/>
    <updated>2005-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/wedding-1.jpg" alt="Mala and Vinod" />{: .inset .left height=112 width=150} Life update time. If you're a keen follower of this site, you'll have noticed the little box in the upper left hand corner announcing my <a href="http://kurup.org/wedding">wedding to Mala</a>. We got married a few months back and it was documented in photos by <a href="http://kurup.org/wedding/photo-album/album?album_id=17012">friends, family</a> and even <a href="http://kurup.org/wedding/photo-album/album?album_id=17010">an official photographer</a>. (Time wasting warning: There are 500 pictures from friends and family, 1200+ proofs from our photographer).</p>

<p>My brother Manoj created a touching slide show which had our guests laughing and Mala and I cringeing. That hasn't made it to the website yet, but negotiations with the concerned parties are in progress ("C'mon Mala, it's not that embarrassing!"). We can't thank enough the people who made our wedding day magical. It was, without question, the happiest day of my life.</p>

<p>Next up in the "Life Update Series": <a href="/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon/">The Honeymoon</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
