<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: education | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/education/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-09T07:01:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[History of Indian Civilization]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2018/05/31/indian-civilization"/>
    <updated>2018-05-31T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2018/05/31/indian-civilization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I briefly mentioned finding the 2012 UCLA lecture series,
"<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93JMjX1XECo&amp;list=PLy3KRgc0HE8B4neta_B8LPM0G9UWy-Cqe">History of Indian Civilization</a>",
a <a href="/blog/2018/05/29/renaissance-man">couple days ago</a>. I'm about halfway through
and have found it thorougly illuminating. I learned a lot about India growing
up, but never in a formal way, so it's nice to have someone as skilled as Vinay
Lal connect all the loose threads into a coherent history. One of the things
that surprises me is that aside from the fact that classes are being streamed
over the internet, there is nothing different than the lectures I skipped (I
mean religiously attended!) about 20 years ago. It's a large auditorium of
students watching a very charismatic, knowledgeable speaker pacing at the front
of the class, occasionally making mostly-legible markings on a chalkboard. Not
that there's anything wrong with that. I learned a lot back in college and I'm
enjoying these lectures immensely. It just seems strange that so little has
changed in the university clasroom (at least this one from 2012) when so much
has changed in the world at large.</p>

<p>Actually, I find it reassuring that little has changed, at least in some
classes. There was a time when the ability to download the audio of any
university class was absolutely new. For me, that was around 2002 or so. I
listened to CS61A (UC Berkley's intro to CS course) and a few other similar
courses back then. The limitations of internet bandwidth and storage made
anything more than audio difficult back then. But now with those barriers
crushed, I was afraid that everything would be "multimedia", and not amenable to
listening while I commute to work. So, it's reassuring to find that audio-only
dissemination of knowledge is still a thing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medical Student Oral Presentations]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/18/medical-student-oral-presentations"/>
    <updated>2011-02-18T14:57:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/18/medical-student-oral-presentations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I enjoyed
<a href="http://twitter.com/FutureDocs/status/38428516961751040">@FutureDocs</a>'
<a href="http://futuredocsblog.com/2010/10/20/preparing-for-attending-rounds-some-things-don%E2%80%99t-change/">guide to medical student oral
presentations</a>,
so I thought I'd share the cheat sheet that I give to the medical
students and PA students when I start each teaching block. As she
mentioned, presentations always have to be tailored to the listener,
and each attending is different, so you'll see minor differences in
what I recommend.</p>

<p>To me, the most important aspects are organization and preparation. I
don't like to have the sense that the student is "winging it". Prepare
for each presentation like you are preparing to give a talk to a
roomful of people. For me, that meant practicing the presentation at
home and with the residents before I presented to an attending.</p>

<p>I also give each student a printed copy of the <a href="https://depts.washington.edu/medclerk/drupal/pages/Oral-Presentation-Guidelines">guidelines posted at
the University of Washington's medical education
site</a>. It
goes into more detail about all of these issues. My favorite portion
is the graph that they present, which I'll reproduce here:</p>

<p><img src="/images/uwash-med-student-presentation.png" title="Skip
 the Boring Stuff" alt="Listener Attention" /></p>

<p>Here's a <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/pub?id=1XjKZsHu_Q54rL9EwtPtS9via-hEs67H2fRDEs8eHAZc">printable copy of my cheat sheet</a>.</p>

<h3>Initial Presentation:</h3>

<p><strong>CC/ID</strong></p>

<p>Be Brief. Gets the listener primed for what type of case is going to be presented.</p>

<blockquote><p>This is a 33 year old male with a history of asthma who presents with a chief complaint of dyspnea.</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>HPI</strong></p>

<p>This is the meat of the presentation. Pretend that you're telling the
patient's story to a friend. How much information would they need to
really understand what the patient is going through? Think about it
from the patient's perspective. What was the tipping point that made
them seek medical attention? What have they tried to make things
better? Stay consistent in your timeline. I like to start at the last
point that the patient was completely well. In patients with chronic
illness, that is hard, so you may have to start at the last time that
they were "relatively" well.</p>

<blockquote><p>He was completely well (or "in his usual state of health" for chronically ill patients) until 5 days ago, when he noticed feeling short of breath after walking 300 feet to his mailbox. Over the course of the next 5 days, his dyspnea worsened to the point that he was short of breath at rest. He tried taking his albuterol inhaler, but felt no relief. Etc…</p></blockquote>

<p>It's also useful to split the HPI into 2 distinct sections. The first
part is the patient's story, as described above. In the second part,
you take that story and decide what a reasonable differential
diagnosis list would be after listening to the first part. Then
provide the listener with appropriate ROS and PMH items to help them
rule those other diagnoses out.</p>

<p><strong>PMH</strong></p>

<p>You may have mentioned a few of these in the CC, but repeat them
here. For most conditions, just list the diagnosis, but if it has
particular pertinence to the HPI, then provide more detail. Also, try
to give some indication of the severity of the condition for certain
conditions: CHF (EF), DM (A1C), COPD (FEV1).</p>

<blockquote><p>Past medical history includes Asthma. He has been hospitalized twice in the past year, and required mechanical ventilation in April. He also has hypertension and allergic rhinitis.</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Meds</strong></p>

<p>List meds like a robot :-) Include doses if they are important. You'll
learn the importance of doses with experience. In general, if the med
is related to the HPI, I want to know the dose. You can't go wrong by
just giving me the dose on each med. Just run through them quickly</p>

<p><strong>FH/SH/ROS</strong></p>

<p>You should obviously have done these portions of the interview, but if
 they were important, I would have wanted to hear about it in the
 HPI. (Pt lives in a nursing home… Pt smokes… etc.) It's OK to go over
 it quickly, but probably better to say:</p>

<blockquote><p>FH/SH/ROS is unremarkable aside from what was presented in HPI</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Exam</strong></p>

<p>List the VS: Temp/HR/BP/RR/O2 sat. Then provide an overall impression:</p>

<blockquote><p>In general, the patient appears tired and seemed to be in mild respiratory distress.</p></blockquote>

<p>Pertinent negatives and significant positives only:</p>

<blockquote><p>Lung exam was remarkable for diffuse expiratory wheezes with accessory muscle use. Cardiac exam confirmed tachycardia. There was no lower extremity edema and the remainder of the complete physical exam was normal.</p></blockquote>

<p>Be completely objective. Avoid downplaying your exam skills. It's OK
to get things wrong – it's often the best way to learn. Avoid patient
interpretations here.</p>

<p><strong>Labs/Xray/EKG/Procedures</strong></p>

<p>If it's all normal, OK to say it's all normal, but if any are
abnormal, I like to hear each value in that group.</p>

<p><strong>ER course</strong></p>

<p>Brief sentence on what happened in the ER before you saw the patient.</p>

<p><strong>Assessment/Plan</strong></p>

<p>Second juicy part of the presentation. Identify each problem and go
one by one. Put the most pressing issue first. If the diagnosis is in
question, give me a differential diagnosis and let me know what we're
doing to rule out items on the differential. If the diagnosis is
relatively certain, present me with various therapeutic options and
the reason why you chose the one you did.</p>

<p>Think about "goals of care", if appropriate</p>

<p>Always mention disposition. What are we looking for before the patient
can be discharged? In some cases, this will be nebulous, but at least
mention it. "Disposition is unclear at this point because of X"</p>

<p><strong>Overnight course</strong></p>

<p>What happened after you put your plan in place? Brief status report on
how patient is doing today.</p>

<h3>Subsequent Day Presentations:</h3>

<p><strong>1 line about patient</strong>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Ms Jones is our 87 year old woman here with an aspiration pneumonia</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Overnight course</strong>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Since yesterday's rounds, she has had a speech evaluation and they recommended a video swallow study. She had one temperature spike to 38.5 degrees and blood cultures were drawn. She appears to more comfortable this morning, though she is still confused.</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Exam</strong>: Vitals, superquick exam describing pertinents only</p>

<p><strong>Labs</strong>: Any new labs that came back since we met for rounds yesterday.</p>

<p><strong>Plan for today</strong>: Go by problem again.</p>

<blockquote><p>Problem 1: aspiration pneumonia, she's on D3 of Zosyn and we will continue to followup cultures. Overall she seems improved, but we'll have to continue to monitor her mental status and oxygenation for further improvement. Problem 2: Altered mental status: This is almost certainly due to her pneumonia, but if it does not improve by tomorrow, we may consider other etiologies. At that point, repeat labs, EKG, and head CT may be indicated.  ... Problem 53: Disposition ...</p></blockquote>

<p>Be prepared to answer questions if you have been appropiately brief!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Literature delivered to your inbox]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox"/>
    <updated>2007-03-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://dailylit.com">DailyLit.com</a> is an interesting service that takes classic books and chops them up in to bite-sized pieces that you can read in just a few minutes. It then emails you one piece at a time until you finish the book. You can customize how often you get the emails.</p>

<p>I just finished "The Art of Money Getting", by P.T. Barnum. It has a lot of practical advice, and predates (by 100 years) a lot of what you see these days in self-help books. There are a lot of gems in here, but this is one of my favorite quotes:</p>

<blockquote><p>Strict honesty, not only lies at the foundation of all success in life (financially), but in every other respect. Uncompromising integrity of character is invaluable. It secures to its possessor a peace and joy which cannot be attained without it--which no amount of money, or houses and lands can purchase.</p></blockquote>

<p>I can't wait to figure out what I'm reading next.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Osteoporosis Talk]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/12/24/osteoporosis-talk"/>
    <updated>2006-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/12/24/osteoporosis-talk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I gave the residents a talk on osteoporosis at noon conference on Friday. Here's the powerpoint slides that I created, in case they might be useful to anyone. They're licensed under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org">Creative Commons</a> license and available in 2 formats - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenDocument">ODP (good)</a> and PPT (bad).</p>

<p>Medical information changes constantly, so hopefully these will be useful until at least the end of 2006. I've also uploaded slides from previous talks on Abnormal Liver Function Tests and Adult Immunizations.</p>

<ul>
<li>Osteoporosis: <a href="/medicine/osteoporosis/op.odp">ODP</a> <a href="/medicine/osteoporosis/">View online</a></li>
<li>Adult Immunizations: <a href="/medicine/adult-immunizations/adult-immunization.odp">ODP</a> <a href="/medicine/adult-immunizations/">View online</a></li>
<li>Abnormal LFT's: <a href="/medicine/lft/lft.odp">ODP</a> <a href="/medicine/lft/">View online</a></li>
</ul>


<!--Creative Commons License-->


<p><a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/"><img alt="Creative Commons License" style="border-width: 0" src="http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/2.5/88x31.png"/></a>This work is licensed under a <a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.5  License</a>.<!--/Creative Commons License--><!-- <rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#">    <work rdf:about="">         <license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/" />   </work>     <license rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/"><permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction"/><permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution"/><requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice"/><requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution"/><permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/DerivativeWorks"/><requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/ShareAlike"/></license>&lt;/rdf:RDF> --></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
