<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>investing on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/investing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in investing on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 16:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/investing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Market Timing</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/19/stock-market-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 16:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/19/stock-market-timing/</guid>
      <description>If you asked me a few years ago, I would have said you absolutely can&amp;rsquo;t time the stock market. The 2008 crash hurt enough to make me review my convictions a little. I still believe that accurate market timing is somewhere between difficult and impossible. Trying to analyze stock charts to figure out what will happen in the short term is mostly a crap shoot. The way to win in the stock market is to buy value stocks, especially when everyone else is selling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes to a younger investor</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/10/04/notes-to-a-younger-investor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/10/04/notes-to-a-younger-investor/</guid>
      <description>A friend asked for some investing advice a few years ago. Here was my response.
I have a feeling this is going to be long&amp;hellip; :-)
First thing - I don&amp;rsquo;t know your exact financial situation, but I know you&amp;rsquo;re in great shape for the long run. Anyone thinking this seriously about their finances this early in life will do fine. Also, since I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about your exact situation, this may be a little &amp;lsquo;condescending&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belated Investment Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/03/belated-investment-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/03/belated-investment-update/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s also get caught up with my investments. I last updated in May 2006 when I bought STS, JAX, EEI, KEYN and RSC.
At my next quarterly evaluation in August 2006, I sold DSWL at a loss of 16.7% because I had held it for 2 years and it no longer met my criteria for a stock I would want to buy. I bought SYPR and BSET.
In November 2006, I sold SEMI because it reported a negative quarter on top of negative trailing 12 month earnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Performance 1996-2006</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/01/07/investment-performance-1996-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/01/07/investment-performance-1996-2006/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s my 2006 Investment Performance update. My individual stock picks broke their 4 year winning streak versus the S&amp;amp;P500 and overall (including my 403b), I lagged the market by a couple percentage points. That makes for a pretty lousy year overall. So, is it time to switch tactics? Give in and stick all my money in an index fund? Some would say yes (or more like &amp;ldquo;YES, you IDIOT!&amp;rdquo;). I knew when I started this approach that there would be times where I would underperform, even for long periods of time, meaning 1-2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bizjournal inaccuracy</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/07/24/bizjournal-inaccuracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/07/24/bizjournal-inaccuracy/</guid>
      <description>Blair Corp, a company in my portfolio, announced second quarter earnings today. They were disappointing, but not as disappointing as reported by bizjournals.
&amp;ldquo;Blair Corp. swings to loss&amp;rdquo; is the title of the article. While dramatic, it&amp;rsquo;s completely wrong.
 Blair Corp., a catalog clothing retailer and direct marketer, reported a loss in the second quarter as sales fell nearly 5 percent.
 False. They reported a profit of $233,000 in the second quarter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update - May 2006</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/11/investment-update-may-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/11/investment-update-may-2006/</guid>
      <description>I sold 3 stocks (OUTL, MRINA.PK and KBALB) and bought 5 (RSC, JAX, EEI, KEYN and STS).
 Sold stocks Purchased Total Return Reason for sell  Outlook Group ([OUTL](http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=OUTL)) Feb 2005 67.65% OUTL is being acquired and taken private at $13.50 per share in a transaction scheduled to close sometime this summer. I decided to sell now at $13.20 rather than wait a few months for an extra 30 cents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>finance.google.com</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/21/finance.google.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/21/finance.google.com/</guid>
      <description>Google just launched it&amp;rsquo;s new financial website, finance.google.com. It combines a lot of information in 1 page and the adjustable graph at the top of a stock&amp;rsquo;s page is just WAY cool. You can focus in on any period of time and see news &amp;amp; reports from that period. They&amp;rsquo;ve also added blog posts as a news source.
It&amp;rsquo;s the ideal place to get a quick snapshot of a stock. Lots of information in a very quick-loading page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COBR starts paying dividends</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/cobr-starts-paying-dividends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/cobr-starts-paying-dividends/</guid>
      <description>Cobra Electronics (COBR) annouced quarterly results on Thursday. Revenue was up a little. Net income was up a lot, but mostly due to one time events. The market wasn&amp;rsquo;t impressed and the stock fell 8%. Day to day price changes don&amp;rsquo;t worry me, so that&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;m writing about. I mentioned back in July that I was concerned about the cash hoard that Cobra was amassing. Specifically I said:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing nothing</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/08/doing-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/08/doing-nothing/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time for my quarterly investment update. Every 3 months, I look at my portfolio and sell stocks that I don&amp;rsquo;t like and then buy ones that I do. This quarter, I&amp;rsquo;m doing nothing.
This is one of the hardest things for me to do. I like to trade. Sell a stock here, buy a new one here. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting. Especially when you sell a stock that&amp;rsquo;s been down for a while because then you no longer have to look at that red smirch on your portfolio every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Performance 1996-2005</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/05/investment-performance-1996-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/05/investment-performance-1996-2005/</guid>
      <description>As promised last year, here&amp;rsquo;s my 2005 Investment Performance update. My 403b account (VFINX, VWNDX, VEXPX and VTRIX) was up 6.7% and my individual stock investments were up 22.0% as compared to the stock market (VFINX) being up 4.7%. That makes 4 years in a row that my overall investments have beat the index and 2 years in a row that my stock picks have. It&amp;rsquo;s that second comparison that is most important to me - my individual stock picks versus the index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investments: Quarterly Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/01/investments-quarterly-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/01/investments-quarterly-update/</guid>
      <description>DUCK lost money both in its most recent quarter and over the past 12 months, so I sold it. I wish I&amp;rsquo;d been smarter about the way I sold it. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t decided which new stocks to buy yet, so instead of just selling DUCK and sitting in cash, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d using a trailing-stop order. With a regular stop, you tell your broker to sell the stock once the price drops below a certain point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBGI</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/07/sbgi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/07/sbgi/</guid>
      <description>Andy asked:
 Hey Vin, what do you think of SBG (Sinclair Broadcast Group) Its the company that owns Channels 18 and 24(my employer). Andy
 I took a quick look at SBGI and would probably avoid it. The first place I always look is the market cap. At 700 million, it&amp;rsquo;s a little bigger than the companies I&amp;rsquo;m investing in. The second place I look is the balance sheet and SBGI&amp;rsquo;s scares me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarterly Sells</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/01/quarterly-sells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/01/quarterly-sells/</guid>
      <description>I try to do my portfolio cleanup every 3 months, selling any companies that don&amp;rsquo;t fit my strategy and buying new ones that do. So, I&amp;rsquo;m selling 5 stocks. I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided on my buys yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m looking at BAMM, BZ, CALM, ESP, PWX, SCX and SRT (among others).
   Stock Purchase Date Total Return Reason for sell     Ameron (AMN) 7/7/2004 11.27% No improvement in the financial results over the past year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobra (COBR) announces great results</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/29/cobra-cobr-announces-great-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/29/cobra-cobr-announces-great-results/</guid>
      <description>Cobra Industries (COBR) announced their second quarter results today. I bought COBR in February 2005 because they seemed really undervalued (based on Price/Book and Price/Earnings ratios). They make CB radios, 2-way radios, radar detectors, and are starting to make handheld GPS devices. Cobra owns around 60% of the CB radio market, 20% of the 2-way radio market and 60% of the radar-detector market. They&amp;rsquo;ve just started in the GPS market and their major product, the NavOne 3000, seems like a flop so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding dirt in the footnotes</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/06/27/finding-dirt-in-the-footnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/06/27/finding-dirt-in-the-footnotes/</guid>
      <description>Footnoted.org is a blog that delves into SEC filings looking for those juicy details that companies are trying to hide from investors. Mainly, these details include things like excessive executive compensation or shady related-party transactions. You don&amp;rsquo;t want companies that you&amp;rsquo;re invested in to show up on her blog (except on Fridays when she tries to find companies that are doing responsible things).
Footnoted.org recently highlighted Flagstar Bank (FBC) because they&amp;rsquo;ve announced that their auditor resigned, their CFO resigned without citing a reason, and finally that he was still being paid as a consultant at a higher salary than he was as an employee ($60,000 per month vs $30,000 per month).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Performance 1996 - 2004</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/04/investment-performance-1996-2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/04/investment-performance-1996-2004/</guid>
      <description>OK, it&amp;rsquo;s well past the end of 2004 and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally calculated how my investments have done for the year. I&amp;rsquo;ve also analyzed my overall investment results since I started investing in 1996.
These are calculated using the XIRR function in OpenOffice. The XIRR function takes a series of cash flows in or out of an account and returns the internal rate of return for that account. It&amp;rsquo;s the best way to compare portfolio returns when investments or withdrawals are made on an irregular basis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>