<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: boston | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/boston/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-07T22:17:08-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boston with little kids]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/06/30/boston-with-little-kids"/>
    <updated>2011-06-30T11:50:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/06/30/boston-with-little-kids</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm sorry, but I just can't believe it's been almost 10 years since I
left Boston. Mala had a meeting there and we love to take advantage of
our employers' generosity <a href="Makes">^1</a>, so I TrippedIt <a href="Is">^2</a> back to Boston for
some nostalgia with 2 kids in tow (Ages 4 and 2). Buildings and
restaurants have come and gone <a href="Where">^3</a>, but it seems like so little has
changed in 10+ years. I forgot how "unfriendly" the city was. The trip
was a few weeks ago, so it's not fresh in my mind anymore, but I
remember thinking that vividly while I was there. You get the sense
that everyone has their shields up (or their guns drawn, to mix
metaphors) for whatever reason. None of the experiences were horrible,
but it was little things... Bathrooms are "broken" in every fast food
restaurant. Restaurants have arcane rules: "No, we only do takeout
after 3PM" or "Cash Only - there's an ATM over there". Customer
service people must be groomed to be rude. We're members of the
(AWESOME!)  <a href="http://www.ncmls.org/">Durham Museum of Life and Science</a>
which gives us free entry to science museums around the country, so we
walked up to the Members desk at Boston's version (Museum of Science)
and promptly got lectured about how we weren't really members and next
time we should go in the Nonmembers line. (Um, we're visiting from
North Carolina... there's probably not going to be a next time anytime
soon). I actually turned around and looked at all of the people behind
me and apologized for our rudeness. Wait! There was no one else
waiting! Just makes you feel small, which burns me up, because I know
that was her objective. I know none of that seems all that bad, but
that general attitude seemed prevalent and brought back memories of
Boston that I had repressed. We all had a great time in Boston, but I
am so glad that I'm living in North Carolina.</p>

<p>Wow, that little interlude took me from excited to depressed in no
time flat. Enough of that. Let's talk about the fun stuff we did. We
always research on the web to get a sense of things Kavi and Anika
might like. I had trouble finding good first-person stories about
<strong>Boston trips with little kids</strong>, so here's mine, in case someone has 2
kids exactly like ours. If this is useful, or if you have stuff to
add, please leave a comment or point to your blog.</p>

<h3>Things the kids loved:</h3>

<ul>
<li>Being in Boston: "We're in BOSTON!"</li>
<li>Walking the streets and seeing all kinds of vehicles: Taxis, buses,
trolleys, Ducks, police cars, and most excitingly, Minivans!.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/74NPRUFqKCQ7b1UdhOcphw?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-udiiy9uwK0I/Tf_Cs_JZjSI/AAAAAAAAStM/idfT4DGvVIg/s400/IMG_1819.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.marybakereddylibrary.org/exhibits/mapparium">Mapparium</a> at Mary Baker Eddy Library:
Kavi talked about this a lot for the rest of the trip, but at the
time didn't seem all that impressed by it. He was intrigued by the
fact that I wasn't allowed to take pictures inside it. He also liked
the Hall of Ideas and the computerized art programs upstairs.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bostoncentral.com/activities/parks/p2055.php">Boston Common Carousel</a>:
It's a carousel. Of course they loved it!
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/m-xAmdHOY3Oj7RLV7GqrfQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-VHxkS2HOz98/Tf_CIWq5aBI/AAAAAAAASn0/4OkxOELTRkM/s400/IMG_1565.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.swanboats.com/">Swan boats</a>:
Definitely a must-do. It's short and sweet.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/b3pFVNPd_qZN9f2aAxkOMg?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-fr-r42kU5Jk/Tf_CPpJ_PLI/AAAAAAAASo8/sShUbKnk9ak/s400/IMG_1633.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.schon.com/public/ducklings-boston.php">Ducklings in the Garden</a>:
Dressed in Bruins outfits while we were there. Those poor ducks were
constantly surrounded by little ones.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/gzG8lLrumqPoaaDWT89pCQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-JXMBbVQC5ss/Tf_B6IyTv-I/AAAAAAAASl4/EYX2c4gS4vI/s400/IMG_1483.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li>Boston Commons and Garden:
There's plenty of stuff for the kids to see and do here, but they're not so big that you'll get lost (think Central Park).
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/mAwQUzWgDQJEPExhJnUA4A?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Rdh48Xnk-14/Tf_CcSdfDBI/AAAAAAAASqY/29JAz9fhlcA/s400/IMG_1705.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://gocitykids.parentsconnect.com/attraction/boston-common-playground-boston-common-boston-ma-02111-us">Boston Commons Playground</a>:
Every parent on a trip knows that step one is finding all the local
playgrounds. This is a nice one and was close to the hotel. That
meets all the necessary requirements. By the way, while putting this
post together, I found this nice listing of <a href="http://gocitykids.parentsconnect.com/sub-category/boston-ma-usa/places-to-go/outdoors/playgrounds">playgrounds in Boston</a>.</li>
<li>Playground on Tremont:
We found a much smaller playground between the Hotel and NEMC that
Kavi and Anika liked a little better, mostly because they had it all
to themselves.</li>
<li>Playgrounds on the Charles River:
Take the bridge over to the Hatch shell, go left (west) and walk for
about half a mile. Nestled between Storrow Drive and the Charles
River, there's plenty to watch and play with. Kavi and Anika really
liked the little car. Oh, and if you happen to go right (east)
instead of left, there's a great playground near the tennis
courts, which is on the way to the Museum of Science. <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/VU9ZILbVTM3WjUQf8ewOVA?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ZyXEp8eIv8E/Tf_CXQ8c-II/AAAAAAAASp0/RwBruXMUjrI/s400/IMG_1675.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hatchshell.com/">Hatch shell</a>:
There was an AIDS race while we were there which meant lots of people and
balloons to keep the kids occupied. I heard it gets crazy on July
4th :-)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mos.org/">Museum of Science</a>:
Aside from the annoying registration employee, this was fun. The
<a href="http://www.mos.org/exhibits_shows/current_exhibits&amp;d=233">Discovery
Center</a>
didn't open for an hour, so we explored the regular museum
first. Most of it was above Kavi and Anika's age level, so they were
getting bored/overwhelmed. The Discovery Center was better, though we
didn't find the best part (the upstairs level) until near the end of
our stay. Kavi's favorite thing was watching the pneumatic tube
system. The volunteers up there were really engaging as well. <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/6tj5VGYyO33R1oOoJJII2A?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-92-8sBu_bEI/Tf_CxW7oNaI/AAAAAAAASuI/0kfvbLMTSvo/s400/IMG_1864.JPG" height="400" width="300" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bostonkids.org/exhibits.html">Children's Museum</a>:
The museum with the "rabbit sitting on top" and the big milk
bottle on the side. Predictably loved by Kavi and Anika.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.neaq.org">New England Aquarium</a>:
The kids were underwhelmed. They liked the
<a href="http://www.vanaqua.org/">Vancouver</a> and
<a href="http://www.georgiaaquarium.org/">Atlanta</a> ones more. We spent most
of our time in the toddler area playing with toys that are normally
found in doctors' waiting rooms. I think they'll love this in a
couple years. <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/UloiGxYpoMj-eJQ62shPrQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-GfsPi7jlpUE/Tf_BztUhHBI/AAAAAAAASlU/-iCxRKEUIMs/s400/IMG_1451.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://mbta.com">The T</a>:
We could have just ridden the T every day. It was loud, which freaks
Kavi out a bit, but not as loud as New York. We rode on the blue
line to get to the aquarium, and the Green line to come back to the
Hotel. He especially liked the Green line because the "floor turns". <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/a6oatS480Dl82Cs8vM6KXA?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-HmXUq5s0sK4/Tf_BywQN-kI/AAAAAAAASlM/eIse1aEcfhE/s400/IMG_1439.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bostonparkplaza.com/">Park Plaza</a>:
A decent hotel. Living mostly on reputation and location. I guess
we've been spoiled by modern hotels in other cities, so the Park
Plaza seemed dingy and overpriced. But the location is awesome, work was
paying for it, and our kids love any hotels, so I recommend it.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Dining:</h3>

<ul>
<li>Vapiano (pseudo-italian restaurant where Bennigan's used to be):
The kids liked their pastas and like sitting at the little tables.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.jaescafe.com/">Jae's Cafe</a>:
Not really a kids thing, but we went early on a weeknight and had a
really nice dinner. They have "training" chopsticks that the kids loved.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/-NPr0GAaytlcornbA7v9vg?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-wts4MU8llwA/Tf_Cgcrx0AI/AAAAAAAASrA/CUFx_h9mQdY/s400/IMG_1732.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mikescitydiner.com/">Mike's City Diner</a>: (Ouch, Flashy website)
Our first breakfast stop and we returned a few days later which is a
huge endorsement. Avoid it on weekends though, because it's
packed. Cash only. <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/HSbAj63Z9vcSgMhKWbkVmQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-MF8LJX6QkDM/Tf_B846X18I/AAAAAAAASmQ/ad_LUNxHneQ/s288/IMG_1505.JPG" height="216" width="288" /></a>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/RLS9xJP1S4jbCwxFC6m7JQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-ho4QA_1CRz8/Tf_B9yDYPgI/AAAAAAAASmY/q8qI5CTVJbs/s288/IMG_1506.JPG" height="216" width="288" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/charlies-sandwich-shoppe-boston">Charlie's Sandwich Shoppe</a>:
Another great breakfast place. We went on Kavi's birthday and were
just about the only ones in the restaurant, so the entire staff sang
Happy Birthday and put a candle on his pancake. He was so
thrilled. Cash only.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/gjT3uIvumJMC2YNhJRXzpg?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-zox0d2diKaM/Tf_Ckj9fGrI/AAAAAAAASr0/eBk3nvUaKUM/s400/IMG_1747.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li>Legal Seafood:
Quick dinner after arriving from the airport. Not the most kid
friendly place, but aside from a long wait, it was fine.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/oDgdkVHgyvxeagZs3GIhjw?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-4XoWN5kwIzE/Tf_BvZu_TVI/AAAAAAAASks/gPpBjKpnWoc/s400/IMG_1421.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li>Dunkin Donuts:
Nostalgic coffee and donuts, but NO BATHROOMS!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/asian-garden-boston">Asian Garden</a>:
The best salt &amp; pepper squid that I have ever had. Still as good as
I remember it 15 years ago! <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/bUxOVG-Gxd9RUfydEzit9Q?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-7kdUE3ux_Uc/Tf_B8KQJ1sI/AAAAAAAASmI/GDK1-ESwPxY/s400/IMG_1500.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li>Dim Sum at <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/hei-la-moon-boston">Hei La Moon</a>:
Mala was at her meeting, Anika was asleep and Kavi was sick, so only
I got to enjoy this luxury.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/4LTUcmjuT_01BGLu-dXjzg?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-nob5EC9E9kk/Tf_Ce-ukRXI/AAAAAAAASqw/WiNBBq-RoJ0/s400/IMG_1722.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li>North End (Boston's Little Italy):
We went to visit Mala's friends and had great take out. The walk
from the Park Plaza was nice, since it crossed the Garden, the
government center area and the North End, all of which had sights
that the kids enjoyed</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/croissant-du-jour-boston">Croissant Du Jour</a>:
Great breakfast food and sandwiches.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.finaledesserts.com/">Finale</a>:
We went here for Kavi's birthday dessert. Nowhere near as good as I
remember it being, but that might be because Mala is just an amazing
cook, so my standards have risen. <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/yagEwh3QcBswOTq0D_O1ZQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-M2Kx1_dLj0k/Tf_CwshBY8I/AAAAAAAASuA/y3DDBygZ1pU/s400/IMG_1835.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.parishcafe.com/index2.html">Parish Cafe</a>:
Sandwiches are awesome! We went there on Monday, which is the day
that we eat only veggies, so I couldn't try the Regis that I used to
love. The bread, though, was enough to satisfy my cravings. Sit
outside and the kids will be entertained by the constant traffic and
activity on Boylston Street.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Useful Android Apps:</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.yelp.android">Yelp</a>:
I downloaded a bunch of other ones including AAA Triptik, Tripadvisor,
HopStop, but I ended up using Yelp and Google Maps predominantly.</li>
<li><a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.tripit">TripIt</a>:
Not specific to Boston, but this app makes traveling easier. Keeps
track of all your flight info, hotel info and any other itinerary info
you want to stick into it.</li>
</ul>


<p>End result of the trip: Success!</p>

<p><a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/U9oMp1w9fSAl3RoGhwZWmA?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-m4RatvhjowA/Tf_Cfk0LnQI/AAAAAAAASq4/8ChBYs5WBCo/s640/IMG_1724.JPG" height="480" width="640" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
