<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cousins-trip on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/cousins-trip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cousins-trip on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/cousins-trip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>6th Annual Cousins Trip</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/06/6th-annual-cousins-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/06/6th-annual-cousins-trip/</guid>
      <description>Cousins Trip 2005 (photos) was in Lake George, NY this year. The weather didn&amp;rsquo;t quite cooperate this time. It was cloudy and rainy all week. Still, we were able to get in a great hike, some competitive bowling, basketball and mini-golf, not to mention enjoying the 2nd annual Elvis Festival. While we didn&amp;rsquo;t run into any bears, we did see plenty of wildlife. Of course, I would be a rumpcake if I were to forget to mention our late-night Taboo contests, the highlight of the trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall of water</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/08/11/wall-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/08/11/wall-of-water/</guid>
      <description>http://www.cnn.com/2004/US/West/08/05/wallofwater.ap/index.html (link now broken)
 The sudden release of water from Ralston Reservoir south of Auburn sent a &amp;ldquo;wall of water three to four-feet high&amp;rdquo; down the Middle Fork of the American River, said California Highway Patrol spokesman Tom Marshall.
 That&amp;rsquo;s the river that we rafted down a couple weeks ago during our 5th Annual Cousins Trip. If it had happened during our trip, I still probably would&amp;rsquo;ve been the first one to fall in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Seattle</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/14/more-seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/14/more-seattle/</guid>
      <description>Girish has put up some pics from the Seattle trip and other family events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4th Annual Cousins Reunion</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/31/4th-annual-cousins-reunion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/31/4th-annual-cousins-reunion/</guid>
      <description>We went whitewater rafting in Pennsylvania in 2000, sea-kayaking in North Carolina in 2001, and death-marching (er&amp;hellip; hiking) in the Grand Canyon in 2002. This year, we chose kayaking and hiking in Seattle.
We went kayaking near the San Juan Islands on Thursday. It was a great upper body workout and our guide Martine was a fountain of information. We saw some harbor seals close up and a bald eagle from afar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Grand Canyon</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/08/26/more-grand-canyon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/08/26/more-grand-canyon/</guid>
      <description>Manu sent me the pics that he took during our Grand Canyon trip. Thanks Manu!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grand Canyon Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/22/grand-canyon-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/22/grand-canyon-update/</guid>
      <description>I found some more pictures from the Phoenix trip, so check &amp;lsquo;em out again! And please don&amp;rsquo;t touch or sit on the Indians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pics</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/14/pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/14/pics/</guid>
      <description>Geoff organized a mini-residency-reunion back in June and somehow scammed Joyce and Howard into hosting it :-)
Manu, Girish, Deepu and I hiked the Grand Canyon in mid-June. I&amp;rsquo;m still not clear who decided it was a great idea to hike down to the Colorado River and back in 115 degree weather, but that may be due to the fact that I fried a good number of my brain cells that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bunch of stuff</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/26/bunch-of-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/26/bunch-of-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Life has been moving too quickly for me to document my menial existence. Check back again soon when my existence is not so menial! In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a Cliff Note&amp;rsquo;s version (may Cliff rest in peace) of the past 5 months (in no particular order).
 I left medicalrecords.com I began doing freelance web development I finished a Palm-based interface for The Answer Page I began moonlighting at MIT&amp;rsquo;s After Hours Medical Center, thus getting in touch with my &amp;ldquo;medical&amp;rdquo; side again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>