<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>parenting on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/parenting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in parenting on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 21:26:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/parenting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids and Computers</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/15/kids-and-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 21:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/15/kids-and-computers/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s probably too early to worry about this, but I often wonder about the best way to introduce Kavi and Anika to computers. &amp;lsquo;Introduce&amp;rsquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t the right word because even Anika has more experience with computers than I did at that age. So far, though, computers are something that Daddy and Mommy use to do work, not things that are for them. We&amp;rsquo;ll show them a Sesame Street video on YouTube or family pictures on Facebook, but they don&amp;rsquo;t spend any significant amount of time on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parenting Highs and Lows</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/03/parenting-highs-and-lows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 21:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/03/parenting-highs-and-lows/</guid>
      <description>Written a few weeks ago
I came home late today, so Anika and Kavi had already eaten dinner and taken their baths. As I drove down the driveway, I could see Kavi&amp;rsquo;s excited little head poking over the upstairs windowsill. I parked the car and opened the door into the house. I was immediately met a voice screaming, &amp;ldquo;Daddy, Daddy!&amp;rdquo; with pure joy in his voice. He ran down the stairs and gave me a huge hug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First full phone conversation with Kavi</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/06/first-full-phone-conversation-with-kavi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 21:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/06/first-full-phone-conversation-with-kavi/</guid>
      <description>I had my first full phone conversation with Kavi today. I was about to leave work, so I called home to let Mala know that I was on my way home. (For the second time&amp;hellip; I got called back to help in the ER on my first attempt, but that&amp;rsquo;s another story). When the phone rang, Kavi picked up the phone. &amp;ldquo;Hi Daddy, when are you coming home?&amp;rdquo; I told him that I was leaving now and that I&amp;rsquo;d be home in half an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PlayDoh</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/15/playdoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/15/playdoh/</guid>
      <description>Kavi&amp;rsquo;s bedroom - 8PM DADDY and KAVI are lying next to each other in KAVI&amp;rsquo;s bed doing their bedtime ritual. They have finished singing a song and are recapping the day.
DADDY: Did you play with playdoh today?
KAVI: No.
DADDY: Are you sure? Did you play with playdoh this morning before going to the Puffin room?
(KAVI thinks)
KAVI: Yes. I did. Why did I play with playdoh?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing up too fast</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/26/growing-up-too-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/26/growing-up-too-fast/</guid>
      <description>I love watching Kavi&amp;rsquo;s expressions. We took the kids to the Museum of Life and Science for a birthday party today. He&amp;rsquo;s been there plenty of times, mostly with Mala. I&amp;rsquo;ve been there a few times with him. It&amp;rsquo;s one of his (and I guess every kid&amp;rsquo;s) favorite places. Each time we go, it&amp;rsquo;s a vastly different experience. Everything seems new to him. His eyes light up with wonder and amazement at the exhibits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>