<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Running</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/running/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m a runner and have been for almost 30 years now. I suppose I&amp;rsquo;m only going to get slower from here on in, so I thought I should list all my PR&amp;rsquo;s so that I can brag while I can.
Here are my blog posts about running.
PRs  | Age &amp;lt;= 30 | Age &amp;gt; 30 | -----------+-----------+----------+ 800m | 2:12 | N/A | 1 mile | 5:07 | 5:44 | 2 mile | 11:06 | N/A | 5K | 18:36 | 23:02 | 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avik 7:30</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2019/04/08/avik-730/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 21:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2019/04/08/avik-730/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Here it comes!&amp;rdquo; His eyes light up.
Slurps one last sip from his small cup.
Then bounding from the kitchen table,
Fast as lighting, he is able
To trash his scraps and stow his dishes.
He yells to Mom, &amp;ldquo;It was delicious!&amp;rdquo;
One more breath then on the couch he lands.
&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s up?&amp;rdquo; says Mom. Dad shrugs his hands.
Big brother also has no idea.
Big sister sighs, &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s a weird one I fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triangle Race Series</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/12/20/triangle-race-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 20:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/12/20/triangle-race-series/</guid>
      <description>When we made our 2018 goals last year, Kavi, Anika and I all had some running-related goals. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember offhand exactly what each of our goals were, but I think we all wanted to run more races, because well, races are fun! I somehow stumbled on the Triangle Race Series. It&amp;rsquo;s a series of a couple dozen races throughout the year around the Triangle, so we signed up for a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Nest Journey</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/12/02/my-nest-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 23:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/12/02/my-nest-journey/</guid>
      <description>I got 2 Nest E thermostats because Duke Energy was having a sale around Black Friday. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any strong motivation to have a Nest. The idea of a smart home is cool, but most &amp;lsquo;smart&amp;rsquo; things nowadays have ended up being more work than benefit. Anyway, for $75 each, I thought it was worth a try. We have 2 thermostats so I decided to install the upstairs thermostat first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composting</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/09/23/composting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/09/23/composting/</guid>
      <description>Guess what, we&amp;rsquo;re composting now! I told you was going to be a gardener, so now you know I&amp;rsquo;m serious. For oh so many years, every Friday, we&amp;rsquo;d haul the garbage and recycling out and I&amp;rsquo;d think to myself, &amp;ldquo;Wow, we&amp;rsquo;d have like no garbage at all if we were composting.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s only taken a few years of thinking that, week in and week out, to get me to try. Actually, that&amp;rsquo;s not even true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a garden</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/09/22/starting-a-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/09/22/starting-a-garden/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to be a gardener. Yup, just decided. Well, re-decided, I guess, since we already have a garden. It&amp;rsquo;s a strip of dirt on the side of our house and we&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to grow vegetables the past couple years. But it has some problems. It&amp;rsquo;s way out of the way, so it&amp;rsquo;s a pain to check on it (since I&amp;rsquo;m lazy). The ground just underneath the topsoil is hard clay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Indian Civilization</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/05/31/history-of-indian-civilization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/05/31/history-of-indian-civilization/</guid>
      <description>I briefly mentioned finding the 2012 UCLA lecture series, &amp;ldquo;History of Indian Civilization&amp;rdquo;, a couple days ago. I&amp;rsquo;m about halfway through and have found it thorougly illuminating. I learned a lot about India growing up, but never in a formal way, so it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have someone as skilled as Vinay Lal connect all the loose threads into a coherent history. One of the things that surprises me is that aside from the fact that classes are being streamed over the internet, there is nothing different than the lectures I skipped (I mean religiously attended!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autovacuum not running</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/05/30/autovacuum-not-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/05/30/autovacuum-not-running/</guid>
      <description>OK, this is a debug session in progress, so don&amp;rsquo;t expect a nice solution at the end. We&amp;rsquo;re working on a project that does analysis of some public voter registration data. The DB is hosted on Amazon RDS and I&amp;rsquo;ve been perplexed by how poorly queries are performing there, despite the tables only have about 10 million rows. Simple queries are taking many minutes, which is orders of magnitude slower than my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renaissance Man</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/05/29/renaissance-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/05/29/renaissance-man/</guid>
      <description>I love this post by Austin Kleon. As someone who has found very few things that I don&amp;rsquo;t find intriguing in some way, it is nice to know that there are others like me and that maybe there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with that. I love being a doctor and I love being a programmer, and I love honing both of those crafts.
He also links to a 2012 New York Times article about a UCLA sophomore who spends 1 hour each day learning something new, mainly by taking online courses from other universities or watching how-to videos on YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using dynamic queries in a CBV</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/28/using-dynamic-queries-in-a-cbv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/28/using-dynamic-queries-in-a-cbv/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s play &amp;lsquo;Spot the bug&amp;rsquo;. We&amp;rsquo;re building a simple system that shows photos. Each photo has a publish_date and we should only show photos that have been published (i.e. their publish_date is in the past).
class PhotoManager(models.Manager): def live(self, as_of=None): if as_of is None: as_of = timezone.now() return super().get_query_set().filter(publish_date__lte=as_of) And the view to show those photos:
class ShowPhotosView(ListView): queryset = Hero.objects.live() Can you spot the bug? I sure didn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip; until the client complained that newly published photos never showed up on the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Emacs Posts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/23/some-emacs-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 21:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/23/some-emacs-posts/</guid>
      <description>A few cool Emacs posts have flown across my radar, so I&amp;rsquo;m noting them here for that time in the future when I have time to play with them.
 Get unicode glyphs to show properly. (╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻ Creating slides with org-mode and Reveal.js. Finally, a sane way to create a presentation :) Anzu: Improves incremental search. Anzu shows the number of matches found, and how many matches remain in the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pygments on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/22/pygments-on-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/22/pygments-on-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>I wrote my first blog post in a little while (ok, ok&amp;hellip; 18 months) yesterday and when I tried to generate the post, it failed. Silently failed, which is the worst kind of failure. I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure why it was silent, but I eventually was able to force it to show me an error message:
/home/vinod/.rbenv/versions/1.9.3-p286/lib/ruby/gems/1.9.1/gems/pygments.rb-0.3.4/lib/pygments/popen.rb:354:in `rescue in get_header&amp;#39;: Failed to get header. (MentosError) from /home/vinod/.rbenv/versions/1.9.3-p286/lib/ruby/gems/1.9.1/gems/pygments.rb-0.3.4/lib/pygments/popen.rb:335:in `get_header&amp;#39; from /home/vinod/.rbenv/versions/1.9.3-p286/lib/ruby/gems/1.9.1/gems/pygments.rb-0.3.4/lib/pygments/popen.rb:232:in `block in mentos&amp;#39; from /home/vinod/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create test models in Django</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/21/how-to-create-test-models-in-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 20:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/21/how-to-create-test-models-in-django/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s occasionally useful to be able to create a Django model class in your unit test suite. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re building a library which creates an abstract model which your users will want to subclass. There&amp;rsquo;s no need for your library to subclass it, but your library should still test that you can create a subclass and test out its features. If you create that model in your models.py file, then Django will think that it is a real part of your library and load it whenever you (or your users) call syncdb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peanut Allergy, a personal clinical review</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/21/peanut-allergy-a-personal-clinical-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 07:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/21/peanut-allergy-a-personal-clinical-review/</guid>
      <description>A Vignette A 22-month-old previously healthy girl was brought to the emergency room in respiratory distress. She had been well until the day of presentation. Shortly after disembarking from an airline flight, she developed cough with one episode of emesis. En route to the emergency room, her breathing became labored and she developed hives. She was diagnosed as having an allergic reaction and treated aggressively with IV methylprednisolone, IV diphenhydramine, inhaled albuterol, and oxygen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Priorities and GTD</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/17/priorities-and-gtd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 13:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/17/priorities-and-gtd/</guid>
      <description>Pre-GTD task management systems recommended that you assign a priority to each task. When looking at a list of tasks, you then choose the ones with the highest priority. David Allen (author of GTD) includes &amp;lsquo;priority&amp;rsquo; as one of the things that you should consider when you are deciding what to do, but only after you have considered context, time available, and energy available. Which makes sense. As Merlin Mann says, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if mowing your lawn is your highest priority when you&amp;rsquo;re sitting in an airplane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GTD again?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/16/gtd-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 09:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/16/gtd-again/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Merlin Mann&amp;rsquo;s recent series of podcasts on GTD, I&amp;rsquo;m getting back on the GTD wagon (for about the 100th time). I read Getting Things Done in 2002 and have been trying to implement it ever since. I&amp;rsquo;ve had periods where I followed it religiously for a month at a time, but it&amp;rsquo;s never completely stuck. From what I hear, this is normal and I accept it now. This won&amp;rsquo;t be the last time that I restart GTD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing paralysis</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/15/writing-paralysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 14:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/15/writing-paralysis/</guid>
      <description>I think twitter and facebook stunt my writing. The more that I read tweets, the more self-conscious I get when I write. Not that my writing is all that original, but I still feel that it is something that comes from me. I worry so much about presenting ideas of others as my own without even remembering that I had seen the ideas before. In the old days, the things that I read were long form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steal My Web App Idea</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/09/steal-my-web-app-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 22:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/09/steal-my-web-app-idea/</guid>
      <description>Now that we have 3 kids, I&amp;rsquo;m always internally comparing one to the other. Sure that&amp;rsquo;s not healthy and will probably breed resentment in them during their teenage years, but what&amp;rsquo;s a bad parent to do?
I need an app that takes 2 kids&amp;rsquo; birthdays and then shows me what day it was when the older kid was the age that the younger kid is now. Wow, that&amp;rsquo;s a confusing sentence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to change the rear tire on a 12 inch bicycle</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/12/30/how-to-change-the-rear-tire-on-a-12-inch-bicycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/12/30/how-to-change-the-rear-tire-on-a-12-inch-bicycle/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not the handiest guy in the world, so I&amp;rsquo;m pretty proud that I was able to fix a flat tire on Kavi&amp;rsquo;s 12&amp;rdquo; bicycle.
DISCLAIMER: I have almost no idea what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. Follow my instructions at your peril.
I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed flats before, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time. Fixing it on such a tiny bike was a lot harder than I thought. The manual makes it seem so simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSBrief gets the best guests</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/11/05/nsbrief-gets-the-best-guests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/11/05/nsbrief-gets-the-best-guests/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not an OS X programmer, but I&amp;rsquo;ve really enjoyed 2 recent episodes of the NSBrief podcast. First was Mark Dalrymple&amp;rsquo;s interview. Here was my 140 character description:
So much geeky fun in @borkware&amp;rsquo;s interview. AOLserver, dtrace, OpenDoc, MPW, need I go on? nsbrief.com/59-mark-dalrym…
&amp;mdash; Vinod Kurup (@vkurup) August 16, 2012 
Today, I listened to Mark Aufflick&amp;rsquo;s interview where he talks eloquently about starting your own business. I love the perspective he had on his first business and how shutting it down gave him the necessary (though painful) experience to make his current business work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Vinod Kurup</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my home page! (Yes, I know it&amp;rsquo;s 2012, but I still call it my home page). I&amp;rsquo;m probably the luckiest guy in the world, with a beautiful wife and 3 sweet, life-loving kids to prove it. I am a hospitalist working at a community hospital in North Carolina. I&amp;rsquo;m a Milwaukee Malayalee who hopes to retire in NYC someday. I am also a (free software) programmer, writer, runner, foodie, homeowner, reader, investor, in addition to about a hundred other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs for Python Programming</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/24/emacs-for-python-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 16:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/24/emacs-for-python-programming/</guid>
      <description>(Note: See the bottom of this post for updates)
I was honored to to give my &amp;ldquo;Emacs for Python Programming&amp;rdquo; talk at the inaugural PyCarolinas conference. The conference was a huge success in every way, thanks to the efforts of Calvin Spealman, et. al. I promised that I would post my Emacs setup, so here it is.
Step 0: Prerequisites This may work with other setups, but here&amp;rsquo;s what I tested:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicine</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/medicine/</guid>
      <description> Presentations Here are some presentations that I&amp;rsquo;ve made in the past. Feel free to use them, if you find them useful.
 Emacs for Python Programming PDF PPTX- Last updated October 2012 Osteoporosis (odp) - Last updated 2006 Adult Immunizations (odp) - Last updated 2004 Abnormal LFTs (odp) - Last updated 2003  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Autocomplete stumbles on yasnippet</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/15/emacs-autocomplete-stumbles-on-yasnippet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 13:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/15/emacs-autocomplete-stumbles-on-yasnippet/</guid>
      <description>Autocomplete Mode is an Emacs mode that tries to guess what word you&amp;rsquo;re typing and provide auto-completion. Recently, it started failing in simple scenarios.
It can use various &amp;lsquo;sources&amp;rsquo; to try to figure out what you&amp;rsquo;re about to type. The simplest source is ac-source-dictionary which is a simple list of words. If you start typing any of those words, it will try to autocomplete them for you. Normally, you&amp;rsquo;d put those words in a file, with each word on a separate line, but for testing purposes, you can also add them manually using an elisp function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve gone to the dark side</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/14/ive-gone-to-the-dark-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 16:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/14/ive-gone-to-the-dark-side/</guid>
      <description>I was a huge Apple fan growing up and IBM was Apple&amp;rsquo;s enemy. Buying an IBM computer would have been unthinkable.
Well, the unthinkable has happened. Of course IBM doesn&amp;rsquo;t make laptops anymore, but their computers live on under the Lenovo name. I am the proud owner of a new Lenovo Thinkpad T420S. I love this computer. It&amp;rsquo;s an ugly black boxy thing, but it&amp;rsquo;s light (4 lbs), quiet and speedy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avik Arrives!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/09/04/avik-arrives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 08:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/09/04/avik-arrives/</guid>
      <description>Anika, Kavi, Mala and I are so proud to announce the birth of healthy, happy baby boy!
His name is Avik Puri Kurup and he was born at 11:01 PM on September 3rd, 2012. He is 6lbs, 12oz and about 19 inches long.
A few pics:
 Avik arrives  Proud Dad  And the obligatory pseudo-nostalgic photo:
Nostalgic Avik  Mom and Baby are doing great! Thanks for all the well wishes and support!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Free Will</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/21/thoughts-on-free-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 12:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/21/thoughts-on-free-will/</guid>
      <description>Time for some pop philosophy. I&amp;rsquo;ve never thought too deeply about the concept of free will. Of course we have free will! I chose to live my life a certain way. I could choose to live a different way. It is my free will to choose how I live. I&amp;rsquo;ve never thought about it more deeply than that.
I recently read Walter Isaacson&amp;rsquo;s biography of Einstein and I was forced to think more deeply about free will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook is killing blogging</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/19/facebook-is-killing-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 07:58:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/19/facebook-is-killing-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Looks like August 18th was International-Prominent-Bloggers-Complain-About-Facebook-Killing-Blogging Day. I was just two weeks too early.
 Tim Bray: Blogodammerung Scott Hanselman: Your words are wasted Jon Udell: Where have all the bloggers gone?  On a side note, I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying Scott Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s podcast This Developer&amp;rsquo;s Life. It&amp;rsquo;s an homage to the awesome This American Life, but focused on programming issues. They interview interesting programmers, but they carefully edit the interviews to focus on the parts that are the most interesting, interspersing them with music and effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A great moment</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/16/a-great-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 10:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/16/a-great-moment/</guid>
      <description>I woke up, got ready and went downstairs. I am not a morning person. I try to do as little thinking as possible, because thinking eventually leads to the rational conclusion that I should just go back to bed. I get to the coffee machine, grab my plastic mug and start pouring. Suddenly, I&amp;rsquo;m woken from my daze. I hear little footsteps pounding across the hallway above me. I look towards the bottom of the stairs and see a little figure race around the corner with a determined, slightly fearful look in her face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Curiosity Lands</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/07/nasa-curiosity-lands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 15:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/07/nasa-curiosity-lands/</guid>
      <description>Like the rest of the geek world, we&amp;rsquo;ve been excited by Curiosity&amp;rsquo;s successful trip to Mars. Here&amp;rsquo;s a cool video which combines an animation of Curiosity&amp;rsquo;s landing mixed with the real reactions of the astronauts that got it there. (Found on thekidshouldseethis.com)
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been disappointed that real space travel is unlikely to become a reality during my life. I honestly thought it would when I was a kid. But watching Curiosity gives me hope that we will be able to continue exploring our universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Again</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/03/blogging-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 14:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/03/blogging-again/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to start blogging more. I know I&amp;rsquo;ve said that before, so take it for what it&amp;rsquo;s worth. I think there is value in blogging. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about my life a lot lately, trying to find what makes me tick. One of those things that gets me excited is programming. I started thinking about that and remembered this meme that had passed around the blog world a few years back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Factoring Large Numbers</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/11/29/on-factoring-large-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 21:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/11/29/on-factoring-large-numbers/</guid>
      <description>I wonder how many of my blog posts are based on stories from This American Life. Probably not enough. Every time I start to listen to a show, I&amp;rsquo;m certain that I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be interested and within a minute I&amp;rsquo;m trapped and can&amp;rsquo;t stop listening. It&amp;rsquo;s that good. A recent show was about people who people who pursued crazy ideas. The first story was about a mathematician named Frank Nelson Cole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClojureScript and PhoneGap</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/11/12/clojurescript-and-phonegap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 21:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/11/12/clojurescript-and-phonegap/</guid>
      <description>Phonegap is a tool that allows you to develop apps in HTML5 + javascript and makes it easy to deploy them to multiple mobile platforms, including Android and iOS.
ClojureScript is a dialect of the awesome language, Clojure, that compiles to Javascript (after a pass through the Google Closure optimizer). Because Clojure, ClojureScript and Google Closure can be confusing terms, I&amp;rsquo;ll use CLJS instead of ClojureScript for the remainder of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing wireless on eeePC</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/09/08/fixing-wireless-on-eeepc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 21:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/09/08/fixing-wireless-on-eeepc/</guid>
      <description>I have an ASUS eeePC 1000, running Ubuntu 10.10. Wireless worked flawlessly at home, which is where I use it 99% of the time. On our most recent trip, however, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t working. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect to a WPA-secured network. Here are the relevant error messages:
NetworkManager[770]: &amp;lt;warn&amp;gt; Activation (wlan0/wireless): association took too long. NetworkManager[770]: &amp;lt;warn&amp;gt; (wlan0): link timed out. NetworkManager[770]: &amp;lt;warn&amp;gt; Activation (wlan0) failed for access point (linksys) NetworkManager[770]: &amp;lt;warn&amp;gt; Activation (wlan0) failed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surprise, I&#39;m 40!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/09/06/surprise-im-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 14:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/09/06/surprise-im-40/</guid>
      <description>Vinod is surprised  Have you ever been in one of those dreams where everything seems normal and then a flying car (or something equally crazy) comes out of nowhere? I&amp;rsquo;m used to having experiences like that when I&amp;rsquo;m dreaming, but it was quite surreal to have it during waking hours.
Mala and Kavi had gone ahead (surreptiously to plan a surprise party for someone else!). We were to meet at the ferris wheel at the Navy Pier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mala&#39;s Bolognese</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/16/malas-bolognese/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 20:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/16/malas-bolognese/</guid>
      <description>Mala&amp;#39;s Bolognese  I have just had the most amazing Italian meal that I&amp;rsquo;ve had outside of Roberto&amp;rsquo;s in the Bronx. Mala made fresh homemade Pappardelle and a Bolognese sauce that she just learned at Revolution&amp;rsquo;s cooking class. The thing is, she made this yesterday, and I just tried it today as leftovers and it was still amazing. This sure is going to make going lo-carb impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids and Computers</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/15/kids-and-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 21:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/15/kids-and-computers/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s probably too early to worry about this, but I often wonder about the best way to introduce Kavi and Anika to computers. &amp;lsquo;Introduce&amp;rsquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t the right word because even Anika has more experience with computers than I did at that age. So far, though, computers are something that Daddy and Mommy use to do work, not things that are for them. We&amp;rsquo;ll show them a Sesame Street video on YouTube or family pictures on Facebook, but they don&amp;rsquo;t spend any significant amount of time on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Octopress</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/14/switching-to-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 13:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/14/switching-to-octopress/</guid>
      <description>You may have noticed that I&amp;rsquo;ve rearranged the furniture a little. It&amp;rsquo;s been almost 2 years since I last redesigned my blog, so I&amp;rsquo;m way overdue for a pointless redesign. I&amp;rsquo;m now using Octopress which basically takes Jekyll and adds nice HTML5 templates, cross-browser stylesheets, jekyll plugins, and a few build scripts to automate common tasks.
Enjoy my new site and let me know if you find any issues. The source code for my site, as always, is at github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our weight loss regimen</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/13/our-weight-loss-regimen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 14:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/13/our-weight-loss-regimen/</guid>
      <description>After writing yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post about how Mala and I have been losing so much weight over the past 8 months, I thought I should post a small sampling of the food that Mala has made for us in that time. Yes, I am a lucky, lucky man.
   Red Wine Pot Roast   Brisket Sandwich             Salad   Steak             Valentine&#39;s Brownies   Beer Can Chicken             Homemade Pizza   Homemade Pizza             Dulce de leche cupcakes   Flank Steak             Steak, aligot, broccoli and red wine   Homemade fried chicken             Beatty&#39;s chocolate cake   Peanut butter pie             Aligot (mashed potatoes with cheese)   Fried chicken             Triple Chocolate Mousse Cake   Triple Chocolate Mousse Cake             Strawberry Shortcake   Curious George Cake             Elmo Cupcakes   French Silk Pie             French Silk Pie   Hot Dogs and Flank Steak (my only contribution to this page)            Hungry yet?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Get Fat Review</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/12/why-we-get-fat-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 12:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/12/why-we-get-fat-review/</guid>
      <description>Dear patients,
 Why We Get Fat  I am sorry. I have been giving you bad dietary advice. In medical school we learned that fat in your diet causes fat to accumulate in your arteries, causing heart attacks and strokes, so I told you to eat a low fat diet. Of course, looking back, we had no evidence to support that conclusion, but it just seemed rather obvious. Obvious ideas are often the most dangerous ideas of all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting through the start of a run</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/11/getting-through-the-start-of-a-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 12:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/11/getting-through-the-start-of-a-run/</guid>
      <description>I love running. Wait, that&amp;rsquo;s a lie. I love running after I&amp;rsquo;ve finished my run. I also love it during those periods where I get my runner&amp;rsquo;s high, usually around the 30 minute mark, but often it happens multiple times after that point. I don&amp;rsquo;t love running when I&amp;rsquo;m contemplating going for a run. There are rare occasions where I&amp;rsquo;m just itching to go for a run, but usually I&amp;rsquo;m only able start a run by forcibly suppressing the compelling rationalizations that my brain develops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Openshot Video Editor</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/10/openshot-video-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 15:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/10/openshot-video-editor/</guid>
      <description>Ever since my Dad brought home an Apple IIe back in 1980, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a huge Apple fan. The design of my website back in the mid 90&amp;rsquo;s was a ripoff of the Mac OS 9 System menu. (I found a later version on the Wayback Machine. I had swapped out the Apple icon for the icon of the startup I was working with at the time.) I loved OS X for a while, especially on my 12&amp;rdquo; Aluminum powerbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running as a metaphor for life</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/09/running-as-a-metaphor-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 20:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/09/running-as-a-metaphor-for-life/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking the other day, on a run, of course, about the many ways that running is a metaphor for life. I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed some of this before with my cousins Dilu and Harish before.
 &amp;hellip; two roads diverged in a wood, and I &amp;ndash;
I took the one less traveled by,
And that has made all the difference.
 While trail running, I have come to the realization that you never have to worry about the fork in the road, nor the decision associated with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old About Me</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/old-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/old-about/</guid>
      <description>I was born in Columbus, Ohio, but my parents moved to Milwaukee, Wisconsin when I was about 2 years old. Hence, I am forever a cheesehead!!! My family still lives in Wisconsin. Thanks to my brother and sister (and my brother-in-law and sister-in-law, of course), I have 6 beautiful and wonderful nieces and nephews. Being here on the east coast, I miss them very much and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to go home and see them again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daivame Kaithozham</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/07/20/daivame-kaithozham/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 19:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/07/20/daivame-kaithozham/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I was a boy, I have been singing a song called &amp;lsquo;Daivame Kaithozham&amp;rsquo;, which is pronounced &amp;lsquo;Dave-O-May Kie-Tho-Ram&amp;rsquo;. My parents taught it to me when I was about 5 years old, so I learned it by learning the syllables in the song. I know bits and pieces of Malayalam, but not enough to know what the words of the song mean. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m feeling stressed, I sing it under my breath and it makes me feel better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything You Want Review</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/07/04/anything-you-want-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 21:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/07/04/anything-you-want-review/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I keep reading books about entrepreneurship. I like the idea of building a business, having passion for something, and most importantly, living life on your own terms. I just don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m cut out for it. But see if that will stop me from devouring Hacker News, startup podcasts and books like Derek Sivers&amp;rsquo; Anything You Want.
Derek was a musician who started selling his own CDs online in the days before Paypal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston with little kids</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/06/30/boston-with-little-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/06/30/boston-with-little-kids/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, but I just can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s been almost 10 years since I left Boston. Mala had a meeting there and we love to take advantage of our employers&amp;rsquo; generosity 1, so I TrippedIt 2 back to Boston for some nostalgia with 2 kids in tow (Ages 4 and 2). Buildings and restaurants have come and gone 3, but it seems like so little has changed in 10+ years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doggcatcher</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/23/doggcatcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 21:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/23/doggcatcher/</guid>
      <description>I talked yesterday about how I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the Google Listen podcast client. I did a little Googling and found a nice solution (somewhat ironic, in an Alanis Morrissette kinda way): Doggcatcher. It costs $6.99 and I spent an extra $3.99 for Presto Sound Library which allows you to speed up the podcasts a little. Sorry Merlin! (He hates when people do this). Doggcatcher seems to do everything I mentioned as requirements in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Listen doesn&#39;t rock</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/22/google-listen-doesnt-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 20:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/22/google-listen-doesnt-rock/</guid>
      <description>In the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to podcasts, I&amp;rsquo;ve only found 2 podcast clients that I&amp;rsquo;ve really liked: iTunes (back around 2005-2007) and a bash script that I wrote which simply copied files downloaded by podget onto my iPod nano. Google Listen on my Droid X (Android 2.2) is tolerable, but only barely. I think my requirements are simple. I want to put in URLs and have the client get all the podcasts in that URL and stick them in a queue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 by 5</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/21/5-by-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 20:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/21/5-by-5/</guid>
      <description>My commute to work is 25 minutes each way, so I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a podcast to listen to. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of the 43folders website for years and Merlin Mann recently started a podcast called Back To Work with Dan Benjamin. Dan Benjamin, it turns out, is the founder of a network called 5by5, which he says has been called &amp;ldquo;NPR for geeks&amp;rdquo;. The shows I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to have all been sharp and entertaining so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gitignore</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/20/gitignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 20:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/20/gitignore/</guid>
      <description>I found this great github project. It&amp;rsquo;s just a list of .gitignore files for various languages and platforms, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have them all in one place. The .gitignore file is, like it sounds, a list of files or directories that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be included in version control. For Android, for example, the bin/ and gen/ directories are generated each time you compile, so you don&amp;rsquo;t want to include that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android ResourcesNotFoundException</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/16/android-resourcesnotfoundexception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 20:44:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/16/android-resourcesnotfoundexception/</guid>
      <description>If you see this error:
E/AndroidRuntime( 457): android.content.res.Resources$NotFoundException: File Yamba1 from xml type layout resource ID #0x7f060000  &amp;hellip; try deleting the bin/ and gen/ directories in your app. It should clear the error.
Reference: http://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=2726#c6</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHM 2011</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/13/shm-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 05:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/13/shm-2011/</guid>
      <description>Here are some (unorganized) thoughts about my experience at the Society of Hospital Medicine (SHM) 2011 conference in Dallas, TX.
Opening Plenary The initial presentation dissected the SHM Annual Compensation survey, discussing regional variations in pay and work effort over time. I understand the importance of that stuff, but ever since I got my first $638.36 paycheck as an intern, money hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an issue for me.
The second talk was by Bob Kocher, an Obama insider during the recent healthcare reformd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Android Review</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/08/learning-android-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 22:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/08/learning-android-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished reading Learning Android. I have a Droid X, Mala has a Droid Eris, and I just bought a Viewsonic g-tablet, so I have plenty of Android devices. While I still have trouble with the idea of typing on a touchscreen, I know that we are moving towards a future where mobile devices are our primary computers. This is not earth shattering. Philip Greenspun mentioned it 5 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosopher&#39;s Way Trail Run</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/07/philosophers-way-trail-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 20:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/07/philosophers-way-trail-run/</guid>
      <description>I ran the 15K Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Way Trail Run today. It&amp;rsquo;s on the eastern end of Carolina North Forest. I&amp;rsquo;ve been running a lot on the western end of these trails so I had never seen any of these trails before. The weather was perfect - sunny and mid 50&amp;rsquo;s - and the trails were in good shape. I only got a little muddy. The race was very well organized for such a small race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canon Powershot S95</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/14/canon-powershot-s95/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2011 20:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/14/canon-powershot-s95/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s something about photography that seems to attract programmers. So many of the really good programmers that I know are also into photography. I, on the other hand, am just happy if my latest photo of the kids doesn&amp;rsquo;t include massive red eye. I&amp;rsquo;m always happy when a shot looks nice, but I know I&amp;rsquo;m not interested enough to be an exceptional photographer. I&amp;rsquo;ve never wanted a fancy SLR camera because I know I&amp;rsquo;d leave it on the shelf collecting dust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter Sweep</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/04/letter-sweep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 06:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/04/letter-sweep/</guid>
      <description>Tim Bray posted the links that his browser displays when he types each letter of the alphabet. Here&amp;rsquo;s mine:
[A]dSense. I spend too much time watching the zero&amp;rsquo;s pile up.
[B]orkware. Always good for a quickie. Wait&amp;hellip; that didn&amp;rsquo;t sound right.
[C]ite-U-Like. I&amp;rsquo;ve started to use this site to keep track of journal articles that I read.
[D]ocs (Google). I store my Habits spreadsheet, my weight spreadsheet, our address book spreadsheet (because Google contacts aren&amp;rsquo;t shareable) and other random documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parenting Highs and Lows</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/03/parenting-highs-and-lows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 21:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/03/parenting-highs-and-lows/</guid>
      <description>Written a few weeks ago
I came home late today, so Anika and Kavi had already eaten dinner and taken their baths. As I drove down the driveway, I could see Kavi&amp;rsquo;s excited little head poking over the upstairs windowsill. I parked the car and opened the door into the house. I was immediately met a voice screaming, &amp;ldquo;Daddy, Daddy!&amp;rdquo; with pure joy in his voice. He ran down the stairs and gave me a huge hug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time is the most powerful force in the universe</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/21/time-is-the-most-powerful-force-in-the-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 14:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/21/time-is-the-most-powerful-force-in-the-universe/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Mala&amp;rsquo;s inspiration, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running a lot more over the past month. Whenever I get into a good running rhythm, my mind starts to relax and I occasionally get bright ideas (believe it or not!). While I am running, these always seem Nobel Prize-worthy, but they seem to lose some of their glitter when the endorphins wear off. I still believe we could solve all the world&amp;rsquo;s problems if everyone was a runner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buying a Minivan</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/19/buying-a-minivan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 20:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/19/buying-a-minivan/</guid>
      <description>The time comes in every man&amp;rsquo;s life where he eventually has to break down and buy a minivan. That time has come. The Altima is on it&amp;rsquo;s last legs and we really need a vehicle which can seat our whole family plus a couple visitors plus luggage. Only a minivan fits those requirements.
I&amp;rsquo;ll probably wait until the spring to buy. That&amp;rsquo;s when the annual Consumer Reports auto issue comes out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Student Oral Presentations</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/18/medical-student-oral-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 14:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/18/medical-student-oral-presentations/</guid>
      <description>I enjoyed @FutureDocs&amp;lsquo; guide to medical student oral presentations, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share the cheat sheet that I give to the medical students and PA students when I start each teaching block. As she mentioned, presentations always have to be tailored to the listener, and each attending is different, so you&amp;rsquo;ll see minor differences in what I recommend.
To me, the most important aspects are organization and preparation. I don&amp;rsquo;t like to have the sense that the student is &amp;ldquo;winging it&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Watson</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/17/dr.-watson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 19:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/17/dr.-watson/</guid>
      <description>All I could think of while watching the news about the supercomputer Watson beating humans at Jeopardy was how this could be used in medicine. Looks like I&amp;rsquo;m not alone.
Time to start looking for a new job?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspirin for everyone</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/16/aspirin-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 21:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/16/aspirin-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Aspirin is one of those wonder drugs - simple, cheap and effective versus so many deadly diseases. We know that aspirin prevents heart attacks and strokes, especially if you&amp;rsquo;ve had one before. There is also some data that it prevents colon cancers, but it was thought that this effect was only seen when using high doses of aspirin. The downside of aspirin is that it increases your risk of bleeding, especially gastrointestinal bleeding (usually from stomach ulcers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I retract my previous tweet</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/04/i-retract-my-previous-tweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 21:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/04/i-retract-my-previous-tweet/</guid>
      <description>I take it back. I was upset, OK? Never tweet when you&amp;rsquo;re upset. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog post to make up for it. See, a whole blog post. That definitely outweighs a tweet, right?
Last week, my 1996 Altima died. The starter seemed to be firing, but the engine never turned over. We tried jumping it, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t work. I called a tow truck and then tweeted about how upset I was with the universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing a Business</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/07/growing-a-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 20:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/07/growing-a-business/</guid>
      <description>I read this book in 2005, but never posted this review. So here it is&amp;hellip;
Growing a Business by Paul Hawken This is an honest and practical guide to running a business. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember where I first heard about this book. Maybe Lars?
It was written in 1987. Hawken talks about building a business. It&amp;rsquo;s often portrayed as a heroic or glamorous endeavor, but really it&amp;rsquo;s not. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of hard work, but also a lot of common sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First full phone conversation with Kavi</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/06/first-full-phone-conversation-with-kavi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 21:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/06/first-full-phone-conversation-with-kavi/</guid>
      <description>I had my first full phone conversation with Kavi today. I was about to leave work, so I called home to let Mala know that I was on my way home. (For the second time&amp;hellip; I got called back to help in the ER on my first attempt, but that&amp;rsquo;s another story). When the phone rang, Kavi picked up the phone. &amp;ldquo;Hi Daddy, when are you coming home?&amp;rdquo; I told him that I was leaving now and that I&amp;rsquo;d be home in half an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autopoint</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/05/autopoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 15:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/05/autopoint/</guid>
      <description>If you get this error message:
Can&#39;t exec &amp;quot;autopoint&amp;quot;: No such file or directory at /usr/share/autoconf/Autom4te/FileUtils.pm  Then, you need to install autopoint:
sudo aptitude install autopoint  I ran into this while building ledger today and had never needed to do that before. The error that acprep provides is even more cryptic:
Automatically preparing build ... Warning: autoreconf failed  Then, I ran autogen.sh and the autpoint error showed up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making blog posting easier</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/05/making-blog-posting-easier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 07:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/05/making-blog-posting-easier/</guid>
      <description>Another piece of advice that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard over and over again is to make things easier. Automate! In that vein, I learned a little elisp in order to make it easier to create a new blog post. I create my posts in emacs, but I often cut and paste the YAML header from a previous post, which is tedious and time-consuming. Here is my new posting function:
(defun vk-blogpost (title) &amp;quot;Create a new blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice on writing</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/04/advice-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/04/advice-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>I just found this great article on writing by Sebastian Marshall. His basic advice boils down to &amp;ldquo;just do it!&amp;rdquo;, but he makes some interesting points along the way. I had never heard of the Equal-Odds rule. Read more details at his blog, but basically, in order to do great work, you have to do a lot of &amp;ldquo;not-great&amp;rdquo; work. No one just does great work. So, let go and just write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A sad day for this Wisconsinite</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/03/a-sad-day-for-this-wisconsinite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 08:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/03/a-sad-day-for-this-wisconsinite/</guid>
      <description>Russ Feingold lost his U.S. Senate race. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been following Wisconsin politics since I left 14 years ago, but this makes me sad. The last time that I really cared about the U.S. political landscape was 1992. I was 21 and in college at the University of Wisconsin and was voting for the first time. Bill Clinton was generating excitement, especially on college campuses, but I was more interested in Russ Feingold&amp;rsquo;s campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rotating videos</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/09/16/rotating-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 09:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/09/16/rotating-videos/</guid>
      <description>I found out how to rotate video today. I often take video with my Canon SD870, but I mistakenly take it in portrait mode. I don&amp;rsquo;t realize this until I&amp;rsquo;m editing the video and then I have to decide if I want to subject my adoring youtube fans to the torture of having to turn their heads sideways to see how cute Kavi and Anika are.
I found this link which gives the mencoder command to rotate the video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 Up and Running</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/25/html5-up-and-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/25/html5-up-and-running/</guid>
      <description>I preordered Mark Pilgrim&amp;rsquo;s HTML5, Up and Running from Amazon back in March. It&amp;rsquo;s available for free as Dive into HTML5. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of Mark&amp;rsquo;s writing for a while, so buying the book was a way to thank him &amp;ldquo;with a buck&amp;rdquo;. Interestingly, the online book and paper book are not identical. For starters, the titles are different. In addition, the beautiful fonts and cutesy images of the online version are gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primary Care Doctors</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/06/primary-care-doctors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/06/primary-care-doctors/</guid>
      <description>I used to be a primary care physician, but switched to being a hospitalist in 2007. I loved parts about being a PCP, namely the relationship that I developed with the patient over many years. I miss that. I think PCPs offer huge value in providing low cost, quality care, especially if they can stay engaged throughout the hospitalization process. Atul Gawande recently wrote a powerful article on the Hospice system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maps are functions, too</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/05/maps-are-functions-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/05/maps-are-functions-too/</guid>
      <description>Braindump time. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve read about clojure in the past few days. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand what this means yet, but maybe someday I will:
 Clojure provides easy access to the Java frameworks, with optional type hints and type inference, to ensure that calls to Java can avoid reflection.
 There are multiple languages that target the JVM (besides Java, of course). It seems that there are 2 classes of languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Bluetooth Workaround</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/02/ubuntu-bluetooth-workaround/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 21:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/02/ubuntu-bluetooth-workaround/</guid>
      <description>I use bluetooth to transfer podcasts from my laptop to my Palm Centro. A Palm Centro is like an iPhone or a Droid, except less smart-like and more phone-like. This worked beautifully but broke when I upgraded to Ubuntu 10.04 (Lucid Lynx). There are 2 bugs involved. First, the bluetooth daemon (/usr/sbin/bluetoothd) never gets started. Second, there&amp;rsquo;s no easy way to start the file transfer daemon automatically (/usr/bin/dund). This used to work automatically, but now it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospitalist Notes 1</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/29/hospitalist-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/29/hospitalist-notes-1/</guid>
      <description>My last night shift was a little less busy than most, so I forced myself to pick something about each patient I admitted and look it up. I tend to do this anyway, but I never keep notes or write about it. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I wrote about that night:
Does Buspar (buspirone) need to be tapered? Answer: No. The full report on Micromedex was a little conflicting, because it stated that there may be some withdrawal symptoms from Buspar, but this quote in the same profile suggests otherwise:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Anti-Writing Cycle</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/27/my-anti-writing-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/27/my-anti-writing-cycle/</guid>
      <description>I blogged daily for a 6 day stretch a couple weeks ago, which is the longest continuous stretch I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done. It was stimulating and stressful at the same time. I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard from the Pulitzer committee about any of the posts yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s not the quality that matters. Writing is more about the process than the product, and I know from experience that writing helps me think. And while most of the posts were written for my own benefit, I really enjoyed the response that I got from family and friends about Playdoh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My video editing process</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/20/my-video-editing-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 20:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/20/my-video-editing-process/</guid>
      <description>I use kino to edit the videos that we take of the kids. I haven&amp;rsquo;t found a Linux program which was as nice as iMovie was on the Mac, but kino is pretty good. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to splice and reconnect video clips together. It has nice special effects, though my needs are pretty simple. It&amp;rsquo;s able to export in plenty of formats, possibly too many, for my simple mind. But, I&amp;rsquo;ve figured it out and have a stable process for getting video from camera to youtube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Market Timing</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/19/stock-market-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 16:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/19/stock-market-timing/</guid>
      <description>If you asked me a few years ago, I would have said you absolutely can&amp;rsquo;t time the stock market. The 2008 crash hurt enough to make me review my convictions a little. I still believe that accurate market timing is somewhere between difficult and impossible. Trying to analyze stock charts to figure out what will happen in the short term is mostly a crap shoot. The way to win in the stock market is to buy value stocks, especially when everyone else is selling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Steps with Clojure</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/18/first-steps-with-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2010 16:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/18/first-steps-with-clojure/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned yesterday, I&amp;rsquo;m teaching myself clojure. I started by trying to install it.
vinod@ike$ aptitude install clojure  Ubuntu has packaged version 1.0.0 of clojure. I always default to the OS-installed version of programs, just for ease of maintenance. The current stable version of clojure is 1.1 and it appears that 1.2 is in beta. I have no idea what has been changed in 1.1 or 1.2, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to get along using 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting some clojure</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/17/getting-some-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 19:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/17/getting-some-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Steve Yegge is one of my favorite bloggers. I read &amp;ldquo;You Should Write Blogs&amp;rdquo; a long time ago and it is one of the main reasons that I still try to keep this blog going at all. He recently took a blogging hiatus and in his return post, he left a little hint that he was interested in a programming language called clojure.
My programming skills have been rusting away (Darn those patients, always getting sick and stuff!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inotify</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/16/inotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/16/inotify/</guid>
      <description>incron seems to be a pretty neat tool. It&amp;rsquo;s cron-for-file-activities. Cron is a common unix tool that allows you to run any command at a specified time. It&amp;rsquo;s immensely useful for running anything that you want to occur on a regular basis: backups, daily reminder emails, downloading podcasts, etc. If you&amp;rsquo;ve used unix to any significant extent, you&amp;rsquo;ve used cron.
incron takes that cron metaphor and applies it to file activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PlayDoh</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/15/playdoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/15/playdoh/</guid>
      <description>Kavi&amp;rsquo;s bedroom - 8PM DADDY and KAVI are lying next to each other in KAVI&amp;rsquo;s bed doing their bedtime ritual. They have finished singing a song and are recapping the day.
DADDY: Did you play with playdoh today?
KAVI: No.
DADDY: Are you sure? Did you play with playdoh this morning before going to the Puffin room?
(KAVI thinks)
KAVI: Yes. I did. Why did I play with playdoh?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/01/03/happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/01/03/happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a great year. I was working on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve. My shift was supposed to end at midnight, which meant that I would normally be home around 12:30 AM, but my colleague let me out early since the ER was unusually light. I got home at 11:55 PM, so I was able to kiss my beautiful wife as the new year began. If that&amp;rsquo;s not an auspicious start to a year, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what one would be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Found the Carolina North trail</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/10/09/found-the-carolina-north-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/10/09/found-the-carolina-north-trail/</guid>
      <description>When Mala and I started looking for homes, we listed on a yellow notepad all the things that were important to us. Like most little notes in my life, it got lost. I found it a few days after we moved into our home and was pleasantly surprised that we had gotten everything on our list, except a lake view. Not bad, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lake about a half mile from our door.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes to a younger investor</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/10/04/notes-to-a-younger-investor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/10/04/notes-to-a-younger-investor/</guid>
      <description>A friend asked for some investing advice a few years ago. Here was my response.
I have a feeling this is going to be long&amp;hellip; :-)
First thing - I don&amp;rsquo;t know your exact financial situation, but I know you&amp;rsquo;re in great shape for the long run. Anyone thinking this seriously about their finances this early in life will do fine. Also, since I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about your exact situation, this may be a little &amp;lsquo;condescending&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing up too fast</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/26/growing-up-too-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/26/growing-up-too-fast/</guid>
      <description>I love watching Kavi&amp;rsquo;s expressions. We took the kids to the Museum of Life and Science for a birthday party today. He&amp;rsquo;s been there plenty of times, mostly with Mala. I&amp;rsquo;ve been there a few times with him. It&amp;rsquo;s one of his (and I guess every kid&amp;rsquo;s) favorite places. Each time we go, it&amp;rsquo;s a vastly different experience. Everything seems new to him. His eyes light up with wonder and amazement at the exhibits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running slow</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/22/running-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/22/running-slow/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a runner for a long time. I started running in junior high school, so I could be on the track team. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few long stretches where I didn&amp;rsquo;t run, but for most of the past 25 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a runner.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the 2005 New York Marathon though, that I really felt like a runner. I had already run 2 marathons, but I had walked a lot in both of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up Firefox on eeepc</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/21/speed-up-firefox-on-eeepc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/21/speed-up-firefox-on-eeepc/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m too weak to lug around my monstrous 7 pound laptop, so I bought a netbook. It&amp;rsquo;s an eeepc 1000 and I love it. I use it for everything, except for processing the kids&amp;rsquo; videos and photos. I still use the desktop for that.
The major issue that I&amp;rsquo;ve had with it is that firefox seemed so slow. I tried other browsers, some which seemed faster, but I missed my firefox extensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye Bye Wordpress</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/19/bye-bye-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/19/bye-bye-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>This site has undergone another transformation. I&amp;rsquo;ve ditched Wordpress and am now using a tool called Jekyll. It&amp;rsquo;s a program that runs on my laptop and generates static files from a bunch of templates. I then upload the static files to my server. Wordpress, like any dynamic software, has security risks. Especially since it&amp;rsquo;s such a popular blog app, it&amp;rsquo;s always under attack. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or interest to keep up with updates, especially since my blogging is so low-profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running is good for your knees</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/08/12/running-is-good-for-your-knees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/08/12/running-is-good-for-your-knees/</guid>
      <description>At the minimum, there is no evidence that it is bad for your knees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flow</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/23/flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/23/flow/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found some old journal entries lying around my hard drive. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that these were meant to be cleaned up and edited before being spewed on the Internet, but in keeping with my newfound obsession with Imperfection, I now present them to you, my dear reader(s). Here is the first one, a review of the book, Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience
Bronx, NY, April 9th, 2007
I finished &amp;ldquo;Flow, The Psychology of Optimal Experience&amp;rdquo; by Mihaly Csikszenthmihalyi on the subway ride into work today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>clamz to the rescue</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/04/clamz-to-the-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/04/clamz-to-the-rescue/</guid>
      <description>Kottke linked to some great deals on classical music at amazon. In order to download them, you need to have the amazon mp3 downloader installed. They now offer a Debian (linux) version, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it working. It&amp;rsquo;s meant for an older version of Debian, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize the newer versions of the libraries installed on my system. I thought about doing some fancy apt-getting to try to get the right versions, but just thinking about that made my head throb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ooohh... gross!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/30/ooohh...-gross/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/30/ooohh...-gross/</guid>
      <description>In order to lose any remaining readers, I am very proud to announce that Kavi made a poopy in his potty. First time! It may well have been a lucky accident, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy about it. In other news, Anika is 1 week old and doing great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anika Puri Kurup</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/23/anika-puri-kurup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/23/anika-puri-kurup/</guid>
      <description>Kavi, Mala and I are so happy to announce the arrival of Anika Puri Kurup. She was born on June 22nd, 2009 at 11:07 PM after a happily uneventful labor and delivery. Mom and Baby are doing well. Here is a quick video, with of course more to follow soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great weekend</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/13/great-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/13/great-weekend/</guid>
      <description>I can barely believe it, but Kavi is 2 years old now. This is such a great age. I remember saying that a year ago, but he&amp;rsquo;s even more enjoyable now. He&amp;rsquo;s excited about everything new. He&amp;rsquo;s running nonstop, singing out loud, and dancing up a storm.
Mala organized a great birthday party for him at a local park. He got a lot of great gifts from all his friends, some of which we&amp;rsquo;re saving so that he can open when the new baby is getting a lot of attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperfection</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/02/04/imperfection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/02/04/imperfection/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of great plans which I&amp;rsquo;ve never fulfilled. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. My life is beyond great and I see it getting better every day. There just happen to be a lot of things that I&amp;rsquo;ve planned to do which I have not done.
I planned to create a web-based running log. I actually did do this and used it for a long time, but I never did build in enough features to make it worthwhile for others to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Shorts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/01/29/selected-shorts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/01/29/selected-shorts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to thank Deepu for giving me a list of some cool podcasts to check out. My commute is about 30 minutes each way, and listening to podcasts I enjoy helps keep me sane. I added the Moth Podcast, NPR Selected Shorts, and RadioLab to my podcast list and have been enjoying all of them. NPR Shorts is my favorite of the bunch. It&amp;rsquo;s usually 2 short stories being read live somewhere in NYC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon there will be two</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/17/soon-there-will-be-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/17/soon-there-will-be-two/</guid>
      <description>Kavi has been getting bored being surrounded by adults all the time. He is very happy to announce that a sibling is on its way. We&amp;rsquo;re calling it blueberry. If things go on schedule, blueberry will be born sometime in June, so we&amp;rsquo;ll have 2 June babies, a couple years apart.
Pregnancy has been uneventful, unless you count those recurrent waves of nausea and vomiting that Mala&amp;rsquo;s been experiencing. Hopefully that will get better as we move into the second trimester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting again</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/13/starting-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/13/starting-again/</guid>
      <description>For the remaining 2 readers of kurup.org (one of them being me), let me apologize for the lack of posts here over the past couple years. I have always meant to write more, but most of my writing seems to consist of apologies for not writing, short bursts of writing, and then long stretches of inactivity. We are nearing the end of a long stretch of inactivity now, so it&amp;rsquo;s time for the apologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House party</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/08/03/house-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/08/03/house-party/</guid>
      <description>We had a few friends over tonight for our first little get-together in our house. Mala made homemade pizza and cake. I provided moral support :-) Everyone had a great time. There were 4 little kiddos and 1 infant, which made for some craziness, but everyone left in good health. It&amp;rsquo;s a treat to watch Kavi interact with other kids. He&amp;rsquo;s a real observer. He sits back and watches what everyone is doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m alive</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/08/02/im-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/08/02/im-alive/</guid>
      <description>OK, I know it&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since I updated this blog, but rest assured that I&amp;rsquo;m still alive and kicking. The observant among you will notice that the design of the blog has changed. The even more observant will notice that huge swaths of content are now missing. Things like my photo albums, my running log, old comments, and Kavi&amp;rsquo;s little site are now gone. They may make a reappearance someday, especially if I get prodded sufficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Kavi videos</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/08/21/more-kavi-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/08/21/more-kavi-videos/</guid>
      <description>There are more videos on my youtube page and I&amp;rsquo;m uploading pics as often as I can at Kavi&amp;rsquo;s Photo Album. UPDATE: I&amp;rsquo;m outsourcing photo management now. Go to Picasa</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Kavi</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/19/introducing-kavi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/19/introducing-kavi/</guid>
      <description>And here&amp;rsquo;s his first video.
Comments from old site congrats
 Vinod, congratulations to you and your wife. Having just celebrated my son&#39;s 2nd birthday last weekend, I&#39;m pretty sure there will be more Kavi chronicles coming up. Deds Castillo 2007-06-19 22:59:43   Hey, Nice Video
 Hey Vin,  Nice video production. I also like the choice of the first song! Dual meaning! Talk to you soon. Gerald Cherayil 2007-06-29 08:56:23</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kavi Arrives!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/07/kavi-arrives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/07/kavi-arrives/</guid>
      <description>Mala and I are so proud to announce the birth of our healthy, happy baby boy!
His name is Kavi Puri Kurup and he was born at 11:28 AM on June 6th, 2007. He is 6lbs, 8.5oz and 19 inches long.
Kavi  Comments from old site Congrats
 Congratulations Vinu and Mala. Kavi is a really nice name...I like it. His big cousins were very excited to hear the news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belated Investment Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/03/belated-investment-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/03/belated-investment-update/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s also get caught up with my investments. I last updated in May 2006 when I bought STS, JAX, EEI, KEYN and RSC.
At my next quarterly evaluation in August 2006, I sold DSWL at a loss of 16.7% because I had held it for 2 years and it no longer met my criteria for a stock I would want to buy. I bought SYPR and BSET.
In November 2006, I sold SEMI because it reported a negative quarter on top of negative trailing 12 month earnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No excuses</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/01/no-excuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/01/no-excuses/</guid>
      <description>Attention Wisconsin Family Members:
Midwest Airlines is restarting direct flights from Milwaukee to Raleigh-Durham.
Just FYI :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update/</guid>
      <description>Once again, I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen behind on my life updates, so let&amp;rsquo;s get caught up.
 Mala&amp;rsquo;s pregnancy is going well, at least from the husband&amp;rsquo;s point of view. She&amp;rsquo;s due June 15th. We drove to Orlando for my CME conference because Delta cancelled our flight. It turned out to be a nice thing because we got to see Puja, Ethan and Loki on the way down and we got to stop in Charleston, SC on the way back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Survival</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/04/15/deep-survival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/04/15/deep-survival/</guid>
      <description>If you go on adventure trips, you should read &amp;ldquo;Deep Survival&amp;rdquo;, by Laurence Gonzales. I finished it on my marathon subway rides yesterday. It&amp;rsquo;s partly a voyeuristic look into how people do or don&amp;rsquo;t survive when bad things happen. This part is pure storytelling and who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love a good story? At times, the outdoorsy jargon made it hard for me to follow what exactly was going on, but on the whole I was sucked in, turning pages to see what happened to our poor characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Ride, Long Run</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/04/15/long-ride-long-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/04/15/long-ride-long-run/</guid>
      <description>I did something yesterday that I haven&amp;rsquo;t done before. I took a ride on the subway from one end all the way to the other end. I took the D train from 205th street in the Bronx to Coney Island/Stillwell Avenue in Brooklyn, passing through Manhattan on the way. Left at 6:04 AM and arrived at 7:46 AM, just in time to make it to the start of the Brooklyn Half Marathon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literature delivered to your inbox</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox/</guid>
      <description>DailyLit.com is an interesting service that takes classic books and chops them up in to bite-sized pieces that you can read in just a few minutes. It then emails you one piece at a time until you finish the book. You can customize how often you get the emails.
I just finished &amp;ldquo;The Art of Money Getting&amp;rdquo;, by P.T. Barnum. It has a lot of practical advice, and predates (by 100 years) a lot of what you see these days in self-help books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Performance 1996-2006</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/01/07/investment-performance-1996-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/01/07/investment-performance-1996-2006/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s my 2006 Investment Performance update. My individual stock picks broke their 4 year winning streak versus the S&amp;amp;P500 and overall (including my 403b), I lagged the market by a couple percentage points. That makes for a pretty lousy year overall. So, is it time to switch tactics? Give in and stick all my money in an index fund? Some would say yes (or more like &amp;ldquo;YES, you IDIOT!&amp;rdquo;). I knew when I started this approach that there would be times where I would underperform, even for long periods of time, meaning 1-2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good causes</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/01/03/good-causes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/01/03/good-causes/</guid>
      <description>I posted about this last year, so here&amp;rsquo;s our updated donation list for 2006. Again, I think they&amp;rsquo;re all great causes, so I encourage you to check them out.
 Electronic Frontier Foundation - The internet is the most innovative force in our lives and the EFF working to preserve freedom on the net. Free Software Foundation - When software is free, it means that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to reinvent the wheel over and over again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google, M.D.</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/27/google-m.d./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/27/google-m.d./</guid>
      <description>I remember telling people at a dinner party that I often entered symptoms into Google to help me diagnose patients. I remember them being apalled.
Turns out that Google is pretty accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Length of therapy with bisphosphonates</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/27/length-of-therapy-with-bisphosphonates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/27/length-of-therapy-with-bisphosphonates/</guid>
      <description>Sorry for another post linking to Journal Watch, but they really are doing a great job of reading my mind&amp;hellip;
In my talk to the residents about osteoporosis, I mentioned that one of the unanswered questions is how long to treat patients with bisphosphonates. Well, a randomized trial published in JAMA says &amp;ldquo;5 years&amp;rdquo;. Bone density in placebo-users decreased minimally and hip fracture risk stayed the same. Vertebral fracture risk increased, but vertebral fractures are much less significant than hip fractures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osteoporosis Talk</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/24/osteoporosis-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/24/osteoporosis-talk/</guid>
      <description>I gave the residents a talk on osteoporosis at noon conference on Friday. Here&amp;rsquo;s the powerpoint slides that I created, in case they might be useful to anyone. They&amp;rsquo;re licensed under a Creative Commons license and available in 2 formats - ODP (good) and PPT (bad).
Medical information changes constantly, so hopefully these will be useful until at least the end of 2006. I&amp;rsquo;ve also uploaded slides from previous talks on Abnormal Liver Function Tests and Adult Immunizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Soon!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been hard to keep this news from friends and family, but we wanted to be sure. So, without further delay, we are immensely happy to present:
Kidney Bean  Comments from old site dude
 Dude! This is one hell (heck) of an announcement. You go public, boy-eee! Unregistered Visitor 2006-12-08 13:55:07   Awesome dude
 Congrats and all the best :) Mark Aufflick 2006-12-11 21:40:16   Congratulations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Trip 2006</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/india-trip-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/india-trip-2006/</guid>
      <description>vaishnodevi  I was fortunate to take a trip with my in-laws to India last month. I&amp;rsquo;ve finally gotten around to uploading the pics, but as I look at them now, they don&amp;rsquo;t quite capture the amount of amazing stuff that we saw. I took about 400 pictures and uploaded 187 here. You&amp;rsquo;d think 400 pics would adequately capture a trip, but not for a trip to India.
Here are some interesting ones in case you don&amp;rsquo;t want to wade through 15 pages of pics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health at every size</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/10/23/health-at-every-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/10/23/health-at-every-size/</guid>
      <description>I read this article on &amp;ldquo;Health at Every Size&amp;rdquo; back in July 2005, took some notes and then put it in my &amp;ldquo;To Blog About&amp;rdquo; Folder. In the &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll get to it &amp;hellip; eventually&amp;rdquo; category, here are my notes from 16 months ago:
Here&amp;rsquo;s a really interesting take on the problem of obesity. The movement is called &amp;ldquo;Health at every size&amp;rdquo;. Proponents argue that society and the medical establishment is too concerned with getting people to lose weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with collections</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/25/working-with-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/25/working-with-collections/</guid>
      <description>Steve Yegge wrote about the expressiveness of Ruby as compared to Java. He used this simple problem as an example:
 How about if we write a program that will print out all the words in the dictionary starting with the letter &amp;lsquo;Q&amp;rsquo; (case-insensitive), grouped by increasing length, and sorted alphabetically within each group.
 The Ruby version was about 12 lines of code and Java version about 43. Of course, the point of the exercise wasn&amp;rsquo;t simply the difference in LOCs, but in the overall simplicity of dealing with collections of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful mind</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/beautiful-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/beautiful-mind/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the most amazing things I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. An autistic man takes a 45 minute helicopter ride over Rome and recreates what he sees with near perfect accuracy on paper. More information about him
  This guy&amp;rsquo;s brain is structurally the same as mine, yet its capabilities make my brain seem like it&amp;rsquo;s broken. It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable to think that my brain could have the same capability if it were exposed to the proper conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Primary Care Dying?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/is-primary-care-dying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/is-primary-care-dying/</guid>
      <description>Dave referenced an interesting article in the NEJM titled &amp;ldquo;Primary Care &amp;ndash; Will it Survive?&amp;rdquo; These two quotes summarize the problem:
 A 2006 report from the Center for Studying Health System Change reveals that from 1995 to 2003, inflation-adjusted income decreased by 7.1 percent for all physicians and by 10.2 percent for primary care physicians.
 and
 It has been estimated that it would take 10.6 hours per working day to deliver all recommended care for patients with chronic conditions, plus 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 weddings, 5 babies, 2 graduations and a dog</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog/</guid>
      <description>I love taking pictures with my trusty old Canon S200. It takes great pics and I get to take the credit. I&amp;rsquo;m just horrible about getting them off my camera and onto my website. I finally uploaded a whole bunch today, dating back to early May when we went to Philadelphia for Kevin and Joanne&amp;rsquo;s wedding. The next group is from Brooklyn and Staten Island for Mary Ann and Benjeil&amp;rsquo;s wedding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecce Bed &amp;amp; Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/ecce-bed-amp-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/ecce-bed-amp-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>Can you believe that it&amp;rsquo;s been a year since we got married? Me neither. For our wedding, Mike and Ellie gave us a generous gift certificate to the bed &amp;amp; breakfast of our choice. It took a while to find the right one. We started at bedandbreakfast.com and surfed dozens of listings. This industry really needs some web consulting advice. Most B&amp;amp;B websites don&amp;rsquo;t provide nearly enough information. I want more photos, more reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pediatric Endocrinologist for Hire</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/08/22/pediatric-endocrinologist-for-hire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/08/22/pediatric-endocrinologist-for-hire/</guid>
      <description>Mala finishes her fellowship in July 2007, so we&amp;rsquo;ve entered job search mode. We&amp;rsquo;ve got a few interviews scheduled, but it just seems harder than it should be to find out who has positions available.
Some criteria:
 focus on clinical practice location with a lower cost of living than NYC (I guess that rules out &amp;hellip; NYC) friendly colleagues, staff, environment family friendly location near friends or family  So if you know of someone that needs hard-working, intelligent, caring pediatric endocrinologist, let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking History is history</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/08/04/talking-history-is-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/08/04/talking-history-is-history/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite podcasts is going on hiatus. (A podcast is basically a fancy word for a radio show that you can download to your MP3 player.) Talking History is produced by the Organization of American Historians and because of budget problems, they cutting funding for Talking History.
The host Brian LeBeau is the epitome of a great interviewer. He mostly stays in the background, giving the stage to the historian, but when he asks a question, you immediately feel like it&amp;rsquo;s a question that you would want to ask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milla Blogs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/08/02/milla-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/08/02/milla-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Milla correctly points out that she is my blogging inspiration. Not just for telling me to blog more, but for providing the inspiration in the form of the most promising blog-start ever! My favorite so far:
 I turned on 1010 Wins &amp;ldquo;you give us 20 minutes, we&amp;rsquo;ll give you traffic updates from yesterday for roads you don&amp;rsquo;t drive on&amp;rdquo; and heard nothing at all about the mudslide on the Saw Mill River Parkway, which turned my road home into a parking lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurrent DVT</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/07/25/recurrent-dvt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/07/25/recurrent-dvt/</guid>
      <description>The duration of treatment for a deep venous thrombosis (DVT) is problematic. Most patients who have one will never have another one, yet those who do have a 5% risk of death due to their recurrent DVT. We need a simple test which separates one group from the other.
This weeks JAMA (no link as issue is not online yet) reports on an article claiming that thrombin generation may be that test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bizjournal inaccuracy</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/07/24/bizjournal-inaccuracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/07/24/bizjournal-inaccuracy/</guid>
      <description>Blair Corp, a company in my portfolio, announced second quarter earnings today. They were disappointing, but not as disappointing as reported by bizjournals.
&amp;ldquo;Blair Corp. swings to loss&amp;rdquo; is the title of the article. While dramatic, it&amp;rsquo;s completely wrong.
 Blair Corp., a catalog clothing retailer and direct marketer, reported a loss in the second quarter as sales fell nearly 5 percent.
 False. They reported a profit of $233,000 in the second quarter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doc on Board</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/06/12/doc-on-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/06/12/doc-on-board/</guid>
      <description>Stop what you&amp;rsquo;re doing and go buy the July 2006 issue of Runner&amp;rsquo;s World. Flip to page 49 and read the fine article by Scott Douglas on things a runner should discuss with their physician.
Yep, the &amp;ldquo;Vinod Kurup&amp;rdquo; quoted is yours truly! I&amp;rsquo;m really grateful to Scott for using me as a source and thus making my dream of being in Runner&amp;rsquo;s World come true. :)
Here&amp;rsquo;s the online version of the article, but go check out the magazine because it&amp;rsquo;s, you know, much cooler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Testing Rules</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/16/automated-testing-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/16/automated-testing-rules/</guid>
      <description>Automated testing is a good thing. For my running log application, I have a proc that creates a new log for a user, called rl::runner::new. If you happen to call it for a user who already has a log, it returns the already created log. When I created the proc way back when, I also created an automated test to make sure that creation worked and that redundant calls returned the orignal log.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Features coming in Tcl 8.5</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/14/new-features-coming-in-tcl-8.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/14/new-features-coming-in-tcl-8.5/</guid>
      <description>I was looking at the Tcl 8.4 man page for &amp;lsquo;split&amp;rsquo; and saw this example code:
## Split into fields on colons set fields [split $rec &amp;#34;:&amp;#34;] ## Assign fields to variables and print some out... lassign $fields userName password uid grp longName homeDir shell It shows how to split a string using &amp;lsquo;:&amp;rsquo; as the delimiter. The interesting part is the &amp;lsquo;lassign&amp;rsquo; statement. I&amp;rsquo;d never seen that before. I&amp;rsquo;ve always done something annoying like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update - May 2006</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/11/investment-update-may-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/11/investment-update-may-2006/</guid>
      <description>I sold 3 stocks (OUTL, MRINA.PK and KBALB) and bought 5 (RSC, JAX, EEI, KEYN and STS).
 Sold stocks Purchased Total Return Reason for sell  Outlook Group ([OUTL](http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=OUTL)) Feb 2005 67.65% OUTL is being acquired and taken private at $13.50 per share in a transaction scheduled to close sometime this summer. I decided to sell now at $13.20 rather than wait a few months for an extra 30 cents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louie and Ernie&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/04/louie-and-ernies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/04/louie-and-ernies/</guid>
      <description>Louie and Ernie&amp;#39;s Pizza  We treated ourselves to our favorite New York Pizza today - Louie and Ernie&amp;rsquo;s. In my mind, it&amp;rsquo;s the perfect pizza. The thin crust is crispy on the bottom, and chewy on the top. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of cheese and the sauce has some flavor. The only problem with this place is that it&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near public transportation and they don&amp;rsquo;t deliver. It&amp;rsquo;s probably a good thing though, or we&amp;rsquo;d be eating this ALL the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenACS in Linux Journal</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/26/openacs-in-linux-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/26/openacs-in-linux-journal/</guid>
      <description>Linux Journal featured an article about a web application written in OpenACS. It&amp;rsquo;s called Fungoes and it tabulates and formats baseball statistics. If I had access to this app when I was a kid, I would&amp;rsquo;ve been in heaven. I remember spending hours and hours memorizing stats from the back of baseball cards. I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten most of what I memorized, but I can still rattle off HR stats for most of the 1982 Brewers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hit The Wall (a running log)</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/21/hit-the-wall-a-running-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/21/hit-the-wall-a-running-log/</guid>
      <description>I built a web application to keep track of my running a couple years ago. I really began using it in earnest during my training for the New York Marathon last year. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to make it available for others to use for a long time, but it always seemed like there was a little more work I needed to do on it. While working on it the other day, I noticed the original timestamp on one of the source files: September 21, 2003 Yikes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How long will it take Gerry to find this post?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/16/how-long-will-it-take-gerry-to-find-this-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/16/how-long-will-it-take-gerry-to-find-this-post/</guid>
      <description>So, I just talked with one of my best friends and learned that he still doesn&amp;rsquo;t read my blog. Devastating! We had an interesting conversation about how the value of &amp;lsquo;The Great Idea&amp;rsquo; can be overrated and I wanted to point him to this great essay about the same topic by Paul Graham. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how long it takes him to find it.
I enjoy most of Paul Graham&amp;rsquo;s writings. He writes about startups and software, aimed at the high school/college age geek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Island Hawai&#39;i</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/10/big-island-hawaii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/10/big-island-hawaii/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re back from a week in paradise and have the photos to prove it. Thanks to Peary and Michelle for the warm hospitality in Honolulu. We thoroughly enjoyed every moment. The weather was perfect which was especially nice since it had rained for the 40 days prior to our arrival. Kalua pig is even better than it sounds.
Mala at Akaka Falls  Oh yeah, and the conference was great too :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prettier permalinks</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/28/prettier-permalinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/28/prettier-permalinks/</guid>
      <description>Permalink stands for &amp;lsquo;permanent link&amp;rsquo;. When you create a blog post, it gets added to the top of your blog, pushing older entries down. Eventually, posts get pushed off the front page, so it&amp;rsquo;s important that you have a way to refer to old blog posts. A permalink is the link that will always point to a specific post.
OpenACS (lars-blogger) permalinks look like this:
http://kurup.org/blog/one-entry?entry_id=58950  This works and it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to code, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give much information about the content or date of the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>finance.google.com</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/21/finance.google.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/21/finance.google.com/</guid>
      <description>Google just launched it&amp;rsquo;s new financial website, finance.google.com. It combines a lot of information in 1 page and the adjustable graph at the top of a stock&amp;rsquo;s page is just WAY cool. You can focus in on any period of time and see news &amp;amp; reports from that period. They&amp;rsquo;ve also added blog posts as a news source.
It&amp;rsquo;s the ideal place to get a quick snapshot of a stock. Lots of information in a very quick-loading page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brooklyn Half Marathon</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/18/brooklyn-half-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/18/brooklyn-half-marathon/</guid>
      <description>It was cold out there today. I was wearing a long sleeve shirt, long pants, a headband and gloves, and I was still cold. I doubted whether I&amp;rsquo;d be able to break 2 hours, like I&amp;rsquo;d hoped. A mile into the race I was sure I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to do it. It felt like I was just running in place. As usual though, I eventually warmed up and felt pretty good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tcl, a short introduction</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/09/tcl-a-short-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/09/tcl-a-short-introduction/</guid>
      <description>The scripting language used in most of OpenACS is Tcl. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t receive a lot of press. When people talk about scripting languages, they mean Perl or Python (and now Ruby). Tcl is not considered in the same category, but it should be. I&amp;rsquo;m not smart enough to explain why, but Salvatore Sanfilippo is and has written a gentle introduction to both the basic and powerful features of Tcl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tag Cloud</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/01/tag-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/01/tag-cloud/</guid>
      <description>And now I have a pretty tag cloud on the side of my blog (that I pretty much stole from del.icio.us)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My blog is tagged</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/27/my-blog-is-tagged/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/27/my-blog-is-tagged/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m finally getting around to moving my blog into the Web 1.5 world. (2.0 minus javascript). I scrapped the categories system and created a super-simple tags package. So, now I can tag posts and technorati can find them. OpenACS barely lights up on technorati. Compare RubyOnRails (20 mentions per day) with OpenACS (1 mention in the past month!). I know Rails is popular, but is OpenACS completely dead? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COBR starts paying dividends</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/cobr-starts-paying-dividends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/cobr-starts-paying-dividends/</guid>
      <description>Cobra Electronics (COBR) annouced quarterly results on Thursday. Revenue was up a little. Net income was up a lot, but mostly due to one time events. The market wasn&amp;rsquo;t impressed and the stock fell 8%. Day to day price changes don&amp;rsquo;t worry me, so that&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;m writing about. I mentioned back in July that I was concerned about the cash hoard that Cobra was amassing. Specifically I said:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gladwell blogs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/gladwell-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/gladwell-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Sorry for two posts about Gladwell in one day, but I just found out that Gladwell has started a blog. Looks like he started the day after his Columbia speech which is interesting because he put some blame on the internet for our society&amp;rsquo;s bias towards Picasso. Maybe he&amp;rsquo;s trying to test his theories :-)
Gladwell is one of most interesting writers I have read and is as adept a speaker as he is a writer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picasso vs Cézanne</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/24/picasso-vs-c%C3%A9zanne/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/24/picasso-vs-c%C3%A9zanne/</guid>
      <description>We saw Malcolm Gladwell talk at Columbia on Tuesday. He&amp;rsquo;s the author of Blink and The Tipping Point and he&amp;rsquo;s a staff writer at the New Yorker. He spoke about different types of genius. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to recreate his main points from memory, so I apologize in advance if I&amp;rsquo;ve remembered things incorrectly.
His talk was about the artists Picasso and Cézanne. An economist named David Galenson did an analysis of the market value of paintings of these great artists and concluded that they represented two distinct types of genius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pound update kills my website</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/17/pound-update-kills-my-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/17/pound-update-kills-my-website/</guid>
      <description>No one but me noticed, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, but my website was down for part of yesterday. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, refunds to paying customers are on their way :-)
What happened? I was doing my regular debian apt-get upgrade and the reverse proxy that I use, pound, got updated. The upgrade was a pretty significant one. Pound 2.0 changed the way that it expects configuration files to be formatted. Unfortunately, the Debian update didn&amp;rsquo;t mention this, so the new version of pound tried to read my old config file, got confused and shut down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Blog Application using the OpenACS Content Repository</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/16/creating-a-blog-application-using-the-openacs-content-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/16/creating-a-blog-application-using-the-openacs-content-repository/</guid>
      <description>I created a very simple blog application using the OpenACS Content Repository (CR). When I say simple, I mean simple, probably to the point of being useless. I just wanted to try writing something as quickly as possible using the CR. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick run-through of the code, in case it might help someone else understand how to use the CR. I&amp;rsquo;m not including much commentary; email me (or comment) if you&amp;rsquo;d like me to expound more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friendship</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/14/friendship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/14/friendship/</guid>
      <description>Happy Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day! Writing about love is a little risque for me, so here instead is a wonderful quote about friendship. I heard it on the University Channel Podcast where Robert Seiple mistakenly attributed it to George Eliot. It was actually written by Dinah Craik in her novel A life for a life (1859).
 Oh, the comfort &amp;ndash;
The inexpressible comfort of feeling
safe with a person,
Having neither to weigh thoughts,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foreign transaction fees</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/13/foreign-transaction-fees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/13/foreign-transaction-fees/</guid>
      <description>Now that credit card companies are charging extra fees for foreign transactions, you need to know where online companies are physically located. For example, did you know that Abebooks, an online aggregator of bookstores, is based in Canada? We found out when we bought books from them and found our credit card statement littered with foreign transaction fees. The ironic thing is that the book actually shipped from the U.S. (from Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing nothing</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/08/doing-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/08/doing-nothing/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time for my quarterly investment update. Every 3 months, I look at my portfolio and sell stocks that I don&amp;rsquo;t like and then buy ones that I do. This quarter, I&amp;rsquo;m doing nothing.
This is one of the hardest things for me to do. I like to trade. Sell a stock here, buy a new one here. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting. Especially when you sell a stock that&amp;rsquo;s been down for a while because then you no longer have to look at that red smirch on your portfolio every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Songflower Man</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/12/mr.-songflower-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/12/mr.-songflower-man/</guid>
      <description>This story about a creative music teacher in Syracuse, NY made me smile out loud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David T is Blogging!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/06/david-t-is-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/06/david-t-is-blogging/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s taken quite a while, but my friend Dave has finally started blogging. You can read his mini-bio on our Wedding Party page. For more info about him, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to follow his blog. I&amp;rsquo;m hosting his site on my server and I&amp;rsquo;ve been too lazy to change the layout of his blog, so it may look eerily familiar at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Performance 1996-2005</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/05/investment-performance-1996-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/05/investment-performance-1996-2005/</guid>
      <description>As promised last year, here&amp;rsquo;s my 2005 Investment Performance update. My 403b account (VFINX, VWNDX, VEXPX and VTRIX) was up 6.7% and my individual stock investments were up 22.0% as compared to the stock market (VFINX) being up 4.7%. That makes 4 years in a row that my overall investments have beat the index and 2 years in a row that my stock picks have. It&amp;rsquo;s that second comparison that is most important to me - my individual stock picks versus the index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senseo Coffee Maker</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/04/senseo-coffee-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/04/senseo-coffee-maker/</guid>
      <description>Oh, in my last post, I forgot to mention one other cause we supported - The New York Botanical Gardens. I don&amp;rsquo;t really think of it as charity, since we definitely get our money&amp;rsquo;s worth of enjoyment out of the park. In addition, the gardens gave their members a gift this year - the Phillips Senseo Coffee Maker. This is one of those Pod coffee makers. You stick in a coffee-pod and the machine shoots boiling water through the pod and into your coffee mug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good causes</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/31/good-causes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/31/good-causes/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again - time to reduce my tax bill! Here are the charities that we&amp;rsquo;re donating to this year. I think they&amp;rsquo;re all great causes, so I encourage you to check them out.
 Electronic Frontier Foundation - The internet is the most innovative force in our lives and the EFF working to preserve freedom on the net. Free Software Foundation - When software is free, it means that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to reinvent the wheel over and over again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editing as root in emacs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/editing-as-root-in-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/editing-as-root-in-emacs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using emacs for 7 years and I just learned today that you can edit files as root while you&amp;rsquo;re logged into emacs as an unprivileged user. Using sudo, of course. The details are here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Zeitgeist</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/google-zeitgeist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/google-zeitgeist/</guid>
      <description>Every year, Google does an analysis of search queries over the past year. They call it the Google Zeitgeist. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how &amp;lsquo;what we search for&amp;rsquo; is a very accurate historical record of our times. The Apple iPod takes up 4 of the top 10 searches on Froogle, Google&amp;rsquo;s consumer search engine.
If you liked Zeitgeist, you can monitor weekly updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT&#39;s guide to writing</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/mits-guide-to-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/mits-guide-to-writing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to become a better writer. In order to become a better writer, you simply have to write more. Funny how most things are like that. Still, sometimes you want a little more structure. MIT has a nice guide to writing that is both simple and useful. Start out by making your document writer-centric. Just get the words down on paper. Satisfy only yourself. Then, revise your writing to make it reader-centric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Chocolate 15K</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/18/hot-chocolate-15k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/18/hot-chocolate-15k/</guid>
      <description>I ran the NYRR Hot Chocolate 15K (9.3 miles) this morning. It was cold, but then again, it&amp;rsquo;s the middle of December, so whaddya expect? I&amp;rsquo;ve only run twice since the marathon, so I took it nice and easy. I planned to run about 10 minute miles, but I felt good around mile 5, so I sped up. I finished in 1:25:22 (9:10 per mile).
Oh yeah&amp;hellip; and the Hot Chocolate was awesome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investments: Quarterly Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/01/investments-quarterly-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/01/investments-quarterly-update/</guid>
      <description>DUCK lost money both in its most recent quarter and over the past 12 months, so I sold it. I wish I&amp;rsquo;d been smarter about the way I sold it. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t decided which new stocks to buy yet, so instead of just selling DUCK and sitting in cash, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d using a trailing-stop order. With a regular stop, you tell your broker to sell the stock once the price drops below a certain point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Ads only for googlers</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/google-ads-only-for-googlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/google-ads-only-for-googlers/</guid>
      <description>I saw this great idea over at this place called Raganwald. Only show ads to visitors who come in from search engines. I really don&amp;rsquo;t want friends and family to see ads, so this effectively shields them since they will probably come here by typing kurup.org in the address bar or using a bookmark.
You&amp;rsquo;re welcome :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTA sucks</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/mta-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/mta-sucks/</guid>
      <description>I had the commute from hell this morning. The 4 train went &amp;ldquo;Out of service&amp;rdquo; at 149th street, so we all got off and crowded onto the other nearly-full 4 train going downtown. They closed the doors for a minute, then opened the doors and said &amp;lsquo;This 4 is out of service&amp;rsquo;. So now there are 2 train-fulls of people trying to get to the 5 train downstairs. It was chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restaurant Review: BLT Fish Shack</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/restaurant-review-blt-fish-shack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/restaurant-review-blt-fish-shack/</guid>
      <description>It looks like a fish shack, but the service is much more attentive. We had clam chowder and crabcakes as appetizers, then the fish &amp;amp; chips and BLT tuna sandwich as entrees. The tuna was seared just on the edges. It was mixed with bacon, hard-boiled eggs, and avocado on fresh chewy bread. Mala says, &amp;ldquo;Best Tuna Fish sandwich ever,&amp;rdquo; and I can&amp;rsquo;t argue. All of the fried stuff was delicious and not too greasy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Update: The Honeymoon</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon/</guid>
      <description>Amazing etched door  We honeymooned in California Wine Country. We stayed at the Hilton in Santa Rosa, about halfway between Napa and Sonoma. In Napa, we visited Sterling, Peju, V. Sattui and Artesa. I enjoy wine, but not to the point that I can tell the difference between a good wine and a great one. So, I grade vineyards on different criteria. Go to Sterling for the view and the self-guided tour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re married!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married/</guid>
      <description>Mala and Vinod  Life update time. If you&amp;rsquo;re a keen follower of this site, you&amp;rsquo;ll have noticed the little box in the upper left hand corner announcing my wedding to Mala. We got married a few months back and it was documented in photos by friends, family and even an official photographer. (Time wasting warning: There are 500 pictures from friends and family, 1200+ proofs from our photographer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lists in CSS</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/14/lists-in-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/14/lists-in-css/</guid>
      <description>A-ha! This article by Eric Meyer explains why &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;&amp;rsquo;s can appear differently in MSIE and Mozilla browsers. Both indent the list items, but MSIE does so by setting the padding to 2.5 em, while Mozilla does so by setting the margin to 2.5 em. These are on the &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt; selectors, not the &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;. So, in order to get consistent display on both browsers, you need to set both padding-left and margin-left to whatever you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Marathon Eve</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/05/new-york-marathon-eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/05/new-york-marathon-eve/</guid>
      <description>The marathon is tomorrow. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty nervous. I really want to break 5 hours this time. You can track me online at the NY Marathon site. I&amp;rsquo;ll be runner number 27072.
UPDATE 2005-11-14:
I finished in 4:28:09 (chip time). I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with my time and the whole experience. Running down 4th avenue in Brooklyn was crowded, but just breathtaking. You could see a river of people for what seemed like miles ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospitalist Handbook</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/22/hospitalist-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/22/hospitalist-handbook/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a clear, concise handbook for Hospitalist Medicine, check out the UCSF Hospitalist Handbook, available free online. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s up-to-date (the copyright notice states 2002), but it still seems relevant and useful. And I&amp;rsquo;m not just saying that because my cousin Deepu Nair wrote the Night Calls section.
Comments from old site You read my mind
 Vin you read my mind I have been waiting for a handbook on hospitalist medicine, thank you so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mmmmm Bacon...</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/12/mmmmm-bacon.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/12/mmmmm-bacon.../</guid>
      <description>Now this is a good idea for a blog.
 ONE BACON RECIPE PER DAY, EVERY DAY, FOREVER
 I think this one is my favorite so far.
found on A Full Belly</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amabuddy</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/08/amabuddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/08/amabuddy/</guid>
      <description>This seems useful.
 You are in a bookshop or a record shop. You find something that interests you. You can&amp;rsquo;t decide whether to buy it now or online later. What you need is a price check and a quick review, perhaps some ideas of something similar that others might recommend. Amabuddy can help!
 What you do is call (617) 712-3574 (There&amp;rsquo;s a 888 number as well, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be using a cell phone anyway).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBGI</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/07/sbgi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/07/sbgi/</guid>
      <description>Andy asked:
 Hey Vin, what do you think of SBG (Sinclair Broadcast Group) Its the company that owns Channels 18 and 24(my employer). Andy
 I took a quick look at SBGI and would probably avoid it. The first place I always look is the market cap. At 700 million, it&amp;rsquo;s a little bigger than the companies I&amp;rsquo;m investing in. The second place I look is the balance sheet and SBGI&amp;rsquo;s scares me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenACS via Darwinports</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/03/openacs-via-darwinports/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/03/openacs-via-darwinports/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned Darwinports before. I&amp;rsquo;ve finally gotten around to (minimally) documenting my Darwinports OpenACS installation. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite 1-click installation, but it&amp;rsquo;s getting closer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarterly Sells</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/01/quarterly-sells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/01/quarterly-sells/</guid>
      <description>I try to do my portfolio cleanup every 3 months, selling any companies that don&amp;rsquo;t fit my strategy and buying new ones that do. So, I&amp;rsquo;m selling 5 stocks. I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided on my buys yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m looking at BAMM, BZ, CALM, ESP, PWX, SCX and SRT (among others).
   Stock Purchase Date Total Return Reason for sell     Ameron (AMN) 7/7/2004 11.27% No improvement in the financial results over the past year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobra (COBR) announces great results</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/29/cobra-cobr-announces-great-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/29/cobra-cobr-announces-great-results/</guid>
      <description>Cobra Industries (COBR) announced their second quarter results today. I bought COBR in February 2005 because they seemed really undervalued (based on Price/Book and Price/Earnings ratios). They make CB radios, 2-way radios, radar detectors, and are starting to make handheld GPS devices. Cobra owns around 60% of the CB radio market, 20% of the 2-way radio market and 60% of the radar-detector market. They&amp;rsquo;ve just started in the GPS market and their major product, the NavOne 3000, seems like a flop so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bronx Half-Marathon</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/15/bronx-half-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/15/bronx-half-marathon/</guid>
      <description>I ran the Bronx Half-Marathon on Sunday in 2:07:05. I ran the same race last year in 2:07:02. How&amp;rsquo;s that for consistent?. Of course, I&amp;rsquo;d rather be consistently fast than consistently slow, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to look on the bright side. By the way, I really do enjoy these races more than my pictures would suggest :-)
We started near Lehman College and ran along beautiful tree-lined streets like Sedgwick Avenue and Mosholu Parkway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6th Annual Cousins Trip</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/06/6th-annual-cousins-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/06/6th-annual-cousins-trip/</guid>
      <description>Cousins Trip 2005 (photos) was in Lake George, NY this year. The weather didn&amp;rsquo;t quite cooperate this time. It was cloudy and rainy all week. Still, we were able to get in a great hike, some competitive bowling, basketball and mini-golf, not to mention enjoying the 2nd annual Elvis Festival. While we didn&amp;rsquo;t run into any bears, we did see plenty of wildlife. Of course, I would be a rumpcake if I were to forget to mention our late-night Taboo contests, the highlight of the trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Pedometer</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/05/google-pedometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/05/google-pedometer/</guid>
      <description>I admit it. As a runner, I&amp;rsquo;m obsessive about my mileage. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I&amp;rsquo;m obsessive about running and getting my mileage in. That would be a good thing. Once I do go for a run, I&amp;rsquo;m obsessive about knowing exactly how far I&amp;rsquo;ve run.
In high school, I&amp;rsquo;d finish my run and then promptly jump on my 10-speed bike which had an odometer, so I could measure how far I&amp;rsquo;d gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take the MIT blog survey</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/05/take-the-mit-blog-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/05/take-the-mit-blog-survey/</guid>
      <description>found on Joel&amp;rsquo;s Blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding dirt in the footnotes</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/06/27/finding-dirt-in-the-footnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/06/27/finding-dirt-in-the-footnotes/</guid>
      <description>Footnoted.org is a blog that delves into SEC filings looking for those juicy details that companies are trying to hide from investors. Mainly, these details include things like excessive executive compensation or shady related-party transactions. You don&amp;rsquo;t want companies that you&amp;rsquo;re invested in to show up on her blog (except on Fridays when she tries to find companies that are doing responsible things).
Footnoted.org recently highlighted Flagstar Bank (FBC) because they&amp;rsquo;ve announced that their auditor resigned, their CFO resigned without citing a reason, and finally that he was still being paid as a consultant at a higher salary than he was as an employee ($60,000 per month vs $30,000 per month).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Milla and Ben!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/06/20/congratulations-milla-and-ben/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/06/20/congratulations-milla-and-ben/</guid>
      <description>Congrats to Milla and Ben on getting engaged. And to getting written up in the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette for their amazing world travels!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I need a Clocky</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/03/30/i-need-a-clocky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/03/30/i-need-a-clocky/</guid>
      <description>Clocky, an alarm clock that runs and hides, so you can&amp;rsquo;t hit snooze.
Comments from old site Just a suggestion
 Why don&#39;t you try putting your alarm clock on the other side of the room so you have to get out of bed to turn it off. Instead of something that looks like a cat coughed it up. Andy Drout 2005-04-04 21:25:49</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pics Pics Pics</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/03/23/pics-pics-pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/03/23/pics-pics-pics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning to write about my trip to India, but since I&amp;rsquo;m the biggest procastinator in the world, I have a feeling that might not happen. Suffice it to say that Mala and I had a blast visiting our families and taking in some amazing sights. Thanks to everyone there for taking such great care of us. Without further delay, go look at some photos:
 The India Trip Layover in Amsterdam We got back just in time for the last day of The Gates exhibition  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open PDFs in Preview by default</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/12/open-pdfs-in-preview-by-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/12/open-pdfs-in-preview-by-default/</guid>
      <description>Adobe Acrobat takes forever to load (with &amp;ldquo;forever&amp;rdquo; being defined as 4-5 seconds), so I wanted all my PDFs to open in Preview, by default. The thread above explains how to do it.
 Select a PDF file in the Finder Select &amp;ldquo;Get Info&amp;rdquo; from the File menu (or hit Cmd-I) Set &amp;ldquo;Open With&amp;rdquo; to Preview Click the &amp;ldquo;Change All&amp;rdquo; button to make this the default for all PDFs  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Maps</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/08/google-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/08/google-maps/</guid>
      <description>Wow Google Maps is really cool. You can drag the maps around. How cool is that? Put in a location, then drag the map so that the location that you put in is just off the map. Then click the little red signpost on the right hand column and google rescrolls so that your location is back on the map. Very nice!
Read more at the Google Maps Tour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Guideline Clearinghouse</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/07/national-guideline-clearinghouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/07/national-guideline-clearinghouse/</guid>
      <description>I subscribe to the National Guideline Clearinghouse&amp;rsquo;s (NGC) email alert service. Sponsored by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, the NGC is a database of clinical guidelines from numerous sources. Sign up for their alert service to receive email whenever a guideline is added or changed.
It&amp;rsquo;s the first place I look when I want to find an evidence-based approach to a problem. Clinical practice guidelines are helpful, but they have problems, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Performance 1996 - 2004</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/04/investment-performance-1996-2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/04/investment-performance-1996-2004/</guid>
      <description>OK, it&amp;rsquo;s well past the end of 2004 and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally calculated how my investments have done for the year. I&amp;rsquo;ve also analyzed my overall investment results since I started investing in 1996.
These are calculated using the XIRR function in OpenOffice. The XIRR function takes a series of cash flows in or out of an account and returns the internal rate of return for that account. It&amp;rsquo;s the best way to compare portfolio returns when investments or withdrawals are made on an irregular basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of anemia with diastolic dysfunction among patients with coronary artery disease in the Heart and Soul Study</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/02/association-of-anemia-with-diastolic-dysfunction-among-patients-with-coronary-artery-disease-in-the-heart-and-soul-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/02/association-of-anemia-with-diastolic-dysfunction-among-patients-with-coronary-artery-disease-in-the-heart-and-soul-study/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to my cousin Deepu for getting published in the American Journal of Cardiology.
He found a strong association between anemia and diastolic dysfunction in patients with coronary disease. Diastolic dysfunction is a condition in which a patient has clinical signs of heart failure, but a normal left ventricular systolic function. So, for some reason, the heart is pumping vigorously, but fluid is still backing up (into the legs or into the lungs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Marathon, here I come</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/01/new-york-marathon-here-i-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/01/new-york-marathon-here-i-come/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s official. I got an email the other day:
 Congratulations Vinod Kurup! You are eligible for guaranteed entry to the ING New York City Marathon 2005. Simply follow the instructions below and register between January 31 and May 1, 2005, in order to enter the marathon without applying for the lottery. The marathon will take place on Sunday, November 6, 2005.
 So, I registered today and am now committed to running the New York Marathon in under 4 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Meals under $10</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/31/100-meals-under-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/31/100-meals-under-10/</guid>
      <description>The Daily News has found 100 restaurants under $10 (not including tip or drinks) in NYC. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to 9 of them - El Paso Taqueria, Carl&amp;rsquo;s (aweome cheesesteaks!), Blue 9, The Burger Joint, Sassy&amp;rsquo;s Sliders, Crif Dogs, Papaya King (of course), Mandler&amp;rsquo;s and Pomme Frites.
Looks like we have some eating to do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Telephone Service</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/25/free-telephone-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/25/free-telephone-service/</guid>
      <description>Has anyone tried any of the Internet phone services? Skype looks very interesting. Nice interface, lots of platforms, high praise from people I trust, and most importantly, it&amp;rsquo;s FREE! Well, as long as the person you&amp;rsquo;re calling also has Skype. If you want to call a real phone, you buy credits (which seem pretty cheap). Lemme know if any of you try it out&amp;hellip;
Comments from old site Skype is cool</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are SUVs safe?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/10/are-suvs-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/10/are-suvs-safe/</guid>
      <description>Interesting article about SUV safety. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quote:
 Most of us think that S.U.V.s are much safer than sports cars. If you asked the young parents of America whether they would rather strap their infant child in the back seat of the TrailBlazer or the passenger seat of the Boxster, they would choose the TrailBlazer. We feel that way because in the TrailBlazer our chances of surviving a collision with a hypothetical tractor-trailer in the other lane are greater than they are in the Porsche.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Race of the Year</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/10/first-race-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/10/first-race-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>Fred Lebow Classic
I&amp;rsquo;ve run about 10 miles in the past 2 months, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting anything great on Sunday. My conservative goal was 50 minutes. I didn&amp;rsquo;t set any other goals.
I got to the start a little late and didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to find the baggage area, so I strapped on my backpack and ran with it. This made it feel even more like a training run, rather than a race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCRIPT Tag on MSIE</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/04/script-tag-on-msie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/04/script-tag-on-msie/</guid>
      <description>Word to the wise. MSIE5 (Mac) doesn&amp;rsquo;t like:
 &amp;amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;blah&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;blah&amp;quot; /&amp;amp;gt;  It only likes:
 &amp;amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;blah&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;blah&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;lt;/script&amp;amp;gt;  It&amp;rsquo;s quite stubborn. If you try the first example, it will refuse to show any of your page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half marathon results</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/10/18/half-marathon-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/10/18/half-marathon-results/</guid>
      <description>I ran 2 more half-marathons in the past couple weeks. I ran Greta&amp;rsquo;s Great Gallop on October 3rd in Central Park and then ran the Staten Island Half Marathon today.
  Date Race Miles Time Pace (min/mile)   October 3 Greta&#39;s Gallop 13.1 1:46:42 8:08   October 17 Staten Island 13.1 1:41:56 7:47   I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy about these 2 races. The weather was perfect and I was able to avoid hitting the wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>She said YES!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/27/she-said-yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/27/she-said-yes/</guid>
      <description>And I&amp;rsquo;m so happy!
{: .inset width=500}
Comments from old site Congratulations
 :) Jade Rubick 2004-09-27 12:40:29   Nice
 May all your troubles be *little ones*. ;-) Carl Robert Blesius 2004-09-27 17:58:23   Congratulations
 Hey Vin that&#39;s great, you two make a great looking couple, I wish you many happy years together. Again Congratulations. Andy Drout 2004-09-27 18:18:54   Congratulations Dude
 I&#39;m excited that I&#39;m gonna have a brother :) Puja Puri 2004-09-29 20:46:14   Best wishes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness Magazine 4 mile run</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/23/fitness-magazine-4-mile-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/23/fitness-magazine-4-mile-run/</guid>
      <description>I ran the Fitness Magazine 4 mile race in Central Park last weekend. The remnants of Hurricane Ivan were flooding the streets, so I was certain that the race would be cancelled (or that I would chicken out). Neither happened as the sky cleared 10 minutes before the race started.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t warm up as much as I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked, but the first 2 miles went suprisingly well (7:11, 7:16). The hills on mile 3 killed me (7:51), but I was able to pick it up at the end (7:29).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harinamakirtanam</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/21/harinamakirtanam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/21/harinamakirtanam/</guid>
      <description>My Dad&amp;rsquo;s book got reviewed in the Hindu (one of India&amp;rsquo;s national newspapers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Summer Racing Results</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/08/21/my-summer-racing-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/08/21/my-summer-racing-results/</guid>
      <description>I ran 5 more races this summer in my quest to automatically qualify for next year&amp;rsquo;s New York Marathon. The Fifth Avenue Mile was a breakthrough run for me. I easily outdid my pre-race goal of breaking 7 minutes and came within 40 seconds of my best time ever (5:07 fifteen years ago). This makes me think that I might be able to break 4 hours in the marathon next year if I train properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall of water</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/08/11/wall-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/08/11/wall-of-water/</guid>
      <description>http://www.cnn.com/2004/US/West/08/05/wallofwater.ap/index.html (link now broken)
 The sudden release of water from Ralston Reservoir south of Auburn sent a &amp;ldquo;wall of water three to four-feet high&amp;rdquo; down the Middle Fork of the American River, said California Highway Patrol spokesman Tom Marshall.
 That&amp;rsquo;s the river that we rafted down a couple weeks ago during our 5th Annual Cousins Trip. If it had happened during our trip, I still probably would&amp;rsquo;ve been the first one to fall in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queens Half</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/05/18/queens-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/05/18/queens-half/</guid>
      <description>I ran the Queens Half-Marathon on Saturday in 2:11:25. That&amp;rsquo;s about 10 minute miles for 13.1 hot humid miles. It was especially fun because my parents were here visiting from Wisconsin and I think this is the first time they saw me run. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how much of a boost that gave me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Israel, a Ban on Indian Wigs; In Brooklyn, a Rush to Comply</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/05/14/in-israel-a-ban-on-indian-wigs-in-brooklyn-a-rush-to-comply/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/05/14/in-israel-a-ban-on-indian-wigs-in-brooklyn-a-rush-to-comply/</guid>
      <description>Reported in the New York Times: (free registration required)
 One of the most respected Jewish authorities in the ultra-Orthodox world, Rabbi Yosef Shalom Elyashiv, issued the Indian hair ban from Israel on Wednesday, prompting some people in Israel to create lists of stores selling banned wigs and to burn Indian wigs in bonfires, according to Ha&amp;rsquo;aretz, an Israeli newspaper.
 This sounds like a story from the The Onion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Elections</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/05/13/indian-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/05/13/indian-elections/</guid>
      <description>India offshores the prime ministership (link broken).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dan Bern</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/29/dan-bern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/29/dan-bern/</guid>
      <description>Dan Bern has quickly become one of my favorite musicians. I saw him a while back at the (now defunct) Bottom Line and then again tonight at Joe&amp;rsquo;s Pub (within spitting distance!). He&amp;rsquo;s been compared to Bob Dylan, although, unlike Dylan, I can understand what he&amp;rsquo;s saying. His music is simple and catchy, and the lyrics can go from hilarious to poignant in one song.
He played a couple songs tonight that I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find on CDs anywhere - one called &amp;ldquo;One More Light&amp;rdquo; and one about 9&amp;frasl;11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iAppleStore</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/28/iapplestore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/28/iapplestore/</guid>
      <description>I caught the tail-end of a free presentation on iLife at the Apple Store in SoHo this afternoon. iMovie has been sitting around unused on my computer for too long. Inspired by how easy the instructor made it seem, I finally got around to launching iMovie and creating this montage of our Telluride trip (5.0 MB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Telluride</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/22/more-telluride/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/22/more-telluride/</guid>
      <description>Sung and Lei sent me some more pics and movies from our Telluride trip. I&amp;rsquo;ve posted a couple of the pics at the end of my Telluride album. I especially like this movie (5.2 M). I&amp;rsquo;m the one struggling down the slope and then Boris comes flashing through at the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strongbad</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/19/strongbad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/19/strongbad/</guid>
      <description>Strongbad&amp;rsquo;s 100th email</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>darwinports</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/08/darwinports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/08/darwinports/</guid>
      <description>In the process of installing Panther from scratch, I decided to use DarwinPorts. It&amp;rsquo;s a packaging system for the abundant UNIX free software available on Mac OS X. I had previously used Fink which, while being an admirable project, seemed a little opaque to me. I never quite knew where data was being installed and which locations were being searched to see if prerequisites were present. Darwinports seems to be a little better at finding programs/libraries that are already installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t use &#34;Archive and Install&#34;</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/08/dont-use-archive-and-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/08/dont-use-archive-and-install/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the fine folks at badgertronics, I was able to upgrade my Powerbook to Panther free-of-charge. I initially did an &amp;ldquo;Archive and Install&amp;rdquo; upgrade, as recommended by the upgrade guide at TidBITS (easily worth the measly $5, IMHO). But soon after the install, I noticed that my system seemed a lot slower. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pinpoint a specific problem, but things just seemed sluggish. I definitely noticed that DNS seemed to be broken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telluride</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/02/20/telluride/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/02/20/telluride/</guid>
      <description>Sung, Lei, Boris, Mimi and I spent a great week skiing in Telluride, Colorado. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what was better &amp;mdash; learning skiing from the masters in the beautiful Rocky Mountains or eating home-cooked, bacon-laden meals. Not to mention the pecan pie! Here are the photos. Watch Sung the snowboarder (609 K) and the crew coming in for lunch (3.5 M).
Group pic  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Break</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/02/08/christmas-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/02/08/christmas-break/</guid>
      <description>I uploaded the pics from my trip home over Christmas. Nope, this is not our house. Comments from old site untitled
 wow. I wish I had that much spare time. Mark Dalrymple 2004-02-11 16:06:45   info@myXmasHouse.com
 Please don&#39;t hesitate to delete this post if you believe it is inappropriate.  In late 2007 we are launching a website where people like yourself can upload their Christmas decorated houses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling OpenFTS on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/15/compiling-openfts-on-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/15/compiling-openfts-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy, but I finally got OpenFTS-0.3.2-tcl to compile on Mac OS X (10.2.8). I started by reading the excellent Mac OS X porting guides from Fink and Apple. Unfortunately, the OpenFTS Makefile and configure scripts aren&amp;rsquo;t standard, so I had to muck around with things alot. Here&amp;rsquo;s the diff:
diff -U 2 -rbB Search-OpenFTS-tcl-0.3.2/aolserver/Makefile Search-OpenFTS-tcl-0.3.2-vk/aolserver/Makefile --- Search-OpenFTS-tcl-0.3.2/aolserver/Makefile Tue Nov 19 14:24:44 2002 +++ Search-OpenFTS-tcl-0.3.2-vk/aolserver/Makefile Wed Jan 14 23:23:13 2004 @@ -13,6 +13,6 @@ OBJ = $(SOBJ) $(POBJ) $(OOBJ) nsfts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing OpenACS via Darwinports</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/10/installing-openacs-via-darwinports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/10/installing-openacs-via-darwinports/</guid>
      <description>Installing OpenACS via Darwinports by Vinod Kurup
I&amp;rsquo;ve created a Darwinports installation for OpenACS. (What is Darwinports?). This will allow you to set up a quick test installation to try out OpenACS. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend it for a production (or even a development) server. For those purposes, I&amp;rsquo;d strictly follow the OpenACS documentation.
Download my OpenACS portfiles and stick them in your local darwinports repository. If you don&amp;rsquo;t already have a local darwinports repository, create one and add its location to /opt/local/etc/ports/sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now running OpenACS 5</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/09/now-running-openacs-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/09/now-running-openacs-5/</guid>
      <description>I upgraded to OpenACS 5 thanks to instructions from DaveB, et. al. I had a few hitches with that process, but the system seems to be working OK and is certainly zippier. I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested everything out yet, so please holler if anything breaks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source saved my photos!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/05/open-source-saved-my-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/05/open-source-saved-my-photos/</guid>
      <description>Loyal readers of my blog will remember that my Powerbook Wallstreet G3 died on September 21st, 2002. Since I&amp;rsquo;m probably the only one that remembers, I&amp;rsquo;ll point you to that blog entry. The good news was that the hard drive was intact, the bad news was that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have an easy way of accessing it. I have a Firewire enclosure, and my old Powerbook was running Linux, so I figured it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too difficult to get my new Powerbook to read the data off the old HD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup strategy</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/02/backup-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/02/backup-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Badgertronics.com, borkware.com, and company went through the same ordeal that kurup.org did and MarkD has promptly published his new backup strategy. He uses rsync over SSH which, interestingly enough, is the same strategy that I came up with. Great minds must think alike.
The canonical standard for doing backups on UNIX systems is tar (short for tape archive). tar converts directories of files into a single tar archive file which you would then spit to an attached tape drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m back!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/17/im-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/17/im-back/</guid>
      <description>This site was down for the past few days due to a SNAFU with acornhosting&amp;rsquo;s upstream provider. You&amp;rsquo;d think I&amp;rsquo;d have learned to have a backup strategy in place by now, but you&amp;rsquo;d be overestimating my intelligence. Luckily, Cathy was somehow able to negotiate with her failed upstream provider to get my (and other acornhosting customers&amp;rsquo;) data back. After this episode, I promise to backup religiously and I&amp;rsquo;m even more sold on acornhosting as a solid web hosting provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Errata for Quick Calculus</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/11/errata-for-quick-calculus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/11/errata-for-quick-calculus/</guid>
      <description>I just read Quick Calculus: A Self-Teaching Guide, 2nd Edition by Daniel Kleppner and Norman Ramsey. I found a few errors, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find an errata listing online, so I&amp;rsquo;m documenting them here for future reference.
 Page 107, Frame 206. The quotient rule as it&amp;rsquo;s initially expressed is incorrect. The correct version is stated at the bottom of the page and also on page 102, Frame 194.
 Page 173, Frame 330.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Party</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/09/christmas-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/09/christmas-party/</guid>
      <description>I missed the Milwaukee Malayalee Christmas Party this past weekend, but Lisa sent me pics. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to go home for the holidays&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Reunion</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/09/summer-reunion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/09/summer-reunion/</guid>
      <description>Ooops - I just realized that I forgot to link to the pics from our Reunion back in August. At least I got them posted before the end of the year.
Comments from old site Everybody looks the same
 Hey Vin, I checked out your pics from your family reunion and everybody looks the same, your parents haven&#39;t aged a bit and Mini and Manu haven&#39;t changed either, you may have put on a few pounds but who hasn&#39;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running is addictive</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/04/running-is-addictive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/04/running-is-addictive/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at my alma mater have shown that mice who have been bred to run long distances show increased activity in &amp;lsquo;craving&amp;rsquo; regions of the brain when they&amp;rsquo;re denied access to their running wheel (Be sure to check out the Quicktime video on that page). The addiction of running is physiologically similar to other addictions. Maybe that explains why I was out on the East River Path in 29 degree weather tonight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkey Trot</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/11/29/turkey-trot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/11/29/turkey-trot/</guid>
      <description>I ran two more races this past week - the Race to Deliver 4 mile in Central Park on Sunday and the Turkey Trot 5 mile in Prospect Park yesterday. The Race to Deliver was crowded with 6000 or so other runners and I spent most of the first half of the race just swerving around everyone else. I never quite got into a groove, but I was still able to finish in 32:34.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross Country</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/11/17/cross-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/11/17/cross-country/</guid>
      <description>I ran the NYRR Cross Country Championships this AM in 26:48 for 5K. My last cross country race was 15 years ago as a senior in high school. Wow, writing that sentence makes me feel old :-) In those days, I could run 5K in 19 minutes easily and I thought that 7 minute miles were slow. Ahh, to be young again! The NYRR run is held at Van Cortland Park, a beautiful oasis in the Bronx and the race starts out deceptively flat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wall is not a myth</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/10/28/the-wall-is-not-a-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/10/28/the-wall-is-not-a-myth/</guid>
      <description>I ran the Marine Corps Marathon yesterday and can now confirm that Hitting the Wall is a real phenomenon. I finished about 5 minutes faster than I did in Chicago (2000), but I was really hoping to break 4:30. Everything was going great through the halfway point (2:11:48 - 10:04 mpm) when a few doubts started to creep into my head. I&amp;rsquo;m only halfway? I gotta do this again? Somehow I was able to make it through to mile 17 at 2:55:30 (10:19 mpm) before things really fell apart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice runs!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/10/12/nice-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/10/12/nice-runs/</guid>
      <description>Dilu and Amit raced 26.2 miles in the Chicago Marathon today and both finished with amazing times. Dilu completed his first marathon in 4:19:18 which is less than 10 minute miles and almost an hour better than my first one. Amit ran the 2000 Chicago Marathon with me and finished in 4:30ish, I think. He ran today in 3:57:32 - breaking that elusive 4 hr barrier. Nice job guys!
Now I&amp;rsquo;m excited for the Marine Corps Marathon - 2 weeks to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments fixed</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/10/08/comments-fixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/10/08/comments-fixed/</guid>
      <description>MarkD informed me that unregistered users couldn&amp;rsquo;t add comments. Turns out it was due to some extra quoting of query variables that has been fixed in more recent versions of OpenACS, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been too lazy to update. The good news is that all of you who&amp;rsquo;ve been dying to tell me off can finally do so!
Comments from old site Maybe they should register
 You shouldn&#39;t have fixed the problem these people should take the time to register with your site and become part of one the coolest communities on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why OpenACS?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/29/why-openacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/29/why-openacs/</guid>
      <description>Bhavesh responded to my seemingly irrational exuberance about OpenACS asking, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the excitement about OpenACS?&amp;rdquo;
There are much better answers to this question, starting with Why OpenACS?, by my web host Cathy Sarisky, but here&amp;rsquo;s my super brief answer.
OpenACS is a toolkit to build online communities, that is, sites which value users and their contributions. OpenACS provides applications which allow users to create and manage content - applications like forums, photo albums, blogs, calendars, wikis, and file storage areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost famous</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/19/almost-famous/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/19/almost-famous/</guid>
      <description>Hey, my colleague Steve Vaughan is quoted in this NY Times article on music file sharing and he even got mentioned by name on scripting.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>phew - not on this list</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/17/phew-not-on-this-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/17/phew-not-on-this-list/</guid>
      <description>The Worst Jobs in Science via badgertronics
The next time an intern complains to me about their job, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna say, &amp;ldquo;Yeah, you&amp;rsquo;re right, but read this!&amp;rdquo; :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenACS everywhere</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/16/openacs-everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/16/openacs-everywhere/</guid>
      <description>Forget MTV. I want my OpenACS! So, I finally got around to install OpenACS on my Powerbook. Mostly, I just followed MarkD&amp;rsquo;s excellent directions, but I used tDom and AOLserver 4, so there were a few differences.
Comments from old site OpenACS
 Vinod...what is the excitment about OpenACS? I went to the website, but couldn&#39;t get a clear idea of what it&#39;s differentiating features are. Are you running OpenACS for this website?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Mac OS X OpenACS Installation Guide</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/14/another-mac-os-x-openacs-installation-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/14/another-mac-os-x-openacs-installation-guide/</guid>
      <description>Another Mac OS X OpenACS Installation Guide by Vinod Kurup
I installed OpenACS 5.0 on my PowerBook G4. Everyone should read MarkD&amp;rsquo;s guide since it&amp;rsquo;s more comprehensive and explains a lot of the changes that I don&amp;rsquo;t explain. I used some different software versions which made my experience different enough to document.
This is a quick and dirty document for people who have installed OpenACS 4. If I haven&amp;rsquo;t been clear enough or if I&amp;rsquo;ve made mistakes, please let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCO</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/11/sco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/11/sco/</guid>
      <description>Open Letter to SCO.
Loud Applause
Comments from old site The Nigerian SCO Connection
 There is a great parody of the nigerian scam spam letter crossed over with SCO over at here(ArsTechnica).  I am very annoyed with these &#34;johnny come lately&#34; types who are trying to claim stake to internet technologies *after* they are already mature. It&#39;s like the company that tried to lay claim to hyperlinks, even though xerox showed the technology back in the 60s, or the recent claim by another company that claims it owns the technology for embedding things like Flash, movies, etc as part of the web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little pain never hurt anybody</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/07/a-little-pain-never-hurt-anybody/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/07/a-little-pain-never-hurt-anybody/</guid>
      <description>I can barely believe it myself, but I ran 20 miles this morning in Central Park. The New York Road Runners Club organized a long run for people training for fall marathons. The longest I had run before was about 17 miles for my Chicago Marathon training, but I remember that &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo; being mostly walking in the second half.
Today went much better. I started with the 10:30 pace group and stayed with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Music Download</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/05/legal-music-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/05/legal-music-download/</guid>
      <description>Legal Music Downloads and some great background information. I&amp;rsquo;m gonna give iRATE a try.
Comments from old site Directory of Legal Music Downloads
 Check out this site for a comprehensive listing of legal music download sites.
Directory of Legal Music Downloads Joel Erenberg 2004-04-11 19:18:06</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vision restored</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/02/vision-restored/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/02/vision-restored/</guid>
      <description>Read this journal of a guy who had his sight restored after 43 years of blindness. via Badgertronics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting faster...</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/28/getting-faster.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/28/getting-faster.../</guid>
      <description>I got home as it was getting dark, so I ran at the gym, on the treadmill. I usually hate running indoors, but running on the treadmill has one huge positive point. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay attention where you&amp;rsquo;re going. I got myself into a groove and before I knew it, I was done with my 5 miles in about 47 minutes. Much faster than I was just a few months ago!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New virus?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/20/new-virus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/20/new-virus/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting weird emails over the past day or so. The From: address is always different, there is no body text and there is an attachment called your_document.pif. The From: address is sometimes recognizable, but seems to be spoofed.
Google only gave me 1 document for &amp;ldquo;your_document.pif&amp;rdquo; and that document states that this is a new virus called W32/Sobig.F-mm (link changed due to 404). Not much info about it yet, but it seems pretty widespread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heads up!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/17/heads-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/17/heads-up/</guid>
      <description>Mars is closer than it will ever be (in our lifetime, at least).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon Story</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/17/marathon-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/17/marathon-story/</guid>
      <description>Kevin Kling of NPR gives a highly accurate recollection of a marathon experience (RealAudio).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Indian Independence Day</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/16/happy-indian-independence-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/16/happy-indian-independence-day/</guid>
      <description>Today is the 56th anniversary of India&amp;rsquo;s Independence from Britain. Interestingly, Google&amp;rsquo;s top results for &amp;ldquo;indian independence day&amp;rdquo; are not very informative - mostly just greeting card sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let there be light!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/16/let-there-be-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/16/let-there-be-light/</guid>
      <description>The power finally came back on at around 7:20 PM tonight. I was sitting on my futon trying as hard as I could not to sweat, when I heard a loud cheer from the courtyard and saw that the lights had gone on in the apartments outside my window.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a weird couple of days. The power went out around 4:15 PM yesterday while I was looking up some labs in the preceptor&amp;rsquo;s room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Seattle</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/14/more-seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/14/more-seattle/</guid>
      <description>Girish has put up some pics from the Seattle trip and other family events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 degrees?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/13/6-degrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/13/6-degrees/</guid>
      <description>An article in the NY Times claims that &amp;lsquo;6 degrees of separation&amp;rsquo; is an exaggeration. They tested it by asking people to forward emails to people that they knew in hopes that the chain would eventually lead to 1 of the researchers&amp;rsquo; destinations. I know that I delete any chain mail that I get, so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that the study&amp;rsquo;s results are valid.
Let me provide an anecdotal rebuttal. I went to Subha and Archana&amp;rsquo;s wedding in Chicago last weekend and I&amp;rsquo;m guessing there were 400 people there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>annual waste of time?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/13/annual-waste-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/13/annual-waste-of-time/</guid>
      <description>Another interesting article in the Times today. Lo and behold, the annual physical exam is useless. Shocking, huh? Well, no - not really. The first questions about the annual physical cropped up 20 years ago and recent studies have only confirmed these initial doubts.
So, do I perform annual physicals? Yup. Why? A few reasons&amp;hellip;. As a relatively young doc, I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to examine LOTS and LOTS of normal patients in order to get a firm sense of what&amp;rsquo;s normal and what&amp;rsquo;s abnormal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running in the Rain</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/02/running-in-the-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/02/running-in-the-rain/</guid>
      <description>It was pouring, monsoon-style here in NYC today, but I went running anyway. When it&amp;rsquo;s raining, no one else is out, so I get the path to myself. And jumping over (or through) the puddles makes me feel like a tough guy. I swear I can hear the Rocky theme song when I run in the rain. The only bad thing about running in the rain is that the always-stunning midtown skyline gets obscured by the clouds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASD</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/01/asd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/01/asd/</guid>
      <description>A young guy came in as a walk-in with some mild shortness of breath on exertion and associated chest pain. He was the last patient that I saw during a long, busy day and his symptoms were very mild. I was thinking that maybe he had mild asthma or a respiratory infection, but he didn&amp;rsquo;t look sick at all. Then I listened to his heart. A loud holosystolic murmur throughout with a fixed split S2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4th Annual Cousins Reunion</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/31/4th-annual-cousins-reunion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/31/4th-annual-cousins-reunion/</guid>
      <description>We went whitewater rafting in Pennsylvania in 2000, sea-kayaking in North Carolina in 2001, and death-marching (er&amp;hellip; hiking) in the Grand Canyon in 2002. This year, we chose kayaking and hiking in Seattle.
We went kayaking near the San Juan Islands on Thursday. It was a great upper body workout and our guide Martine was a fountain of information. We saw some harbor seals close up and a bald eagle from afar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t get sued</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/30/dont-get-sued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/30/dont-get-sued/</guid>
      <description>The topic of music sharing and its legality came up during our annual cousins trip in Seattle. Here&amp;rsquo;s an important article on How Not to Get Sued by the RIAA. The most important thing is the last line in the article:
 Join EFF and support our efforts to protect file-sharing.
 I don&amp;rsquo;t use P2P music-sharing apps anymore. While I love the idea of being able to access an unending library of music, I don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of getting it for free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AOLserver CGI errors</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/20/aolserver-cgi-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/20/aolserver-cgi-errors/</guid>
      <description>Scenario: You&amp;rsquo;re trying to run a CGI program under AOLserver and you see this in your error log:
19/Jul/2003:00:00:23 Error: exec /home/vinod/cgi-bin/mt: execve() failed: Permission denied 19/Jul/2003:00:00:23 Error: waitpid(-3) failed: No child processes 19/Jul/2003:00:00:23 Error: nscgi: wait for /home/vinod/cgi-bin/mt failed: No child processes  I&amp;rsquo;m trying to run /home/vinod/cgi-bin/mt/mt.cgi. Why isn&amp;rsquo;t this working? Because I need to tell AOLserver about each and every directory which might contain CGI programs.
So I need to change my nsd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating from CVS</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/20/updating-from-cvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/20/updating-from-cvs/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the steps I take in order to update my site from the latest OpenACS CVS. All of this info comes from Andrew Piskorski&amp;rsquo;s great CVS page or from pages listed in his document.
 Make sure that I&amp;rsquo;ve committed all the local changes that I&amp;rsquo;ve made.
vinod:~$ cd web/kurup vinod:~/web/kurup$ cvs commit -m &amp;ldquo;Fixed foo, bar and blah&amp;rdquo;
 Go into the directory containing my OpenACS CVS checkout and grab the latest sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up WEP</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/16/setting-up-wep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/16/setting-up-wep/</guid>
      <description>How to set up WEP encryption:
 SMC Barricade Basestation Airport Extreme Wireless Card Mac OS X 10.2.6  Note that if things don&amp;rsquo;t go 100% right, you may lock yourself out of your wireless network. Be sure you know how to get back in before you follow any of these instructions.
 Set up non-encrypted transmission first. Make sure you can connect to your basestation and surf on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oh, the pain!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/15/oh-the-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/15/oh-the-pain/</guid>
      <description>Ugh&amp;hellip; I woke up this morning with a nagging pain in my right knee. It kinda improved through the day, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too worried about it, but when I tried to run on it this evening, it really hurt. So I&amp;rsquo;m gonna keep to the bike for awhile. I remember having this problem (which I think is patellar tendonitis) during the last marathon and I remember that it got better pretty quick, so I&amp;rsquo;m praying it&amp;rsquo;s the same this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>marriage &#39;tames&#39; genius</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/12/marriage-tames-genius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/12/marriage-tames-genius/</guid>
      <description>Ha! I found another reason not to get married. Apparently, marriage quelches genius. On the other hand, if I got married, I could blame marriage for the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m not a genius&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Mail Woes</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/05/more-mail-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/05/more-mail-woes/</guid>
      <description>I spent most of this afternoon struggling with a mail issue and I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it documented well anywhere else, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to write about it here in the hopes that it might help someone else.
What I was trying to do: Setup qmail + vpopmail + courier imap for imap and pop3d
Problem I was having: For some users, checking POP3 mail would work for a while (about 5 minutes), but then would fail:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Mac OS X and UNIX Programming</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/02/core-mac-os-x-and-unix-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/02/core-mac-os-x-and-unix-programming/</guid>
      <description>Not only has MarkD produced a book, but he&amp;rsquo;s made SlashDot as well. Guess it&amp;rsquo;s about time to retire now&amp;hellip;
I&amp;rsquo;m going to get it eventually, but I&amp;rsquo;m still working my way through Cocoa Programming for Mac OS X</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Not Call</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/29/do-not-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/29/do-not-call/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to sign up for the National Do-Not-Call Registry, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that it&amp;rsquo;s going to reduce the number of calls I get. Look at the exemption list:
 Exempt businesses include: - long-distance phone companies - airlines - banks and credit unions; and - the business of insurance, to the extent that it is regulated by state law.
However, many telemarketing calls are placed by professional telemarketing companies, and even if the company whose goods or services are being sold is exempt, the telemarketing company may be covered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>me vs. daemontools</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/29/me-vs.-daemontools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/29/me-vs.-daemontools/</guid>
      <description>I have a love/hate relationship with daemontools. It&amp;rsquo;s powerful way to manage services (like web servers and mail servers), but it sometimes doesn&amp;rsquo;t act the way I expect it to.
Today, I tried to set up qmail-pop3d. I set up a directory called /var/qmail/supervise/qmail-pop3d and put a file named &amp;lsquo;run&amp;rsquo; inside it. This contained:
#!/bin/sh PATH=/var/qmail/bin:/usr/local/sbin:/usr/local/bin:/usr/bin:/bin export PATH tcpserver -H -R 0 pop-3 /var/qmail/bin/qmail-popup vkurup.acornhosting.net /home/vpopmail/bin/vchkpw /var/qmail/bin/qmail-pop3d Maildir &amp;amp;  Then I connected the run script to my /service directory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>compiling vpopmail</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/28/compiling-vpopmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/28/compiling-vpopmail/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m setting up vpopmail 5.2.1 - a POP3 email manager for qmail, but it won&amp;rsquo;t compile out of the box.
gcc -I. -Icdb -g -O2 -Wall -c vconvert.c In file included from vconvert.c:35: vmysql.h:53:22: missing terminating &amp;quot; character vmysql.h:60:35: missing terminating &amp;quot; character make[2]: *** [vconvert.o] Error 1 make[2]: Leaving directory `/usr/local/src/vpopmail-5.2.1&#39; make[1]: *** [all-recursive] Error 1 make[1]: Leaving directory `/usr/local/src/vpopmail-5.2.1&#39; make: *** [all-recursive-am] Error 2  Whenever make gives you an error, look for the first error you can find.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PG 7.2 to 7.3</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/24/pg-7.2-to-7.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/24/pg-7.2-to-7.3/</guid>
      <description>Not all of OpenACS is Postgres 7.3 compliant yet. OpenACS 5 is compliant and the core packages in OpenACS 4.6 are compliant, but some non-core packages haven&amp;rsquo;t been fixed yet. Noncompliant packages will complain:
[24/Jun/2003:15:21:36][26623.196621][-conn:kurup::4] Error: Ns_PgExec: result status: 7 message: ERROR: Function pa_collection__new(&amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;, timestamp with time zone, &amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;unknown&amp;quot;) does not exist Unable to identify a function that satisfies the given argument types You may need to add explicit typecasts  It is looking for a function with timestamp with time zone as one of its parameters, but most OpenACS pl/pgsql functions were defined as accepting timestamp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psql doesn&#39;t like tabs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/24/psql-doesnt-like-tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/24/psql-doesnt-like-tabs/</guid>
      <description>psql doesn&amp;rsquo;t deal well with tabs. If you feed it a function that has tabs in it, and then call that function, you&amp;rsquo;ll often get this: ERROR: parser: parse error at or near &amp;quot;for&amp;quot; at character 15. Thus, if you ever see this in your error log, it&amp;rsquo;s time to M-x untabify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karate?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/23/karate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/23/karate/</guid>
      <description>I had dinner with a friend of mine whom I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen in a few months. Turned out that she had been mugged in the lobby of her apartment in Hell&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen, so she&amp;rsquo;s spent the last few months moving to a safer neighborhood and dealing with all the pain that goes along with that. How sobering. Thanks to self-defense classes that she took in college, she was able to ultimately fight off her attacker by pushing him away just long enough for her to scream for help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to OpenACS</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/22/moving-to-openacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/22/moving-to-openacs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m slowly in the process of moving my site from PHP/MySQL to OpenACS. Things are broken in the meantime. Specifically, I need to import all my old photos, steal MarkD&amp;rsquo;s book module, and implement my family-tree module. If you find something that&amp;rsquo;s broken, feel free to let me know.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently using an open-source stylesheet from The NYPL, but I need to edit it at some point. But for now, at least, it looks better than anything I could drum up by myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Computers</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/04/02/my-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/04/02/my-computers/</guid>
      <description>My introduction to computers came when I was about 6 or 7 years old - I can&amp;rsquo;t quite remember exactly when&amp;hellip; Venu Mammen (my uncle) brought home a terminal from work. It looked like a typewriter, but it had 2 suction-cup-thingys where you could attach a phone headset. (Phone headsets were pretty much all the same shape back then). Venu Mammen issued some magical command and then up on the screen came the most amazing phrase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My brother is so cool</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/03/03/my-brother-is-so-cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/03/03/my-brother-is-so-cool/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to put this pic up for a while. That&amp;rsquo;s me in back, with my super-cool brother and his even-cooler Harley Davidson VRod. It was about 40 degrees F and despite sitting in back and despite having the warm helmet, I was still freezing. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine what Manu was feeling. Halfway through the ride, I asked him, but his face was too frozen to talk. :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BorkDrip!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/20/borkdrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/20/borkdrip/</guid>
      <description>Got Mac OS X? Want a cool screensaver? I stole this from MarkD over at BorkWare and then modified it to allow multiple drips and configurable block sizes.
 Get the ScreenSaver (expand archive and put it in &amp;ldquo;~/Library/Screen Savers&amp;rdquo;). Get the source code.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India 2003</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/20/india-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/20/india-2003/</guid>
      <description>My parents and I went to India for 2 weeks. We spent a couple days in Delhi and then the rest of the time in Kerala. I thoroughly enjoyed myself and actually found the vacation relaxing. Kerala is more beautiful than I ever remember (somehow I seem to forget in between trips). It&amp;rsquo;s lush and green and the food is amazing. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to go back. Here are some pics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/01/snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/01/snow/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s snowing in NYC. Really hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerry and Kim - the website</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/01/07/gerry-and-kim-the-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/01/07/gerry-and-kim-the-website/</guid>
      <description>I finally finished Gerry and Kim&amp;rsquo;s wedding site. The HTTP address is temporary. I had made a promise to Kim back in September that I would finish it, but that I needed a deadline. My brain seems to refuse to work without a deadline. Anyway, she said, &amp;ldquo;end of the year&amp;rdquo; and sure enough, it went live on 12/31/2002. It&amp;rsquo;s running on OpenACS 4 (CVS HEAD 12/25/2002), using an Open Source CSS stylesheet from http://w3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding Video</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/28/wedding-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/28/wedding-video/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ll scroll down a bit, back to June 28th, 2001, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that I promised &amp;lsquo;Video&amp;rsquo; of the wedding of Gerry and Kim. Go ahead, scroll&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll wait.
Back? OK&amp;hellip; I actually said &amp;lsquo;Video at 11&amp;rsquo;, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t specify exactly when &amp;lsquo;11&amp;rsquo; was. Well&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s now!!!! OK, so it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly video, but it&amp;rsquo;s a slideshow of the festivities (4.6 Mb).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Medicine</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/24/open-source-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/24/open-source-medicine/</guid>
      <description>I wrote up a little intro piece on the use of open source software in medical applications (PDF). HTML below&amp;hellip;
Improving the communication of patient information is the key to improving healthcare quality and efficiency. In most health care organizations, written records are the main conduit of this information, yet they are notoriously illegible and difficult to browse. Reviewing past problems and past interventions is time-consuming, if not impossible. The record is used mostly as a one-way device for the clinician to record data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R.I.P.</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/09/22/r.i.p./</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/09/22/r.i.p./</guid>
      <description>Bad news! My Powerbook G3 went kaput yesterday. After a day or so of troubleshooting, I&amp;rsquo;m blaming it on a dead Power Management Unit. I bought it used in 1999 and have been using it heavily since. It&amp;rsquo;s lived in 7 apartments with me (yup, 7!) from Boston to Green Bay to Minneapolis to Boston (again!) and now to NYC. I still think that 4-5 years is way too short a lifespan for a computer, especially since it was meeting my needs in every other way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Grand Canyon</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/08/26/more-grand-canyon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/08/26/more-grand-canyon/</guid>
      <description>Manu sent me the pics that he took during our Grand Canyon trip. Thanks Manu!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bork!!!!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/08/03/bork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/08/03/bork/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on the Bork Team - no relation to Bork Log or Borkware, of course&amp;hellip; :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grand Canyon Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/22/grand-canyon-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/22/grand-canyon-update/</guid>
      <description>I found some more pictures from the Phoenix trip, so check &amp;lsquo;em out again! And please don&amp;rsquo;t touch or sit on the Indians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pics</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/14/pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/14/pics/</guid>
      <description>Geoff organized a mini-residency-reunion back in June and somehow scammed Joyce and Howard into hosting it :-)
Manu, Girish, Deepu and I hiked the Grand Canyon in mid-June. I&amp;rsquo;m still not clear who decided it was a great idea to hike down to the Colorado River and back in 115 degree weather, but that may be due to the fact that I fried a good number of my brain cells that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delay</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/06/20/delay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/06/20/delay/</guid>
      <description>OK, OK&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s been way too long since I&amp;rsquo;ve updated this page. I just moved to Manhattan to take a job as an internist at Metropolitan Hospital. I&amp;rsquo;ve got pics from a mini-residency-reunion as well as an awesome trip to the Grand Canyon that I need to put up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airport Conspiracy?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/09/18/airport-conspiracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/09/18/airport-conspiracy/</guid>
      <description>My allegiance to Apple is wavering. I came home to find my home wireless network down. I walked over to my Apple Airport Basestation and saw that instead of emitting reassuring green lights, it was alternating between lighting the left red light and then all three amber lights. I searched on apple&amp;rsquo;s website for troubleshooting information without any luck. Finally, (thanks again to Google) I found these 3 reports of Basestations that had bit the dust shortly after warranty expiration:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerry and Kim!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/06/28/gerry-and-kim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/06/28/gerry-and-kim/</guid>
      <description>Gerry and Kim got married on Saturday!!!! Video at 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhotoDB fixed</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/06/19/photodb-fixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/06/19/photodb-fixed/</guid>
      <description>I fixed some security issues in the OpenACS photodb module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girish is published!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/29/girish-is-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/29/girish-is-published/</guid>
      <description>My cousin Girish was interviewed for an article about hormone replacement in heart disease on Rx.com. Unfortunately Rx.com has gone kaput and the author doesn&amp;rsquo;t want me to publish the article here, so it&amp;rsquo;s no longer available. Take my word that it was interesting and Girish sounded really smart!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bunch of stuff</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/26/bunch-of-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/26/bunch-of-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Life has been moving too quickly for me to document my menial existence. Check back again soon when my existence is not so menial! In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a Cliff Note&amp;rsquo;s version (may Cliff rest in peace) of the past 5 months (in no particular order).
 I left medicalrecords.com I began doing freelance web development I finished a Palm-based interface for The Answer Page I began moonlighting at MIT&amp;rsquo;s After Hours Medical Center, thus getting in touch with my &amp;ldquo;medical&amp;rdquo; side again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first OpenACS port</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/01/04/my-first-openacs-port/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/01/04/my-first-openacs-port/</guid>
      <description>I finished porting the homepage module from ACS to OpenACS. Actually, it had already been ported, but the ACS version changed substantially, so I guess I merged the new ACS version with the old OpenACS version. Anyway, it works! Here&amp;rsquo;s the file -&amp;gt; homepage.tar.gz</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y2K1</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/01/02/y2k1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/01/02/y2k1/</guid>
      <description>I found a Y2K1 bug &amp;hellip; well, not really, but I found and fixed a minor problem in the OpenACS toolkit that only occurs on the first of every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless on LinuxPPC</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/12/10/wireless-on-linuxppc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/12/10/wireless-on-linuxppc/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve coaxed my wireless card to work on LinuxPPC. Read how I did it. This link is now gone because it&amp;rsquo;s obsolete&amp;hellip;. vinod.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/10/23/marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/10/23/marathon/</guid>
      <description>My cousin Deepu and I (plus about 30,000 or so other people) ran the Chicago Marathon. Cross that off my life&amp;rsquo;s to-do list!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerry &amp; Kim</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/09/06/gerry-kim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/09/06/gerry-kim/</guid>
      <description>My roommate Gerry has somehow tricked Kim into getting engaged! :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Massachusetts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/12/06/back-to-massachusetts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/12/06/back-to-massachusetts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started a new rotation in at a chronic rehab hospital in Waltham, Massachusetts. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a different pace from any other work I&amp;rsquo;ve done before. I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning a lot about bed sores and tube feeding!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medicalrecords.com</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/12/06/medicalrecords.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/12/06/medicalrecords.com/</guid>
      <description>An opportunity arose that I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass up. I&amp;rsquo;ve been offered a position with an internet startup company. The company is medicalrecords.com and is focused on providing a place for patients to store their own medical records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night shifts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/09/14/night-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/09/14/night-shifts/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be here in Green Bay for a little while longer, probably until Thanksgiving. So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working mostly night shifts, bringing back vivid memories of &amp;lsquo;night float&amp;rsquo; during residency. Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying it. Everyone&amp;rsquo;s really nice and welcoming. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a change from residency when you&amp;rsquo;re the low man on the totem pole. The patient population is more primary care oriented. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen one transplant patient so far, wheras I used to see almost one-a-day in residency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to the homeland!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/08/06/going-to-the-homeland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/08/06/going-to-the-homeland/</guid>
      <description>I found out recently that I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending 3 weeks (maybe longer) in Green Bay, WI. I&amp;rsquo;ll be working as a hospitalist at St. Vincent&amp;rsquo;s Hospital (Prevea HealthCare). It&amp;rsquo;s a 580 bed hospital with 40 ICU beds and I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing 12 hour shifts - mostly day shifts, but a couple nights. It should be fun! I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to being back in Wisconsin, especially Green Bay, for football season. Go PACKERS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/15/waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/15/waiting/</guid>
      <description>Still waiting to hear where my first assignment will be. Possibilities include a VA Hospital in Maine, a hospitalist practice in Green Bay, WI, a practice in Racine, WI, or an outpatient practice in Minnesota. Details to follow&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Done with residency</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/02/done-with-residency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/02/done-with-residency/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally finished my internal medicine residency at New England Medical Center. WooHoo! I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to be a real doctor now&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m planning to spend the next year as a locum tenens physician. I&amp;rsquo;ll be travelling throughout the country, working for 1-2 months at a time. Hopefully, I will get a broad exposure to different types of primary care medicine, so that I can make an informed decision down the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trivandrum Medical College</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/12/01/trivandrum-medical-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/12/01/trivandrum-medical-college/</guid>
      <description>In November 1998, I travelled to India to visit family and work in an Infectious Disease Clinic. I visited the Trivandrum Medical College and the Sree Chitra Tirunal Institue For Medical Sciences &amp;amp; Technology. The experience at the Trivandrum Medical College was a little disappointing, but I was very impressed by the Sree Chitra Institute. I got a personal tour of the hospital and operating rooms from Dr. Krishnamanohar (a close friend of my brother-in-law).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter From Devi</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/10/22/letter-from-devi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/10/22/letter-from-devi/</guid>
      <description>I recently got a letter from my niece, Devi, which broke my heart&amp;hellip;
 Dear Vinu Mamman,
I visited your page and you didn&amp;rsquo;t put a picture of me. I am really mad at you because you didn&amp;rsquo;t give me a picture. Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you put a picture of me? If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a picture of me, I could send you one. Everybody else have a picture of them. If you have a picture you can put it on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cruise</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/03/01/cruise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/03/01/cruise/</guid>
      <description>In March &amp;lsquo;98, after a grueling month in the ICU, I went on a cruise with my cousins and their parents. I&amp;rsquo;m currently seriously considering working as a cruise physician! We went to Freeport and Nassau. The weather and scenery were beautiful, but my most enjoyable moments were spent discussing old (and new) times with my cousins at 3:00 AM looking across the unending ocean.
It&amp;rsquo;s an experience I hope to repeat soon&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/license/</guid>
      <description>Copied and adapted from Parsia Hakimian &amp;hellip;
Content License Except where otherwise noted, my non-code content on this website is licensed under a Creative Commons BY-NC-SA 4.0 (Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International).
Code License Except where otherwise noted, my code on this website is licensed under MIT:
 Copyright &amp;copy; 1998-2019 Vinod Kurup
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>