<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>marathon on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/marathon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in marathon on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/marathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Marathon Eve</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/05/new-york-marathon-eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/05/new-york-marathon-eve/</guid>
      <description>The marathon is tomorrow. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty nervous. I really want to break 5 hours this time. You can track me online at the NY Marathon site. I&amp;rsquo;ll be runner number 27072.
UPDATE 2005-11-14:
I finished in 4:28:09 (chip time). I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with my time and the whole experience. Running down 4th avenue in Brooklyn was crowded, but just breathtaking. You could see a river of people for what seemed like miles ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bronx Half-Marathon</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/15/bronx-half-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/15/bronx-half-marathon/</guid>
      <description>I ran the Bronx Half-Marathon on Sunday in 2:07:05. I ran the same race last year in 2:07:02. How&amp;rsquo;s that for consistent?. Of course, I&amp;rsquo;d rather be consistently fast than consistently slow, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to look on the bright side. By the way, I really do enjoy these races more than my pictures would suggest :-)
We started near Lehman College and ran along beautiful tree-lined streets like Sedgwick Avenue and Mosholu Parkway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Marathon, here I come</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/01/new-york-marathon-here-i-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/01/new-york-marathon-here-i-come/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s official. I got an email the other day:
 Congratulations Vinod Kurup! You are eligible for guaranteed entry to the ING New York City Marathon 2005. Simply follow the instructions below and register between January 31 and May 1, 2005, in order to enter the marathon without applying for the lottery. The marathon will take place on Sunday, November 6, 2005.
 So, I registered today and am now committed to running the New York Marathon in under 4 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wall is not a myth</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/10/28/the-wall-is-not-a-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/10/28/the-wall-is-not-a-myth/</guid>
      <description>I ran the Marine Corps Marathon yesterday and can now confirm that Hitting the Wall is a real phenomenon. I finished about 5 minutes faster than I did in Chicago (2000), but I was really hoping to break 4:30. Everything was going great through the halfway point (2:11:48 - 10:04 mpm) when a few doubts started to creep into my head. I&amp;rsquo;m only halfway? I gotta do this again? Somehow I was able to make it through to mile 17 at 2:55:30 (10:19 mpm) before things really fell apart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon Story</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/17/marathon-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/17/marathon-story/</guid>
      <description>Kevin Kling of NPR gives a highly accurate recollection of a marathon experience (RealAudio).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/10/23/marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/10/23/marathon/</guid>
      <description>My cousin Deepu and I (plus about 30,000 or so other people) ran the Chicago Marathon. Cross that off my life&amp;rsquo;s to-do list!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>