<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: design | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-30T21:57:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bye Bye Wordpress]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2009/09/19/bye-bye-wordpress"/>
    <updated>2009-09-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2009/09/19/bye-bye-wordpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This site has undergone another transformation. I've ditched <a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> and am now using a tool called <a href="http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a>. It's a program that runs on my laptop and generates static files from a bunch of templates. I then upload the static files to my server. Wordpress, like any dynamic software, has security risks. Especially since it's such a popular blog app, it's always under attack. I don't have the time or interest to keep up with updates, especially since my blogging is so low-profile. It's just something I do for fun.</p>

<p>Static files have none of those security risks. There are a lot of static file generators out there, but I chose Jekyll because it seemed intuitive and it's run by the <a href="http://github.com">GitHub</a> folks. I've started using git and GitHub and am impressed by their power so far.</p>

<p>This takes me full circle to my post-geocities days when I was generating static pages using <a href="http://frontier.userland.com/">Userland Frontier</a>. This still doesn't feel as satisfying as that did, but maybe that's only because it was such a new thing back then. I must admit that writing posts in emacs sure does feel nice.</p>

<p>Anyway, the design is completely ripped off from <a href="http://mark.reid.name">Mark Reid</a>. My design skills suck, and his rock. Of course, I am a tweaker, so I'll probably end up ruining his beauty at some point.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lists in CSS]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/11/14/lists-in-css"/>
    <updated>2005-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2005/11/14/lists-in-css</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A-ha! This <a href="http://www.meyerweb.com/eric/css/list-indent.html">article by Eric Meyer</a> explains why &lt;ul> and &lt;ol>'s can appear differently in MSIE and Mozilla browsers. Both indent the list items, but MSIE does so by setting the padding to 2.5 em, while Mozilla does so by setting the margin to 2.5 em. These are on the &lt;ul> and &lt;ol> selectors, not the &lt;li>. So, in order to get consistent display on both browsers, you need to set both padding-left and margin-left to whatever you want.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
