<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:50:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston with little kids</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/06/30/boston-with-little-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/06/30/boston-with-little-kids/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, but I just can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s been almost 10 years since I left Boston. Mala had a meeting there and we love to take advantage of our employers&amp;rsquo; generosity 1, so I TrippedIt 2 back to Boston for some nostalgia with 2 kids in tow (Ages 4 and 2). Buildings and restaurants have come and gone 3, but it seems like so little has changed in 10+ years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Trip 2006</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/india-trip-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/india-trip-2006/</guid>
      <description>vaishnodevi  I was fortunate to take a trip with my in-laws to India last month. I&amp;rsquo;ve finally gotten around to uploading the pics, but as I look at them now, they don&amp;rsquo;t quite capture the amount of amazing stuff that we saw. I took about 400 pictures and uploaded 187 here. You&amp;rsquo;d think 400 pics would adequately capture a trip, but not for a trip to India.
Here are some interesting ones in case you don&amp;rsquo;t want to wade through 15 pages of pics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecce Bed &amp;amp; Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/ecce-bed-amp-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/ecce-bed-amp-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>Can you believe that it&amp;rsquo;s been a year since we got married? Me neither. For our wedding, Mike and Ellie gave us a generous gift certificate to the bed &amp;amp; breakfast of our choice. It took a while to find the right one. We started at bedandbreakfast.com and surfed dozens of listings. This industry really needs some web consulting advice. Most B&amp;amp;B websites don&amp;rsquo;t provide nearly enough information. I want more photos, more reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>