<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>friends on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/friends/</link>
    <description>Recent content in friends on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 14:01:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/friends/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Surprise, I&#39;m 40!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/09/06/surprise-im-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 14:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/09/06/surprise-im-40/</guid>
      <description>Vinod is surprised  Have you ever been in one of those dreams where everything seems normal and then a flying car (or something equally crazy) comes out of nowhere? I&amp;rsquo;m used to having experiences like that when I&amp;rsquo;m dreaming, but it was quite surreal to have it during waking hours.
Mala and Kavi had gone ahead (surreptiously to plan a surprise party for someone else!). We were to meet at the ferris wheel at the Navy Pier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House party</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/08/03/house-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/08/03/house-party/</guid>
      <description>We had a few friends over tonight for our first little get-together in our house. Mala made homemade pizza and cake. I provided moral support :-) Everyone had a great time. There were 4 little kiddos and 1 infant, which made for some craziness, but everyone left in good health. It&amp;rsquo;s a treat to watch Kavi interact with other kids. He&amp;rsquo;s a real observer. He sits back and watches what everyone is doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update/</guid>
      <description>Once again, I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen behind on my life updates, so let&amp;rsquo;s get caught up.
 Mala&amp;rsquo;s pregnancy is going well, at least from the husband&amp;rsquo;s point of view. She&amp;rsquo;s due June 15th. We drove to Orlando for my CME conference because Delta cancelled our flight. It turned out to be a nice thing because we got to see Puja, Ethan and Loki on the way down and we got to stop in Charleston, SC on the way back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 weddings, 5 babies, 2 graduations and a dog</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog/</guid>
      <description>I love taking pictures with my trusty old Canon S200. It takes great pics and I get to take the credit. I&amp;rsquo;m just horrible about getting them off my camera and onto my website. I finally uploaded a whole bunch today, dating back to early May when we went to Philadelphia for Kevin and Joanne&amp;rsquo;s wedding. The next group is from Brooklyn and Staten Island for Mary Ann and Benjeil&amp;rsquo;s wedding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milla Blogs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/08/02/milla-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/08/02/milla-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Milla correctly points out that she is my blogging inspiration. Not just for telling me to blog more, but for providing the inspiration in the form of the most promising blog-start ever! My favorite so far:
 I turned on 1010 Wins &amp;ldquo;you give us 20 minutes, we&amp;rsquo;ll give you traffic updates from yesterday for roads you don&amp;rsquo;t drive on&amp;rdquo; and heard nothing at all about the mudslide on the Saw Mill River Parkway, which turned my road home into a parking lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How long will it take Gerry to find this post?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/16/how-long-will-it-take-gerry-to-find-this-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/16/how-long-will-it-take-gerry-to-find-this-post/</guid>
      <description>So, I just talked with one of my best friends and learned that he still doesn&amp;rsquo;t read my blog. Devastating! We had an interesting conversation about how the value of &amp;lsquo;The Great Idea&amp;rsquo; can be overrated and I wanted to point him to this great essay about the same topic by Paul Graham. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how long it takes him to find it.
I enjoy most of Paul Graham&amp;rsquo;s writings. He writes about startups and software, aimed at the high school/college age geek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David T is Blogging!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/06/david-t-is-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/06/david-t-is-blogging/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s taken quite a while, but my friend Dave has finally started blogging. You can read his mini-bio on our Wedding Party page. For more info about him, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to follow his blog. I&amp;rsquo;m hosting his site on my server and I&amp;rsquo;ve been too lazy to change the layout of his blog, so it may look eerily familiar at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Milla and Ben!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/06/20/congratulations-milla-and-ben/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/06/20/congratulations-milla-and-ben/</guid>
      <description>Congrats to Milla and Ben on getting engaged. And to getting written up in the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette for their amazing world travels!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Telluride</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/22/more-telluride/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/03/22/more-telluride/</guid>
      <description>Sung and Lei sent me some more pics and movies from our Telluride trip. I&amp;rsquo;ve posted a couple of the pics at the end of my Telluride album. I especially like this movie (5.2 M). I&amp;rsquo;m the one struggling down the slope and then Boris comes flashing through at the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telluride</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/02/20/telluride/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/02/20/telluride/</guid>
      <description>Sung, Lei, Boris, Mimi and I spent a great week skiing in Telluride, Colorado. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what was better &amp;mdash; learning skiing from the masters in the beautiful Rocky Mountains or eating home-cooked, bacon-laden meals. Not to mention the pecan pie! Here are the photos. Watch Sung the snowboarder (609 K) and the crew coming in for lunch (3.5 M).
Group pic  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 degrees?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/13/6-degrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/13/6-degrees/</guid>
      <description>An article in the NY Times claims that &amp;lsquo;6 degrees of separation&amp;rsquo; is an exaggeration. They tested it by asking people to forward emails to people that they knew in hopes that the chain would eventually lead to 1 of the researchers&amp;rsquo; destinations. I know that I delete any chain mail that I get, so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that the study&amp;rsquo;s results are valid.
Let me provide an anecdotal rebuttal. I went to Subha and Archana&amp;rsquo;s wedding in Chicago last weekend and I&amp;rsquo;m guessing there were 400 people there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerry and Kim - the website</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/01/07/gerry-and-kim-the-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/01/07/gerry-and-kim-the-website/</guid>
      <description>I finally finished Gerry and Kim&amp;rsquo;s wedding site. The HTTP address is temporary. I had made a promise to Kim back in September that I would finish it, but that I needed a deadline. My brain seems to refuse to work without a deadline. Anyway, she said, &amp;ldquo;end of the year&amp;rdquo; and sure enough, it went live on 12/31/2002. It&amp;rsquo;s running on OpenACS 4 (CVS HEAD 12/25/2002), using an Open Source CSS stylesheet from http://w3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding Video</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/28/wedding-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/28/wedding-video/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ll scroll down a bit, back to June 28th, 2001, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that I promised &amp;lsquo;Video&amp;rsquo; of the wedding of Gerry and Kim. Go ahead, scroll&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll wait.
Back? OK&amp;hellip; I actually said &amp;lsquo;Video at 11&amp;rsquo;, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t specify exactly when &amp;lsquo;11&amp;rsquo; was. Well&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s now!!!! OK, so it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly video, but it&amp;rsquo;s a slideshow of the festivities (4.6 Mb).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pics</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/14/pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/14/pics/</guid>
      <description>Geoff organized a mini-residency-reunion back in June and somehow scammed Joyce and Howard into hosting it :-)
Manu, Girish, Deepu and I hiked the Grand Canyon in mid-June. I&amp;rsquo;m still not clear who decided it was a great idea to hike down to the Colorado River and back in 115 degree weather, but that may be due to the fact that I fried a good number of my brain cells that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerry and Kim!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/06/28/gerry-and-kim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/06/28/gerry-and-kim/</guid>
      <description>Gerry and Kim got married on Saturday!!!! Video at 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerry &amp; Kim</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/09/06/gerry-kim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2000/09/06/gerry-kim/</guid>
      <description>My roommate Gerry has somehow tricked Kim into getting engaged! :-)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>