<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>family on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in family on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 21:19:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Avik 7:30</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2019/04/08/avik-730/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 21:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2019/04/08/avik-730/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Here it comes!&amp;rdquo; His eyes light up.
Slurps one last sip from his small cup.
Then bounding from the kitchen table,
Fast as lighting, he is able
To trash his scraps and stow his dishes.
He yells to Mom, &amp;ldquo;It was delicious!&amp;rdquo;
One more breath then on the couch he lands.
&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s up?&amp;rdquo; says Mom. Dad shrugs his hands.
Big brother also has no idea.
Big sister sighs, &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s a weird one I fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triangle Race Series</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/12/20/triangle-race-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 20:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/12/20/triangle-race-series/</guid>
      <description>When we made our 2018 goals last year, Kavi, Anika and I all had some running-related goals. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember offhand exactly what each of our goals were, but I think we all wanted to run more races, because well, races are fun! I somehow stumbled on the Triangle Race Series. It&amp;rsquo;s a series of a couple dozen races throughout the year around the Triangle, so we signed up for a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composting</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/09/23/composting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/09/23/composting/</guid>
      <description>Guess what, we&amp;rsquo;re composting now! I told you was going to be a gardener, so now you know I&amp;rsquo;m serious. For oh so many years, every Friday, we&amp;rsquo;d haul the garbage and recycling out and I&amp;rsquo;d think to myself, &amp;ldquo;Wow, we&amp;rsquo;d have like no garbage at all if we were composting.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s only taken a few years of thinking that, week in and week out, to get me to try. Actually, that&amp;rsquo;s not even true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a garden</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/09/22/starting-a-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2018/09/22/starting-a-garden/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to be a gardener. Yup, just decided. Well, re-decided, I guess, since we already have a garden. It&amp;rsquo;s a strip of dirt on the side of our house and we&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to grow vegetables the past couple years. But it has some problems. It&amp;rsquo;s way out of the way, so it&amp;rsquo;s a pain to check on it (since I&amp;rsquo;m lazy). The ground just underneath the topsoil is hard clay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peanut Allergy, a personal clinical review</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/21/peanut-allergy-a-personal-clinical-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 07:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/21/peanut-allergy-a-personal-clinical-review/</guid>
      <description>A Vignette A 22-month-old previously healthy girl was brought to the emergency room in respiratory distress. She had been well until the day of presentation. Shortly after disembarking from an airline flight, she developed cough with one episode of emesis. En route to the emergency room, her breathing became labored and she developed hives. She was diagnosed as having an allergic reaction and treated aggressively with IV methylprednisolone, IV diphenhydramine, inhaled albuterol, and oxygen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avik Arrives!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/09/04/avik-arrives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 08:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/09/04/avik-arrives/</guid>
      <description>Anika, Kavi, Mala and I are so proud to announce the birth of healthy, happy baby boy!
His name is Avik Puri Kurup and he was born at 11:01 PM on September 3rd, 2012. He is 6lbs, 12oz and about 19 inches long.
A few pics:
 Avik arrives  Proud Dad  And the obligatory pseudo-nostalgic photo:
Nostalgic Avik  Mom and Baby are doing great! Thanks for all the well wishes and support!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surprise, I&#39;m 40!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/09/06/surprise-im-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 14:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/09/06/surprise-im-40/</guid>
      <description>Vinod is surprised  Have you ever been in one of those dreams where everything seems normal and then a flying car (or something equally crazy) comes out of nowhere? I&amp;rsquo;m used to having experiences like that when I&amp;rsquo;m dreaming, but it was quite surreal to have it during waking hours.
Mala and Kavi had gone ahead (surreptiously to plan a surprise party for someone else!). We were to meet at the ferris wheel at the Navy Pier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daivame Kaithozham</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/07/20/daivame-kaithozham/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 19:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/07/20/daivame-kaithozham/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I was a boy, I have been singing a song called &amp;lsquo;Daivame Kaithozham&amp;rsquo;, which is pronounced &amp;lsquo;Dave-O-May Kie-Tho-Ram&amp;rsquo;. My parents taught it to me when I was about 5 years old, so I learned it by learning the syllables in the song. I know bits and pieces of Malayalam, but not enough to know what the words of the song mean. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m feeling stressed, I sing it under my breath and it makes me feel better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston with little kids</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/06/30/boston-with-little-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/06/30/boston-with-little-kids/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, but I just can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s been almost 10 years since I left Boston. Mala had a meeting there and we love to take advantage of our employers&amp;rsquo; generosity 1, so I TrippedIt 2 back to Boston for some nostalgia with 2 kids in tow (Ages 4 and 2). Buildings and restaurants have come and gone 3, but it seems like so little has changed in 10+ years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First full phone conversation with Kavi</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/06/first-full-phone-conversation-with-kavi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 21:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/06/first-full-phone-conversation-with-kavi/</guid>
      <description>I had my first full phone conversation with Kavi today. I was about to leave work, so I called home to let Mala know that I was on my way home. (For the second time&amp;hellip; I got called back to help in the ER on my first attempt, but that&amp;rsquo;s another story). When the phone rang, Kavi picked up the phone. &amp;ldquo;Hi Daddy, when are you coming home?&amp;rdquo; I told him that I was leaving now and that I&amp;rsquo;d be home in half an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PlayDoh</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/15/playdoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/15/playdoh/</guid>
      <description>Kavi&amp;rsquo;s bedroom - 8PM DADDY and KAVI are lying next to each other in KAVI&amp;rsquo;s bed doing their bedtime ritual. They have finished singing a song and are recapping the day.
DADDY: Did you play with playdoh today?
KAVI: No.
DADDY: Are you sure? Did you play with playdoh this morning before going to the Puffin room?
(KAVI thinks)
KAVI: Yes. I did. Why did I play with playdoh?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/01/03/happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/01/03/happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a great year. I was working on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve. My shift was supposed to end at midnight, which meant that I would normally be home around 12:30 AM, but my colleague let me out early since the ER was unusually light. I got home at 11:55 PM, so I was able to kiss my beautiful wife as the new year began. If that&amp;rsquo;s not an auspicious start to a year, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what one would be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing up too fast</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/26/growing-up-too-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/09/26/growing-up-too-fast/</guid>
      <description>I love watching Kavi&amp;rsquo;s expressions. We took the kids to the Museum of Life and Science for a birthday party today. He&amp;rsquo;s been there plenty of times, mostly with Mala. I&amp;rsquo;ve been there a few times with him. It&amp;rsquo;s one of his (and I guess every kid&amp;rsquo;s) favorite places. Each time we go, it&amp;rsquo;s a vastly different experience. Everything seems new to him. His eyes light up with wonder and amazement at the exhibits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ooohh... gross!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/30/ooohh...-gross/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/30/ooohh...-gross/</guid>
      <description>In order to lose any remaining readers, I am very proud to announce that Kavi made a poopy in his potty. First time! It may well have been a lucky accident, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy about it. In other news, Anika is 1 week old and doing great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anika Puri Kurup</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/23/anika-puri-kurup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/23/anika-puri-kurup/</guid>
      <description>Kavi, Mala and I are so happy to announce the arrival of Anika Puri Kurup. She was born on June 22nd, 2009 at 11:07 PM after a happily uneventful labor and delivery. Mom and Baby are doing well. Here is a quick video, with of course more to follow soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great weekend</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/13/great-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/06/13/great-weekend/</guid>
      <description>I can barely believe it, but Kavi is 2 years old now. This is such a great age. I remember saying that a year ago, but he&amp;rsquo;s even more enjoyable now. He&amp;rsquo;s excited about everything new. He&amp;rsquo;s running nonstop, singing out loud, and dancing up a storm.
Mala organized a great birthday party for him at a local park. He got a lot of great gifts from all his friends, some of which we&amp;rsquo;re saving so that he can open when the new baby is getting a lot of attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soon there will be two</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/17/soon-there-will-be-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/17/soon-there-will-be-two/</guid>
      <description>Kavi has been getting bored being surrounded by adults all the time. He is very happy to announce that a sibling is on its way. We&amp;rsquo;re calling it blueberry. If things go on schedule, blueberry will be born sometime in June, so we&amp;rsquo;ll have 2 June babies, a couple years apart.
Pregnancy has been uneventful, unless you count those recurrent waves of nausea and vomiting that Mala&amp;rsquo;s been experiencing. Hopefully that will get better as we move into the second trimester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Kavi videos</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/08/21/more-kavi-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/08/21/more-kavi-videos/</guid>
      <description>There are more videos on my youtube page and I&amp;rsquo;m uploading pics as often as I can at Kavi&amp;rsquo;s Photo Album. UPDATE: I&amp;rsquo;m outsourcing photo management now. Go to Picasa</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Kavi</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/19/introducing-kavi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/19/introducing-kavi/</guid>
      <description>And here&amp;rsquo;s his first video.
Comments from old site congrats
 Vinod, congratulations to you and your wife. Having just celebrated my son&#39;s 2nd birthday last weekend, I&#39;m pretty sure there will be more Kavi chronicles coming up. Deds Castillo 2007-06-19 22:59:43   Hey, Nice Video
 Hey Vin,  Nice video production. I also like the choice of the first song! Dual meaning! Talk to you soon. Gerald Cherayil 2007-06-29 08:56:23</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kavi Arrives!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/07/kavi-arrives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/07/kavi-arrives/</guid>
      <description>Mala and I are so proud to announce the birth of our healthy, happy baby boy!
His name is Kavi Puri Kurup and he was born at 11:28 AM on June 6th, 2007. He is 6lbs, 8.5oz and 19 inches long.
Comments from old site Congrats
 Congratulations Vinu and Mala. Kavi is a really nice name...I like it. His big cousins were very excited to hear the news. I&#39;m not sure if Sunny was happy or sad to give up the title of youngest grandchild.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No excuses</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/01/no-excuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/06/01/no-excuses/</guid>
      <description>Attention Wisconsin Family Members:
Midwest Airlines is restarting direct flights from Milwaukee to Raleigh-Durham.
Just FYI :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update/</guid>
      <description>Once again, I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen behind on my life updates, so let&amp;rsquo;s get caught up.
 Mala&amp;rsquo;s pregnancy is going well, at least from the husband&amp;rsquo;s point of view. She&amp;rsquo;s due June 15th. We drove to Orlando for my CME conference because Delta cancelled our flight. It turned out to be a nice thing because we got to see Puja, Ethan and Loki on the way down and we got to stop in Charleston, SC on the way back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Soon!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been hard to keep this news from friends and family, but we wanted to be sure. So, without further delay, we are immensely happy to present:
Kidney Bean  Comments from old site dude
 Dude! This is one hell (heck) of an announcement. You go public, boy-eee! Unregistered Visitor 2006-12-08 13:55:07   Awesome dude
 Congrats and all the best :) Mark Aufflick 2006-12-11 21:40:16   Congratulations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Trip 2006</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/india-trip-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/08/india-trip-2006/</guid>
      <description>vaishnodevi  I was fortunate to take a trip with my in-laws to India last month. I&amp;rsquo;ve finally gotten around to uploading the pics, but as I look at them now, they don&amp;rsquo;t quite capture the amount of amazing stuff that we saw. I took about 400 pictures and uploaded 187 here. You&amp;rsquo;d think 400 pics would adequately capture a trip, but not for a trip to India.
Here are some interesting ones in case you don&amp;rsquo;t want to wade through 15 pages of pics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 weddings, 5 babies, 2 graduations and a dog</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/05/3-weddings-5-babies-2-graduations-and-a-dog/</guid>
      <description>I love taking pictures with my trusty old Canon S200. It takes great pics and I get to take the credit. I&amp;rsquo;m just horrible about getting them off my camera and onto my website. I finally uploaded a whole bunch today, dating back to early May when we went to Philadelphia for Kevin and Joanne&amp;rsquo;s wedding. The next group is from Brooklyn and Staten Island for Mary Ann and Benjeil&amp;rsquo;s wedding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Island Hawai&#39;i</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/10/big-island-hawaii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/04/10/big-island-hawaii/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re back from a week in paradise and have the photos to prove it. Thanks to Peary and Michelle for the warm hospitality in Honolulu. We thoroughly enjoyed every moment. The weather was perfect which was especially nice since it had rained for the 40 days prior to our arrival. Kalua pig is even better than it sounds.
Mala at Akaka Falls  Oh yeah, and the conference was great too :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Update: The Honeymoon</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/27/life-update-the-honeymoon/</guid>
      <description>Amazing etched door  We honeymooned in California Wine Country. We stayed at the Hilton in Santa Rosa, about halfway between Napa and Sonoma. In Napa, we visited Sterling, Peju, V. Sattui and Artesa. I enjoy wine, but not to the point that I can tell the difference between a good wine and a great one. So, I grade vineyards on different criteria. Go to Sterling for the view and the self-guided tour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re married!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married/</guid>
      <description>Mala and Vinod  Life update time. If you&amp;rsquo;re a keen follower of this site, you&amp;rsquo;ll have noticed the little box in the upper left hand corner announcing my wedding to Mala. We got married a few months back and it was documented in photos by friends, family and even an official photographer. (Time wasting warning: There are 500 pictures from friends and family, 1200+ proofs from our photographer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospitalist Handbook</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/22/hospitalist-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/22/hospitalist-handbook/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a clear, concise handbook for Hospitalist Medicine, check out the UCSF Hospitalist Handbook, available free online. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s up-to-date (the copyright notice states 2002), but it still seems relevant and useful. And I&amp;rsquo;m not just saying that because my cousin Deepu Nair wrote the Night Calls section.
Comments from old site You read my mind
 Vin you read my mind I have been waiting for a handbook on hospitalist medicine, thank you so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6th Annual Cousins Trip</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/06/6th-annual-cousins-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/07/06/6th-annual-cousins-trip/</guid>
      <description>Cousins Trip 2005 (photos) was in Lake George, NY this year. The weather didn&amp;rsquo;t quite cooperate this time. It was cloudy and rainy all week. Still, we were able to get in a great hike, some competitive bowling, basketball and mini-golf, not to mention enjoying the 2nd annual Elvis Festival. While we didn&amp;rsquo;t run into any bears, we did see plenty of wildlife. Of course, I would be a rumpcake if I were to forget to mention our late-night Taboo contests, the highlight of the trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pics Pics Pics</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/03/23/pics-pics-pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/03/23/pics-pics-pics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning to write about my trip to India, but since I&amp;rsquo;m the biggest procastinator in the world, I have a feeling that might not happen. Suffice it to say that Mala and I had a blast visiting our families and taking in some amazing sights. Thanks to everyone there for taking such great care of us. Without further delay, go look at some photos:
 The India Trip Layover in Amsterdam We got back just in time for the last day of The Gates exhibition  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of anemia with diastolic dysfunction among patients with coronary artery disease in the Heart and Soul Study</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/02/association-of-anemia-with-diastolic-dysfunction-among-patients-with-coronary-artery-disease-in-the-heart-and-soul-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/02/association-of-anemia-with-diastolic-dysfunction-among-patients-with-coronary-artery-disease-in-the-heart-and-soul-study/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to my cousin Deepu for getting published in the American Journal of Cardiology.
He found a strong association between anemia and diastolic dysfunction in patients with coronary disease. Diastolic dysfunction is a condition in which a patient has clinical signs of heart failure, but a normal left ventricular systolic function. So, for some reason, the heart is pumping vigorously, but fluid is still backing up (into the legs or into the lungs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harinamakirtanam</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/21/harinamakirtanam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/21/harinamakirtanam/</guid>
      <description>My Dad&amp;rsquo;s book got reviewed in the Hindu (one of India&amp;rsquo;s national newspapers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall of water</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/08/11/wall-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/08/11/wall-of-water/</guid>
      <description>http://www.cnn.com/2004/US/West/08/05/wallofwater.ap/index.html (link now broken)
 The sudden release of water from Ralston Reservoir south of Auburn sent a &amp;ldquo;wall of water three to four-feet high&amp;rdquo; down the Middle Fork of the American River, said California Highway Patrol spokesman Tom Marshall.
 That&amp;rsquo;s the river that we rafted down a couple weeks ago during our 5th Annual Cousins Trip. If it had happened during our trip, I still probably would&amp;rsquo;ve been the first one to fall in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Party</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/09/christmas-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/09/christmas-party/</guid>
      <description>I missed the Milwaukee Malayalee Christmas Party this past weekend, but Lisa sent me pics. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to go home for the holidays&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Reunion</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/09/summer-reunion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/09/summer-reunion/</guid>
      <description>Ooops - I just realized that I forgot to link to the pics from our Reunion back in August. At least I got them posted before the end of the year.
Comments from old site Everybody looks the same
 Hey Vin, I checked out your pics from your family reunion and everybody looks the same, your parents haven&#39;t aged a bit and Mini and Manu haven&#39;t changed either, you may have put on a few pounds but who hasn&#39;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Seattle</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/14/more-seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/14/more-seattle/</guid>
      <description>Girish has put up some pics from the Seattle trip and other family events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 degrees?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/13/6-degrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/13/6-degrees/</guid>
      <description>An article in the NY Times claims that &amp;lsquo;6 degrees of separation&amp;rsquo; is an exaggeration. They tested it by asking people to forward emails to people that they knew in hopes that the chain would eventually lead to 1 of the researchers&amp;rsquo; destinations. I know that I delete any chain mail that I get, so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that the study&amp;rsquo;s results are valid.
Let me provide an anecdotal rebuttal. I went to Subha and Archana&amp;rsquo;s wedding in Chicago last weekend and I&amp;rsquo;m guessing there were 400 people there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4th Annual Cousins Reunion</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/31/4th-annual-cousins-reunion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/31/4th-annual-cousins-reunion/</guid>
      <description>We went whitewater rafting in Pennsylvania in 2000, sea-kayaking in North Carolina in 2001, and death-marching (er&amp;hellip; hiking) in the Grand Canyon in 2002. This year, we chose kayaking and hiking in Seattle.
We went kayaking near the San Juan Islands on Thursday. It was a great upper body workout and our guide Martine was a fountain of information. We saw some harbor seals close up and a bald eagle from afar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My brother is so cool</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/03/03/my-brother-is-so-cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/03/03/my-brother-is-so-cool/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to put this pic up for a while. That&amp;rsquo;s me in back, with my super-cool brother and his even-cooler Harley Davidson VRod. It was about 40 degrees F and despite sitting in back and despite having the warm helmet, I was still freezing. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine what Manu was feeling. Halfway through the ride, I asked him, but his face was too frozen to talk. :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India 2003</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/20/india-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/20/india-2003/</guid>
      <description>My parents and I went to India for 2 weeks. We spent a couple days in Delhi and then the rest of the time in Kerala. I thoroughly enjoyed myself and actually found the vacation relaxing. Kerala is more beautiful than I ever remember (somehow I seem to forget in between trips). It&amp;rsquo;s lush and green and the food is amazing. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to go back. Here are some pics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grand Canyon Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/22/grand-canyon-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/22/grand-canyon-update/</guid>
      <description>I found some more pictures from the Phoenix trip, so check &amp;lsquo;em out again! And please don&amp;rsquo;t touch or sit on the Indians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pics</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/14/pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/07/14/pics/</guid>
      <description>Geoff organized a mini-residency-reunion back in June and somehow scammed Joyce and Howard into hosting it :-)
Manu, Girish, Deepu and I hiked the Grand Canyon in mid-June. I&amp;rsquo;m still not clear who decided it was a great idea to hike down to the Colorado River and back in 115 degree weather, but that may be due to the fact that I fried a good number of my brain cells that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girish is published!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/29/girish-is-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/29/girish-is-published/</guid>
      <description>My cousin Girish was interviewed for an article about hormone replacement in heart disease on Rx.com. Unfortunately Rx.com has gone kaput and the author doesn&amp;rsquo;t want me to publish the article here, so it&amp;rsquo;s no longer available. Take my word that it was interesting and Girish sounded really smart!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bunch of stuff</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/26/bunch-of-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/26/bunch-of-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Life has been moving too quickly for me to document my menial existence. Check back again soon when my existence is not so menial! In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a Cliff Note&amp;rsquo;s version (may Cliff rest in peace) of the past 5 months (in no particular order).
 I left medicalrecords.com I began doing freelance web development I finished a Palm-based interface for The Answer Page I began moonlighting at MIT&amp;rsquo;s After Hours Medical Center, thus getting in touch with my &amp;ldquo;medical&amp;rdquo; side again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter From Devi</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/10/22/letter-from-devi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/10/22/letter-from-devi/</guid>
      <description>I recently got a letter from my niece, Devi, which broke my heart&amp;hellip;
 Dear Vinu Mamman,
I visited your page and you didn&amp;rsquo;t put a picture of me. I am really mad at you because you didn&amp;rsquo;t give me a picture. Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you put a picture of me? If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a picture of me, I could send you one. Everybody else have a picture of them. If you have a picture you can put it on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cruise</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/03/01/cruise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/03/01/cruise/</guid>
      <description>In March &amp;lsquo;98, after a grueling month in the ICU, I went on a cruise with my cousins and their parents. I&amp;rsquo;m currently seriously considering working as a cruise physician! We went to Freeport and Nassau. The weather and scenery were beautiful, but my most enjoyable moments were spent discussing old (and new) times with my cousins at 3:00 AM looking across the unending ocean.
It&amp;rsquo;s an experience I hope to repeat soon&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>