<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gtd | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/gtd/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-08T21:58:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Priorities and GTD]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/17/priorities-and-gtd"/>
    <updated>2013-01-17T13:38:07-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/17/priorities-and-gtd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pre-GTD task management systems recommended that you assign a priority
to each task. When looking at a list of tasks, you then choose the
ones with the highest priority. David Allen (author of GTD) includes
'priority' as one of the things that you should consider when you are
deciding what to do, but only after you have considered context, time
available, and energy available. Which makes sense. As Merlin Mann
says, it doesn't matter if mowing your lawn is your highest priority
when you're sitting in an airplane. Only if you're in the right
context with the right amount of time and the right amount of energy,
should you consider which of the remaining available tasks is highest
priority.</p>

<p>The risk, though, is that there are so many little 'easy' tasks that I
could do instead of important, 'hard' tasks. I'm also really good at
convincing myself that I don't have the energy available to do harder
tasks when I really should. So when I get back into GTD, I process all
the things hiding in the back of my brain which leads to the creation
of lots of simple tasks. Google this, buy that, throw away the other
thing. But the two things that I really want to be doing more are
writing and programming. Both of those take blocks of uninterrupted
time and effort, so I end up subconsciously shying away from them. I
actually feel better about it, too, because now I have all these other
tasks that I can do instead. So, I feel productive, even when ignoring
the more important things that I should be doing. I'm moving more
efficiently, but in the wrong direction.</p>

<p>I've avoided that a little bit this time by doing a little bit of
prioritization each night before I go to bed. I look through my todo
list and pick about 3-5 things that I want to get done the next day. I
tag those with the 'today' tag and then the next morning I look at
that list and start working on those things before doing anything
else. I've heard this
<a href="http://gettingresults.com/wiki/The_Rule_of_3">trick</a> from a lot of
people before, so I don't remember who I heard it from first.</p>

<p>So far it's been effective for me. The problem always starts again
though when I go back on service, because then I can only really focus
on one thing and that is getting my work done at the hospital. We'll
see if I can somehow figure out a way to get at least one non-work
thing done on each of those days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GTD again?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/16/gtd-again"/>
    <updated>2013-01-16T09:27:03-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/16/gtd-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to
<a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w/95">Merlin Mann's recent series of podcasts on GTD</a>,
I'm getting back on the GTD wagon (for about the 100th time). I read
<a href="http://www.davidco.com/">Getting Things Done</a> in 2002 and have been
trying to implement it ever since. I've had periods where I followed
it religiously for a month at a time, but it's never completely stuck.
From what I hear, this is normal and I accept it now. This won't be
the last time that I restart GTD. Even when I'm not actively using
GTD, I think in GTD terms, thinking about next actions and projects
and ruthlessly placing projects on the backburner. I just have trouble
sticking with the entire GTD workflow, especially the ubiquitous
capture (I trust my brain too much) and the weekly reviews (they just
seem too painful). I've used every online and offline tool in the
book, too. Despite not doing so great with GTD, I'd say my life is an
overwhelming success.</p>

<p>So why try again? Each time I have gotten back on the bandwagon, I've
had a surge in productivity. I wrote more. I made some clear decisions
on issues that I had been procrastinating on. I wouldn't be surprised
if each of my major life improvements over the past 10 years was
associated with a time where I got back on the GTD wagon. I can't
prove that, because I don't keep enough details, but I always feel
better and think clearer when I'm on GTD.</p>

<p>But, I've failed so many times... what kind of hubris makes me think
I'll get it this time?
<a href="http://www.quotationspage.com/quote/36285.html">"Fall down seven times, get up eight."</a>
Parenthood has taught this to me. Of course we don't expect our kids
to learn each skill the first time they try. We expect that walking
and reading and writing and bike-riding will take time, multiple
efforts, and multiple failures. But eventually they will get it. Yet,
with each failure, kids get upset (to varying degrees). The answer at
that point is not to tell them to give up. Yet, that's what I do to
myself. So, I'm going to treat myself like a kid and let myself fail,
understanding that each failure will get me closer to that one time
where I will succeed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
