<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>clojure on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/clojure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in clojure on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 21:59:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/clojure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Factoring Large Numbers</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/11/29/on-factoring-large-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 21:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/11/29/on-factoring-large-numbers/</guid>
      <description>I wonder how many of my blog posts are based on stories from This American Life. Probably not enough. Every time I start to listen to a show, I&amp;rsquo;m certain that I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be interested and within a minute I&amp;rsquo;m trapped and can&amp;rsquo;t stop listening. It&amp;rsquo;s that good. A recent show was about people who people who pursued crazy ideas. The first story was about a mathematician named Frank Nelson Cole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClojureScript and PhoneGap</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/11/12/clojurescript-and-phonegap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 21:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/11/12/clojurescript-and-phonegap/</guid>
      <description>Phonegap is a tool that allows you to develop apps in HTML5 + javascript and makes it easy to deploy them to multiple mobile platforms, including Android and iOS.
ClojureScript is a dialect of the awesome language, Clojure, that compiles to Javascript (after a pass through the Google Closure optimizer). Because Clojure, ClojureScript and Google Closure can be confusing terms, I&amp;rsquo;ll use CLJS instead of ClojureScript for the remainder of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maps are functions, too</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/05/maps-are-functions-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/05/maps-are-functions-too/</guid>
      <description>Braindump time. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve read about clojure in the past few days. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand what this means yet, but maybe someday I will:
 Clojure provides easy access to the Java frameworks, with optional type hints and type inference, to ensure that calls to Java can avoid reflection.
 There are multiple languages that target the JVM (besides Java, of course). It seems that there are 2 classes of languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Anti-Writing Cycle</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/27/my-anti-writing-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/27/my-anti-writing-cycle/</guid>
      <description>I blogged daily for a 6 day stretch a couple weeks ago, which is the longest continuous stretch I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done. It was stimulating and stressful at the same time. I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard from the Pulitzer committee about any of the posts yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s not the quality that matters. Writing is more about the process than the product, and I know from experience that writing helps me think. And while most of the posts were written for my own benefit, I really enjoyed the response that I got from family and friends about Playdoh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Steps with Clojure</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/18/first-steps-with-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2010 16:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/18/first-steps-with-clojure/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned yesterday, I&amp;rsquo;m teaching myself clojure. I started by trying to install it.
vinod@ike$ aptitude install clojure  Ubuntu has packaged version 1.0.0 of clojure. I always default to the OS-installed version of programs, just for ease of maintenance. The current stable version of clojure is 1.1 and it appears that 1.2 is in beta. I have no idea what has been changed in 1.1 or 1.2, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to get along using 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting some clojure</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/17/getting-some-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 19:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/17/getting-some-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Steve Yegge is one of my favorite bloggers. I read &amp;ldquo;You Should Write Blogs&amp;rdquo; a long time ago and it is one of the main reasons that I still try to keep this blog going at all. He recently took a blogging hiatus and in his return post, he left a little hint that he was interested in a programming language called clojure.
My programming skills have been rusting away (Darn those patients, always getting sick and stuff!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>