<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Running</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/running/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m a runner and have been for almost 30 years now. I suppose I&amp;rsquo;m only going to get slower from here on in, so I thought I should list all my PR&amp;rsquo;s so that I can brag while I can.
Here are my blog posts about running.
PRs  | Age &amp;lt;= 30 | Age &amp;gt; 30 | -----------+-----------+----------+ 800m | 2:12 | N/A | 1 mile | 5:07 | 5:44 | 2 mile | 11:06 | N/A | 5K | 18:36 | 23:02 | 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Vinod Kurup</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my home page! (Yes, I know it&amp;rsquo;s 2012, but I still call it my home page). I&amp;rsquo;m probably the luckiest guy in the world, with a beautiful wife and 3 sweet, life-loving kids to prove it. I am a hospitalist working at a community hospital in North Carolina. I&amp;rsquo;m a Milwaukee Malayalee who hopes to retire in NYC someday. I am also a (free software) programmer, writer, runner, foodie, homeowner, reader, investor, in addition to about a hundred other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicine</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/medicine/</guid>
      <description> Presentations Here are some presentations that I&amp;rsquo;ve made in the past. Feel free to use them, if you find them useful.
 Emacs for Python Programming PDF PPTX- Last updated October 2012 Osteoporosis (odp) - Last updated 2006 Adult Immunizations (odp) - Last updated 2004 Abnormal LFTs (odp) - Last updated 2003  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old About Me</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/old-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/old-about/</guid>
      <description>I was born in Columbus, Ohio, but my parents moved to Milwaukee, Wisconsin when I was about 2 years old. Hence, I am forever a cheesehead!!! My family still lives in Wisconsin. Thanks to my brother and sister (and my brother-in-law and sister-in-law, of course), I have 6 beautiful and wonderful nieces and nephews. Being here on the east coast, I miss them very much and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to go home and see them again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/license/</guid>
      <description>Copied and adapted from Parsia Hakimian &amp;hellip;
Content License Except where otherwise noted, my non-code content on this website is licensed under a Creative Commons BY-NC-SA 4.0 (Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International).
Code License Except where otherwise noted, my code on this website is licensed under MIT:
 Copyright &amp;copy; 1998-2019 Vinod Kurup
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>