<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>interesting on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/interesting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in interesting on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/interesting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Literature delivered to your inbox</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox/</guid>
      <description>DailyLit.com is an interesting service that takes classic books and chops them up in to bite-sized pieces that you can read in just a few minutes. It then emails you one piece at a time until you finish the book. You can customize how often you get the emails.
I just finished &amp;ldquo;The Art of Money Getting&amp;rdquo;, by P.T. Barnum. It has a lot of practical advice, and predates (by 100 years) a lot of what you see these days in self-help books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful mind</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/beautiful-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/beautiful-mind/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the most amazing things I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. An autistic man takes a 45 minute helicopter ride over Rome and recreates what he sees with near perfect accuracy on paper. More information about him
  This guy&amp;rsquo;s brain is structurally the same as mine, yet its capabilities make my brain seem like it&amp;rsquo;s broken. It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable to think that my brain could have the same capability if it were exposed to the proper conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking History is history</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/08/04/talking-history-is-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/08/04/talking-history-is-history/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite podcasts is going on hiatus. (A podcast is basically a fancy word for a radio show that you can download to your MP3 player.) Talking History is produced by the Organization of American Historians and because of budget problems, they cutting funding for Talking History.
The host Brian LeBeau is the epitome of a great interviewer. He mostly stays in the background, giving the stage to the historian, but when he asks a question, you immediately feel like it&amp;rsquo;s a question that you would want to ask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gladwell blogs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/gladwell-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/gladwell-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Sorry for two posts about Gladwell in one day, but I just found out that Gladwell has started a blog. Looks like he started the day after his Columbia speech which is interesting because he put some blame on the internet for our society&amp;rsquo;s bias towards Picasso. Maybe he&amp;rsquo;s trying to test his theories :-)
Gladwell is one of most interesting writers I have read and is as adept a speaker as he is a writer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picasso vs Cézanne</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/24/picasso-vs-c%C3%A9zanne/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/24/picasso-vs-c%C3%A9zanne/</guid>
      <description>We saw Malcolm Gladwell talk at Columbia on Tuesday. He&amp;rsquo;s the author of Blink and The Tipping Point and he&amp;rsquo;s a staff writer at the New Yorker. He spoke about different types of genius. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to recreate his main points from memory, so I apologize in advance if I&amp;rsquo;ve remembered things incorrectly.
His talk was about the artists Picasso and Cézanne. An economist named David Galenson did an analysis of the market value of paintings of these great artists and concluded that they represented two distinct types of genius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David T is Blogging!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/06/david-t-is-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/01/06/david-t-is-blogging/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s taken quite a while, but my friend Dave has finally started blogging. You can read his mini-bio on our Wedding Party page. For more info about him, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to follow his blog. I&amp;rsquo;m hosting his site on my server and I&amp;rsquo;ve been too lazy to change the layout of his blog, so it may look eerily familiar at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Zeitgeist</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/google-zeitgeist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/google-zeitgeist/</guid>
      <description>Every year, Google does an analysis of search queries over the past year. They call it the Google Zeitgeist. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how &amp;lsquo;what we search for&amp;rsquo; is a very accurate historical record of our times. The Apple iPod takes up 4 of the top 10 searches on Froogle, Google&amp;rsquo;s consumer search engine.
If you liked Zeitgeist, you can monitor weekly updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Maps</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/08/google-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/08/google-maps/</guid>
      <description>Wow Google Maps is really cool. You can drag the maps around. How cool is that? Put in a location, then drag the map so that the location that you put in is just off the map. Then click the little red signpost on the right hand column and google rescrolls so that your location is back on the map. Very nice!
Read more at the Google Maps Tour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are SUVs safe?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/10/are-suvs-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/10/are-suvs-safe/</guid>
      <description>Interesting article about SUV safety. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quote:
 Most of us think that S.U.V.s are much safer than sports cars. If you asked the young parents of America whether they would rather strap their infant child in the back seat of the TrailBlazer or the passenger seat of the Boxster, they would choose the TrailBlazer. We feel that way because in the TrailBlazer our chances of surviving a collision with a hypothetical tractor-trailer in the other lane are greater than they are in the Porsche.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>