<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>emacs on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emacs on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 21:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Emacs Posts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/23/some-emacs-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 21:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/23/some-emacs-posts/</guid>
      <description>A few cool Emacs posts have flown across my radar, so I&amp;rsquo;m noting them here for that time in the future when I have time to play with them.
 Get unicode glyphs to show properly. (╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻ Creating slides with org-mode and Reveal.js. Finally, a sane way to create a presentation :) Anzu: Improves incremental search. Anzu shows the number of matches found, and how many matches remain in the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs for Python Programming</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/24/emacs-for-python-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 16:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/24/emacs-for-python-programming/</guid>
      <description>(Note: See the bottom of this post for updates)
I was honored to to give my &amp;ldquo;Emacs for Python Programming&amp;rdquo; talk at the inaugural PyCarolinas conference. The conference was a huge success in every way, thanks to the efforts of Calvin Spealman, et. al. I promised that I would post my Emacs setup, so here it is.
Step 0: Prerequisites This may work with other setups, but here&amp;rsquo;s what I tested:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Autocomplete stumbles on yasnippet</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/15/emacs-autocomplete-stumbles-on-yasnippet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 13:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/15/emacs-autocomplete-stumbles-on-yasnippet/</guid>
      <description>Autocomplete Mode is an Emacs mode that tries to guess what word you&amp;rsquo;re typing and provide auto-completion. Recently, it started failing in simple scenarios.
It can use various &amp;lsquo;sources&amp;rsquo; to try to figure out what you&amp;rsquo;re about to type. The simplest source is ac-source-dictionary which is a simple list of words. If you start typing any of those words, it will try to autocomplete them for you. Normally, you&amp;rsquo;d put those words in a file, with each word on a separate line, but for testing purposes, you can also add them manually using an elisp function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making blog posting easier</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/05/making-blog-posting-easier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 07:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/05/making-blog-posting-easier/</guid>
      <description>Another piece of advice that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard over and over again is to make things easier. Automate! In that vein, I learned a little elisp in order to make it easier to create a new blog post. I create my posts in emacs, but I often cut and paste the YAML header from a previous post, which is tedious and time-consuming. Here is my new posting function:
(defun vk-blogpost (title) &amp;quot;Create a new blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editing as root in emacs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/editing-as-root-in-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/editing-as-root-in-emacs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using emacs for 7 years and I just learned today that you can edit files as root while you&amp;rsquo;re logged into emacs as an unprivileged user. Using sudo, of course. The details are here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psql doesn&#39;t like tabs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/24/psql-doesnt-like-tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/24/psql-doesnt-like-tabs/</guid>
      <description>psql doesn&amp;rsquo;t deal well with tabs. If you feed it a function that has tabs in it, and then call that function, you&amp;rsquo;ll often get this: ERROR: parser: parse error at or near &amp;quot;for&amp;quot; at character 15. Thus, if you ever see this in your error log, it&amp;rsquo;s time to M-x untabify.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>