<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: howto | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/howto/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-09T07:01:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to change the rear tire on a 12 inch bicycle]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/12/30/how-to-change-the-rear-tire-on-a-12-inch-bicycle"/>
    <updated>2012-12-30T15:00:40-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/12/30/how-to-change-the-rear-tire-on-a-12-inch-bicycle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm not the handiest guy in the world, so I'm pretty proud that I was
able to fix a flat tire on Kavi's 12" bicycle.</p>

<p>DISCLAIMER: I have almost no idea what I'm doing. Follow my
instructions at your peril.</p>

<p>I've fixed flats before, but it's been a long time. Fixing it on such
a tiny bike was a lot harder than I thought. The manual makes it seem
so simple. "Remove the wheel, take the tube out, patch the tube and
then replace the tube and tire." Right... I got stuck at step 1.
Removing the wheel isn't straightforward. Most of the videos available
online focus on adult-sized bikes which have quick-release tires. You
pull a release lever back and then pull the tire off. Kids bikes have
bolts instead of quick-release levers. You have to loosen the bolts,
but you don't have to take the bolts completely off. You also have to
take off the plastic chain guard that prevents kids from rubbing their
legs against the chain. Finally, there's this little metal piece that
attaches the wheel to the frame. I think it's there for the
pedal-brake to work. In any case, you have to take that off. Once the
wheel is loosened, you have to unhook the wheel from the chain. This
is also easier in big bikes which have multiple gears, making it
possible to place the chain in a position to easily get it off the
wheel. In a kid's bike, it's harder. Once I loosened the bolts on both
sides of the wheel, I pushed the wheel a little forward, which
loosened the chain and made it easy to release from the chain.</p>

<p>The next difficulty was getting the tube out of the tire. All the
videos make this seem so easy. Place a tire lever in the tire to pull
it over the rim. Put another tire lever in and slide it around the rim
to get the rest of the tire out. Kavi's tires are so tight that this
was impossible. I could get the first tire lever in, but when I put
the second tire lever in, it was completely immovable. There was no
way that I was going to be able to slide it anywhere. I finally found
a website where they recommended using a third tire lever. Put the
first two in a few inches apart. Then put the third one in another
inch away from the second one. Finally remove the middle one and move
it an inch past the third one. In this way, I was able to get the tire
off eventually.</p>

<p>I then got the tube out and found the leak. I placed a patch on it,
but when I reinflated the tire, the leaking air just pushed it's way
through the patch. I tried roughing up the area with the roughing
tool, but that didn't help. Finally, I resorted to the layman's
favorite tool: duct tape. I placed the patch, then wrapped it with
duct tape. It's held together for a few months now.</p>

<p>Hopefully Kavi will graduate to the next size bike before my handiwork
breaks down. On another note, Kavi was easily able to pick up the
basics of riding a bike by following the
<a href="http://www.rei.com/learn/expert-advice/teach-child-to-ride-a-bike.html">REI guide</a>.
I took off the training wheels and the pedals, which allowed him to
get the feeling of balancing the bike without having to keep his feet
on the pedals. Once he got that part, it was relatively easy for him
to balance with the pedals on. He also proved to be a much tougher kid
than I was. Everytime he fell, he got right back on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
