<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: running | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/running/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-07T22:18:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting through the start of a run]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/11/getting-through-the-start-of-a-run"/>
    <updated>2011-08-11T12:06:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/11/getting-through-the-start-of-a-run</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love running. Wait, that's a lie. I love running after I've finished
my run. I also love it during those periods where I get my runner's
high, usually around the 30 minute mark, but often it happens multiple
times after that point. I <strong>don't</strong> love running when I'm
contemplating going for a run. There are rare occasions where I'm just
itching to go for a run, but usually I'm only able start a run by
forcibly suppressing the compelling rationalizations that my brain
develops. My brain is really good at finding reasons not to run. One
trick that seems to work is to tell my brain that I have the right to
turn around when I get to the mailbox at the end of the driveway. Of
course, once I've done the mechanics of getting my shoes and starting,
I never turn around. My brain is so gullible.</p>

<p>I also don't love my run during the first 10 to 15 minutes. Those are
always a struggle. Always. Stretching beforehand makes it less of a
struggle, but I hate stretching, so I rarely do that. I have a few
techniques to get myself through the beginnings of my runs.</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Count</strong>: Just count from 1 to 100. Once you get to a hundred, start
over. This one works the best. That's why it's first!</li>
<li><strong>Mantra</strong>: Repeat a mantra to yourself. My favorites are: <em>Keep
covering ground</em> (inspired by my favorite running book, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0915297019/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=vinodkurupshomep&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369&amp;creativeASIN=0915297019">Once a Runner</a>) and <em>Just keep swimming</em>
<iframe width="560" height="349"
src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/CmyUkm2qlhA?rel=0" frameborder="0"
allowfullscreen></iframe></li>
<li><strong>Food</strong>: Start thinking about what I'm going to eat after the
run. OK, this rarely helps, but I can't stop thinking about it.</li>
<li><strong>Slow</strong>: If I'm really feeling sluggish, then I force myself to slow
down. As I've mentioned before, <a href="/blog/2009/09/22/running-slow/">running
slow</a> is probably the most important
running technique I have. It's counter-intuitive, but it always
work. Running slower than I think I should always makes the run go
faster than I thought it would.</li>
<li><strong>Shorten</strong>: Shorten your stride. I aim to get 3 strides per
second, which seems really quick to me. In order to do that I shorten
my stride. I think most runners would benefit from a shorter
stride. It automatically improves your form.</li>
</ol>


<p>Basically, all of these are tricks to get your mind to focus on
something else besides the pain of the run. One thing that also helps
is to listen to music or podcasts. It works by the same principle of
getting your mind off the pain, but I found that my best runs were
always the ones where I left the iPod at home. It certainly makes the
beginning of the run harder, but it frees my brain up to really listen
to my body. I would otherwise find myself adjusting my pace to the
beat of the music, rather than to the pace that my body naturally
wanted to go. I also tend to have my deepest thoughts (don't laugh!)
when I'm running and having music pumped in would drown those out. I
consider it my meditation practice, since I suck at real
meditation. Finally, it's a safety issue. When running in the woods,
you never know what kind of creature will attack:</p>

<p>{% img /images/deer.jpg Deer %}
{% img /images/turtle.jpg Turtle %}</p>

<p>Take my advice for what it's worth... running advice from a part-time
runner who is slower than molasses. I'd love to hear any other running
tricks you have!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running as a metaphor for life]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/09/running-as-a-metaphor-for-life"/>
    <updated>2011-08-09T20:41:02-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/09/running-as-a-metaphor-for-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was thinking the other day, on a run, of course, about the many ways
that running is a metaphor for life. I've <a href="/blog/2003/10/28/the-wall-is-not-a-myth/">discussed some of this
before with my cousins Dilu and
Harish</a> before.</p>

<p>{% blockquote Robert Frost http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Road_Not_Taken_(poem) %}
... two roads diverged in a wood, and I --
I took the one less traveled by,
And that has made all the difference.
{% endblockquote %}</p>

<p>While trail running, I have come to the realization that you never
have to worry about the fork in the road, nor the decision associated
with it. During my first trail run in the forest near our home, I was
amazed by the number of single track trailheads that I saw. I didn't
take any of them that first day, content to just take the wide dirt
path along the creek. After a few runs though, I started to take some
of the single track trails and found myself amongst even more
beautiful nature. I found more forks in the trails and I agonized a
bit about taking the right one, mainly so I wouldn't get lost. Now
that I've run in the woods dozens of times, I don't worry about the
fork in the road. I know that I can take one fork today and the other
fork tomorrow.</p>

<p>Life is like that too. Every decision point seems so important. Making
the wrong decision seems like it will doom me forever. But, I've found
so far that there are very few decisions that are not
reversible. Certainly some are, but even the important ones like
career and family don't have to be set in stone. I wish I had come to
this realization earlier. Every decision seems so final at the time
that I'm making it, but when you look back it seems obvious that there
are plenty of options available, no matter which path you chose. Even
knowing that bias, it's hard to remember that when a new decision has
to be made.</p>

<p>Some of the single track trails have pathmarkers to help keep you on
the right trail. They are little numbered plastic circles nailed to a
tree. They are few and far between. Occasionally, you'll come to a
fork in the trail and there won't be an obvious pathmarker around, so
you have to make a decision. That can be somewhat stressful, so you
keep your eyes peeled for pathmarkers as you're running to see if you
made the right decision. At some point, you've gone so far without
seeing a marker that you're almost certain that you've gone the wrong
way. Either you keep the faith and keep going, or you turn around and
try the other fork. There is no right answer.</p>

<p>Life is sometimes like that. We have signposts and decision trees that
are easy to follow in many cases. But inevitably, there will be a
point where we have to make a decision without all of the evidence or
without all of the data or without a clear idea of where we're
going. Not until you take that leap of faith will you get the signal
that you've made the right decision. And sometimes that signal won't
come for a long time. I'm not sure what the point of this is, but it
seemed very profound at the time while I was running in the woods,
about to give up, thinking that I had gone down the wrong path, when I
suddenly saw the elusive pathmarker that confirmed that I was not
lost. Trail running is like that... everything is not set in stone and
predefined. You have to develop your faith and intuition, and if that
fails, accept that maybe you'll do better next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Philosopher's Way Trail Run]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/05/07/philosophers-way-trail-run"/>
    <updated>2011-05-07T20:44:27-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/05/07/philosophers-way-trail-run</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I ran the 15K <a href="http://www.trailheads.org/pwtr/">Philosopher's Way Trail
Run</a> today. It's on the eastern end
of Carolina North Forest. I've been running a lot on the western end
of these trails so I had never seen any of these trails before. The
weather was perfect - sunny and mid 50's - and the trails were in good
shape. I only got a little muddy. The race was very well organized for
such a small race. The only minor annoyance was the beginning of the
race where a couple hundred runners turned from a 20 foot wide course
onto a single track bike course. Everyone came to a halt and we all
walked for about a quarter mile. I didn't really start running
smoothly until about a mile in and the next 3 miles were spent passing
and waiting, passing and waiting. That in itself is ok ... it's part
of trail running. I would've just extended the time that we were on
the wide track to give time for people to string out a bit more. Like I
said ... minor annoyance.</p>

<p>Once we got moving, I had a blast. I just love running in the woods. I
felt unstoppable until about mile 7 and then I lost my gumption and my
thighs started to complain. I held on to the people in front of me as
much as I could, but one person did pass me at the end, the only
person to pass me in the last 5 miles. I think I saw 1:33 as I
finished, but my GPS time was 1:29:09. I think it stops the clock
whenever it thinks I have stopped and it got really confused on the
trails. It recorded my final distance as 6.0 miles which is 3.3 miles
too short. I had suspicions that my earlier trail runs were
underestimated, but never thought it was this inaccurate. My <a href="http://www.lovingtherun.com/running-tips/the-a-b-cs">B
goal</a> was 1:30 so
I was close and I definitely hit my C goal.</p>

<p>I'll definitely be doing this run again next year, if I'm free. I'm
currently posting my runs at <a href="http://www.dailymile.com/">dailymile</a> (a
cool site built by two <a href="http://onwisconsin.uwalumni.com/departments/ben-weiner-06-and-kelly-korevec-06-partnership-in-motion/">UW
grads</a>),
so <a href="http://www.dailymile.com/people/vkurup">follow me</a> there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time is the most powerful force in the universe]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/21/time-is-the-most-powerful-force-in-the-universe"/>
    <updated>2011-02-21T14:23:43-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/21/time-is-the-most-powerful-force-in-the-universe</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to Mala's inspiration, I've been running a lot more over the
past month. Whenever I get into a good running rhythm, my mind starts
to relax and I occasionally get bright ideas (believe it or
not!). While I am running, these always seem Nobel Prize-worthy, but
they seem to lose some of their glitter when the endorphins wear
off. I still believe we could solve all the world's problems if
everyone was a runner.</p>

<p>On a recent run, I was thinking about how Einstein said that compound
interest is the most powerful force in the universe. (<a href="http://www.snopes.com/quotes/einstein/interest.asp">Turns out he
probably didn't say
that</a>, but let's
pretend someone did.) It occurred
to me that really, it's <em>time</em> that is the most powerful
force. Compound interest is a function of time and possibly may be the
most efficient way to turn time into money, but <em>time</em> is what makes
compound interest powerful. Compound interest over the course of 10
days isn't very powerful. Any activity repeated over a long period of
time can be a powerful force, even if each individual activity doesn't
accomplish much.</p>

<p>Spending a few minutes a day over the past few weeks
has made a significant difference in my life. I've started a <strong>Habit</strong>
spreadsheet to track some habits, specifically, brushing my teeth at
night (wanted to start with something easy), writing, pushups,
running and meditation. Each day's activity is miniscule, sometimes to
the point of seeming pointless, but over just a few weeks, I've seen
tangible benefits. I'm writing more and therefore learning more about
myself. Sure, I've also written some really bad stuff, but I know if I
continue these sessions, my life will improve because I will know more
about what I really want out of life. That small amount of time,
compounded over days, weeks and years will make such a huge
difference. The kind of difference where, in a year from now, I'll be
able to describe it better than "such a huge difference".</p>

<p>I am probably in better shape than I've been in since college because
I'm running, doing push-ups and playing more with the kids. I ran 40
miles last week, which I haven't done since my marathon training
days. It felt easy and most importantly it's been giving my mind some
time to relax (and generate blog posts like this!) Finally, I'm
meditating daily and while that has felt like the least useful of the
new habits I'm forming, it is the habit that I think has the most
overall potential to improve my life. Having more control over my
thoughts and my mind will have positive implications for all parts of
my life. My mind has just been very hard to settle down during my
sessions so far. (Any tips for a beginning meditator would be
appreciated!)</p>

<p>I also started working on my website again and I found that I was able
to pick up commands and bits of knowledge that I thought I had
forgotten. Little pieces of web scripting and SQL just seemed to come
back to me even though I haven't actively used them in a couple
years. Since I had put in so much time learning them before, I picked
them up with much less effort now. Same with running. I find it
impossible to run on days that I am working, so I have to wait for my
"stretches off" to run. It used to be really hard to get to a decent
level when I had taken time off, but now I can take a week off and
still run 5 miles without feeling bad. Maybe that's because I <a href="/blog/2009/09/22/running-slow/">run so
slow</a>.</p>

<p>When I think about the huge benefit I've gotten in a few weeks with
such a small amount of daily commitments, I just can't wait to see
what will happen in a few years! Thinking that far in the future used
to seem ridiculous because I always wanted results <strong>now</strong>, but the
older I get, the more I'm willing to wait. Paradoxically, stretching
out my time-frame for results makes it more likely that I will see
results sooner. When I was always trying to make things happen
<strong>now</strong>, I would ignore the little self-improvement things in the name
of efficiency. Now that I take the time to do those things, the
benefits compound with time and I may end up seeing results even on
the things that have nothing directly to do with the habits I'm
performing daily.</p>

<p>I also thought about how I've been trying to simplify my life and I
wonder whether it was worth it. As a general rule, simplifying is a
great idea. Try to drive less, spend less, eat less. Those are all
good things. But I also found that I limited the time that I spent
developing my website. I moved it from <a href="http://openacs.org">OpenACS</a>
to a static template solution. There were steps in between, but each
step since leaving OpenACS has been in the name of
simplification. OpenACS (like all active free-software projects) was
changing and I couldn't keep up with it while also being a dad and a
doctor, so I thought it would be better to outsource
(<a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a>) or simplify
(<a href="http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a>/<a href="http://blogofile.com">Blogofile</a>). While
that seems to make sense, it also means that I've spent less time on
my website and one of the joys of my life became smaller. So, I am
going to take a more active role in improving my website because I
love doing it. I'm not going back to OpenACS, because I do think it
was more complex than I needed. I've reimplemented google analytics
and adsense because watching those numbers gave me some satisfaction.</p>

<p>Final thought for the day. I've gotten so much accomplished over the
past few weeks because I've become more physically and mentally
active. I used fatherhood as an excuse to avoid running and self
improvement. I said I didn't have time for it. That lack of activity
just reflects poorly on everything else in life. I know that's too
dramatic, because life truly has been good for all of us. But, I guess
my lesson to new parents would be to make time for exercise and
self-improvement. It will make you a better parent.</p>

<p>Lessons from this run:</p>

<ol>
<li>Time is the most powerful force in the universe; using it to do
meaningful things is <strong>never</strong> a waste.</li>
<li>Don't simplify things that you enjoy doing!</li>
<li>Take care of yourself first.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Found the Carolina North trail]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2009/10/09/found-the-carolina-north-trail"/>
    <updated>2009-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2009/10/09/found-the-carolina-north-trail</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When Mala and I started looking for homes, we listed on a yellow notepad
all the things that were important to us. Like most little notes in my
life, it got lost. I found it a few days after we moved into our home and
was pleasantly surprised that we had gotten everything on our list, except
a lake view. Not bad, and there's a lake about a half mile from our
door. One of the things on that list that we "kinda" got was "running
trails nearby". I say "kinda" because there is a trail which is just behind
the back of our property, but I wouldn't call it a running trail. It is a
paved trail which runs behind the houses in our neighborhood and extends
about 1 mile in total length. It is mostly through woods or along the lake,
so it's nice, but it's not a running trail. A running trail is not
paved. More importantly, a running trail goes for miles and miles, so that
you can feel like you are away from (sub)urban life.</p>

<p>So this was one of those things on our "list" that I would say we checked
off, but, not really, you know?</p>

<p>I <a href="http://twitter.com/vkurup/status/4533018776">went for a run</a> recently
and I can now say with certainty that this is my dream house. That paved
running trail which I had been so ambivalent about eventually ends at a
main road. And that's where I thought it ended. On Thursday, I crossed the
road and found a little mowed path which takes you to the local high
school. And then you take a right and WOW! A huge forest with a 10 foot
wide rock and dirt trail opens up in front of you. I started down this
trail, expecting it to end at someone's private property, but it kept going
and going and going. It ran next to a bubbling stream with water clear
enough to see the river's bottom. There were countless little paths snaking
away from the main one. I just kept running and it just got more and more
beautiful. I wish I had brought my camera. It felt like a religious
experience. I couldn't believe that this beautiful, seemingly endless trail
- the type of trail that I would have driven miles to get to in the past -
was in my backyard. I ended up running 11 miles, which is longer than I
have run since moving to North Carolina. I can't wait to run there
again. This is just another example of how I am the luckiest man in the
world. I always wanted to live in a house near trails like this, but didn't
think it was possible, so I settled for a little "running trail". Just my
luck, it turns out to be the trail of my dreams :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
