<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>food on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in food on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 20:51:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mala&#39;s Bolognese</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/16/malas-bolognese/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 20:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/16/malas-bolognese/</guid>
      <description>Mala&amp;#39;s Bolognese  I have just had the most amazing Italian meal that I&amp;rsquo;ve had outside of Roberto&amp;rsquo;s in the Bronx. Mala made fresh homemade Pappardelle and a Bolognese sauce that she just learned at Revolution&amp;rsquo;s cooking class. The thing is, she made this yesterday, and I just tried it today as leftovers and it was still amazing. This sure is going to make going lo-carb impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our weight loss regimen</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/13/our-weight-loss-regimen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 14:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/13/our-weight-loss-regimen/</guid>
      <description>After writing yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post about how Mala and I have been losing so much weight over the past 8 months, I thought I should post a small sampling of the food that Mala has made for us in that time. Yes, I am a lucky, lucky man.
   Red Wine Pot Roast   Brisket Sandwich             Salad   Steak             Valentine&#39;s Brownies   Beer Can Chicken             Homemade Pizza   Homemade Pizza             Dulce de leche cupcakes   Flank Steak             Steak, aligot, broccoli and red wine   Homemade fried chicken             Beatty&#39;s chocolate cake   Peanut butter pie             Aligot (mashed potatoes with cheese)   Fried chicken             Triple Chocolate Mousse Cake   Triple Chocolate Mousse Cake             Strawberry Shortcake   Curious George Cake             Elmo Cupcakes   French Silk Pie             French Silk Pie   Hot Dogs and Flank Steak (my only contribution to this page)            Hungry yet?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louie and Ernie&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/04/louie-and-ernies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/04/louie-and-ernies/</guid>
      <description>Louie and Ernie&amp;#39;s Pizza  We treated ourselves to our favorite New York Pizza today - Louie and Ernie&amp;rsquo;s. In my mind, it&amp;rsquo;s the perfect pizza. The thin crust is crispy on the bottom, and chewy on the top. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of cheese and the sauce has some flavor. The only problem with this place is that it&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near public transportation and they don&amp;rsquo;t deliver. It&amp;rsquo;s probably a good thing though, or we&amp;rsquo;d be eating this ALL the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restaurant Review: BLT Fish Shack</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/restaurant-review-blt-fish-shack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/restaurant-review-blt-fish-shack/</guid>
      <description>It looks like a fish shack, but the service is much more attentive. We had clam chowder and crabcakes as appetizers, then the fish &amp;amp; chips and BLT tuna sandwich as entrees. The tuna was seared just on the edges. It was mixed with bacon, hard-boiled eggs, and avocado on fresh chewy bread. Mala says, &amp;ldquo;Best Tuna Fish sandwich ever,&amp;rdquo; and I can&amp;rsquo;t argue. All of the fried stuff was delicious and not too greasy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mmmmm Bacon...</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/12/mmmmm-bacon.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/12/mmmmm-bacon.../</guid>
      <description>Now this is a good idea for a blog.
 ONE BACON RECIPE PER DAY, EVERY DAY, FOREVER
 I think this one is my favorite so far.
found on A Full Belly</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Meals under $10</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/31/100-meals-under-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/31/100-meals-under-10/</guid>
      <description>The Daily News has found 100 restaurants under $10 (not including tip or drinks) in NYC. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to 9 of them - El Paso Taqueria, Carl&amp;rsquo;s (aweome cheesesteaks!), Blue 9, The Burger Joint, Sassy&amp;rsquo;s Sliders, Crif Dogs, Papaya King (of course), Mandler&amp;rsquo;s and Pomme Frites.
Looks like we have some eating to do!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>