<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>free on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/free/</link>
    <description>Recent content in free on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/free/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Telephone Service</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/25/free-telephone-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/25/free-telephone-service/</guid>
      <description>Has anyone tried any of the Internet phone services? Skype looks very interesting. Nice interface, lots of platforms, high praise from people I trust, and most importantly, it&amp;rsquo;s FREE! Well, as long as the person you&amp;rsquo;re calling also has Skype. If you want to call a real phone, you buy credits (which seem pretty cheap). Lemme know if any of you try it out&amp;hellip;
Comments from old site Skype is cool</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Music Download</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/05/legal-music-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/05/legal-music-download/</guid>
      <description>Legal Music Downloads and some great background information. I&amp;rsquo;m gonna give iRATE a try.
Comments from old site Directory of Legal Music Downloads
 Check out this site for a comprehensive listing of legal music download sites.
Directory of Legal Music Downloads Joel Erenberg 2004-04-11 19:18:06</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t get sued</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/30/dont-get-sued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/30/dont-get-sued/</guid>
      <description>The topic of music sharing and its legality came up during our annual cousins trip in Seattle. Here&amp;rsquo;s an important article on How Not to Get Sued by the RIAA. The most important thing is the last line in the article:
 Join EFF and support our efforts to protect file-sharing.
 I don&amp;rsquo;t use P2P music-sharing apps anymore. While I love the idea of being able to access an unending library of music, I don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of getting it for free.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>