<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: instrospection | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/instrospection/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-08T22:40:46-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing paralysis]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/15/writing-paralysis"/>
    <updated>2013-01-15T14:45:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/15/writing-paralysis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think twitter and facebook stunt my writing. The more that I read
tweets, the more self-conscious I get when I write. Not that my
writing is all that original, but I still feel that it is something
that comes from me. I worry so much about presenting ideas of others
as my own without even remembering that I had seen the ideas before.
In the old days, the things that I read were long form. Books,
articles, maybe blog posts. They each left an impression on me, maybe
good, maybe bad, but I had a sense where they were coming from. When I
wrote I could reliably say where the inspiration for my idea had come
from. Now with twitter, I see all these ideas and thoughts, some of
which are interesting, but few of which leave a lasting impression on
me. So now I have this fear that the things that I am considering my
own ideas are actually the ideas of others, improperly attributed. Of
course, that's silly. No idea is original, but it's just serious
enough to stifle my writing. Because, as a writer, I am the
scaredy-cat of all scaredy-cats and any criticism of my writing bites
deep to the heart. I also know that this is something that I just need
to get over. You cannot express ideas without inviting criticism.
I also don't just want to let criticism fall off me. I want to learn
from critics. But saying all that doesn't necessarily make it any
easier. Even writing this post, I feel like a fraud. I've said that
I'm a writer a couple times up there, but what evidence do I have to
support that claim? Most of my blog posts are so simple or technical
or repetitive. Nothing that would strike me as an 'original idea'.
This whole post makes it seem like I am more important or better than
I really am.</p>

<p>What is my point with all this? I want to be able to write. I know
that there are people out there who could benefit from things in my
brain (maybe not a lot). I know that there are people out there who
can help me (in ways that I can't even expect). So, I want to write
and I want it to be freely flowing and I don't want to force myself to
feel that what I am writing is useful or authoritative or perfect. I
apologize to you, Vinod, my biggest critic. I know that you are
cringing inside because you're thinking that anyone who reads this
will think that you are so full of yourself for even considering
yourself a writer. But, this is my first step in letting my guard down
to get this blog flowing. Because I do believe that writing is healthy
and will make me a better person.</p>

<p>In addition to committing to blogging more frequently, I'm also going
to try a twitter hiatus for a week and see what happens.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
