<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: parenting | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/parenting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-09-22T21:30:24-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kids and Computers]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/15/kids-and-computers"/>
    <updated>2011-08-15T21:26:31-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/15/kids-and-computers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm sure it's probably too early to worry about this, but I often
wonder about the best way to introduce Kavi and Anika to
computers. 'Introduce' isn't the right word because even Anika has
more experience with computers than I did at that age. So far, though,
computers are something that Daddy and Mommy use to do work, not
things that are for them. We'll show them a Sesame Street video on
YouTube or family pictures on Facebook, but they don't spend any
significant amount of time on it. They're easily entertained without
computers. I know that will change as they get older, but for now at
least, they prefer their toys and their imagination to TV or
computers. Even at their young age, that is rare.</p>

<p>The dilemma is that I <strong>do</strong> want them to learn about technology and learn
how to use it in their lives without being controlled by it. I don't
see anything wrong with exposing them to things like computers, iPads,
YouTube, etc., as long as it is monitored. I just want it to be a
healthy portion of their leisure time, not all of it. So many
children's entertainment options are spoon-fed propaganda. They are
meant to be passively enjoyed, and the child just sits and absorbs
it. The source of the content is often questionable. Advertisers for
big corporations or government trying to get their message to kids
either overtly or subtly.</p>

<p>I like my childhood experience. My first major exposure to computers
was an Apple IIe. There was nothing organized about it. I spent a
large majority of my time playing games, but those were just the
gateway drugs to get me to realize that there was much more power in
those machines. The entire experience was about tinkering. Trying
to figure out how it worked, how to make it work for me, how I could
make it do things. The most exciting days in my childhood were the
days that the inCider magazine arrived with pages of DOS code listings
in the back. Retyping those code listings, making alterations, trying
to figure out how things worked... that is much more healthy than just
watching a video over and over again. I, of course, was much older
than Kavi is now, so I'm not too worried. I just don't want them to
get addicted to a certain concept of what technology is for, before
they have the skills to really take advantage of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parenting Highs and Lows]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/03/03/parenting-highs-and-lows"/>
    <updated>2011-03-03T21:11:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/03/03/parenting-highs-and-lows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Written a few weeks ago</em></p>

<p>I came home late today, so Anika and Kavi had already eaten dinner and
taken their baths. As I drove down the driveway, I could see Kavi's
excited little head poking over the upstairs windowsill. I parked the
car and opened the door into the house. I was immediately met a voice
screaming, "Daddy, Daddy!" with pure joy in his voice. He ran down the
stairs and gave me a huge hug. I just love that. There is nothing
better than coming home to such a loving family. It makes all the
stress and BS at work melt away.</p>

<p>Then I followed him upstairs and Anika ran over and gave me a big hug
and then started "Dancing on the diaper pad!" (Will have to upload a
video of that someday). I watched for a few moments and then got up to
go change my clothes. She started to get upset, so I held her hand and
walked her down the hallway with me. That's another thing I
love. Seeing this sweet little girl with her arm extended as high as
she can possibly reach to hold my hand, walking with me, like I'm the
most important person in the world, just makes my heart melt. I don't
know what I've done to deserve such love and admiration. I just hope
that I can live up to their expectations.</p>

<p>Kavi had a scary episode on Superbowl Sunday. We were just getting
ready to go next door for the Superbowl party. I was upstairs with
Anika and she had just been getting upset about how she wanted to go
downstairs. Kavi and Mommy were downstairs, but they were coming
upstairs, so I wanted Anika to stay up here, rather than go down and
then come up again. I picked her up and held her in my arms to keep
her happy. I heard Kavi start coming up the stairs, and normally I
would have opened the baby-gate for him, but this time I didn't want
Anika to see me opening the gate, because I thought she'd start
getting upset again, wanting to go downstairs. Instead, I just stood a
few feet away from the gate, telling Anika, "See, Kavi's coming
upstairs." He's opened the gate hundreds of times and has never had
any trouble doing it. This time, however, he opened the gate, lost his
balance and the gate started swinging open over the stairs. He held on
to the gate and swung with it. He was hanging on tightly and I could
see his feet dangling, trying to find a foothold on a step, but since
the gate had swung open over the stairs, he was too high to reach the
stairs. I vividly saw the fear in his huge eyes and ran to the gate,
but by the time I got there, the gate had given way and he was
tumbling down the stairs.</p>

<p>Time stopped.</p>

<p>He screamed with the most terrified scream that I've ever heard. He
initially landed on his feet in the middle of the staircase, but the
momentum made him fly down the stairs and his head banged against the
far wall. The gate followed close behind and landed on top of
him. Anika started screaming in my arms. She instinctively knew that
something bad had happened. I initially bent over to put her down at
the top of the stairs and then quickly reconsidered, knowing that she
would want to come down with me and might fall in the process. I
picked her back up and headed down the stairs as Mala raced up from
the kitchen. I gave Anika to Mala as I grabbed Kavi and looked him
over. He had a tiny scrape on his head, but no bleeding. He seemed to
be complaining most about pain in his left arm and shoulder. It
reassured me a bit, because I was worried about his head, but then I
got worried that maybe he had broken his arm or something. We held him
for a while and put ice on his head and shoulders. Anika was tearful
watching all of this but calmed down quickly. Then I went upstairs to
fix the gate.</p>

<p>Within a few minutes he was bouncing around without any sign that he
had fallen. I was so relieved, but I still have visions of his eyes
being full of fear as he was hanging from that swinging gate. I know
how lucky I am and how lucky we have been, in general. I also know
that there will be other scary moments in the future - it's a part of
life. Weathering this admittedly minor mishap took all the strength
and fortitude that I could muster. How do people do it? How do people
withstand bad things happening to their kids? I just don't know how
people can take so much potential pain.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First full phone conversation with Kavi]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/11/06/first-full-phone-conversation-with-kavi"/>
    <updated>2010-11-06T21:53:36-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/11/06/first-full-phone-conversation-with-kavi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had my first full phone conversation with Kavi today. I was about to
leave work, so I called home to let Mala know that I was on my way
home. (For the second time... I got called back to help in the ER on
my first attempt, but that's another story). When the phone rang, Kavi
picked up the phone. "Hi Daddy, when are you coming home?" I told him
that I was leaving now and that I'd be home in half an hour. "OK
Daddy. Bye!" <em>Click</em></p>

<p>Hopefully, he gave the message to Mala :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PlayDoh]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/07/15/playdoh"/>
    <updated>2010-07-15T20:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/07/15/playdoh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Kavi's bedroom - 8PM</h4>

<p>DADDY and KAVI are lying next to each other in KAVI's bed doing their
bedtime ritual. They have finished singing a song and are recapping the
day.</p>

<p>DADDY: Did you play with playdoh today?</p>

<p>KAVI: No.</p>

<p>DADDY: Are you sure? Did you play with playdoh this morning before going to
the Puffin room?</p>

<p>(KAVI thinks)</p>

<p>KAVI: Yes. I did. Why did I play with playdoh?</p>

<p>DADDY: Because you wanted to. You asked me if you could play with it.</p>

<p>KAVI: Why did I want to play with the playdoh?</p>

<p>DADDY: I don't know.</p>

<p>KAVI: Why you don't know?</p>

<p>DADDY: Because. I can't answer that question.</p>

<p>KAVI: Why you can't answer that question?</p>

<p>DADDY: It's a question of your motivation, KAVI. I can speculate about why
you wanted to play with the playdoh, but I can't tell you why you wanted
to.</p>

<p>(pause)</p>

<p>KAVI: Why?</p>

<p>DADDY: I can tell you what I want, but I can't tell you what you want.</p>

<p>KAVI: What do you want DADDY?</p>

<p>(DADDY takes a deep breath)</p>

<p>DADDY: A lot of things. I want you to grow up to be a strong, intelligent,
loving, happy boy. I want Anika to grow up to be a strong, intelligent,
loving, happy girl. I want Mommy to be able to do what she wants in life. I
want all of us to travel, spend time with family, and enjoy the world. That's
what I want.</p>

<p>KAVI: oh.</p>

<p>DADDY: What do you want?</p>

<p>KAVI: Playdoh.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Growing up too fast]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2009/09/26/growing-up-too-fast"/>
    <updated>2009-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2009/09/26/growing-up-too-fast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love watching Kavi's expressions. We took the kids to the <a href="http://www.ncmls.org/">Museum of Life
and Science</a> for a birthday party today. He's been
there plenty of times, mostly with Mala. I've been there a few times with
him. It's one of his (and I guess every kid's) favorite places. Each time
we go, it's a vastly different experience. Everything seems new to him. His
eyes light up with wonder and amazement at the exhibits.</p>

<p>We were late for the party, so Mala took Anika ahead of us while Kavi
dawdled in the front exhibits. Ahead of us was a large skeleton of a
dinosaur's head. I know that he has seen this before, but, it was as if
he'd noticed it for the first time today. And it was scary. Not too scary,
mind you. He wasn't crying or anything. He just was very cautious about
getting too close to it. But, there was no way to avoid it, since the party
room (with the cake!) was just past the dinosaur. He held my hand tightly
and asked what it was. I told him and he repeated it, "Dinosaur?". His eyes
were wide open, but focused on the T-Rex's head. His right hand clenched my
left and when I tried to walk past it, he pulled me back. Still no crying
or complaining, just ... concern. So I took my time and talked to him about
the dinosaur and the other exhibits nearby. Eventually, he mustered up the
courage to walk around the back of the dinosaur and towards the party
room. Later, after the cake and festivities, we made our way back to the
other exhibits. This time, he pointed out the dinosaur, still in a
concerned voice, but made no effort to shy away or slow down. Now, he
noticed other things that he had missed before -- cool astronauts uniforms
and a glass elevator slowly ascending. When he saw each of these things,
his face turned into the embodiment of wonder. Eyes wide open, jaw slightly
ajar. I love seeing him experience life like this, so fully.</p>

<p>I write this because I know that I'm otherwise going to forget them. I had
the distinct feeling this afternoon, while watching him, that he was
growing up in front of my eyes. That these expressions of wonderment would
soon be replaced by the apathy of young adulthood. I know, I know... he's
only 2, but everyone keeps telling me that he will be grown and with kids
of his own before I know it! I hope not and if so, I hope not <em>too soon</em>. I
want to make sure that I remember these moments, simply for their own sake.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
