<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: business | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/business/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-09T08:22:17-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anything You Want Review]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/07/04/anything-you-want-review"/>
    <updated>2011-07-04T21:12:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/07/04/anything-you-want-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://t.co/rdADtHa"><img class="inset right" src="http://ws.assoc-amazon.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&Format=_SL160_&ASIN=1936719118&MarketPlace=US&ID=AsinImage&WS=1&tag=vinodkurupshomep&ServiceVersion=20070822" ></a>
<img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=&l=as2&o=1&a=1936719118&camp=217145&creative=399373" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></p>

<p>I don't know why I keep reading books about entrepreneurship. I like
the idea of building a business, having passion for something, and
most importantly, living life on your own terms. I just <a href="/blog/2010/11/07/growing-a-business">don't think
I'm cut out for it</a>. But see if
that will stop me from devouring <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com">Hacker
News</a>, <a href="http://mixergy.com">startup
podcasts</a> and books like <a href="http://sivers.org">Derek Sivers'</a> <a href="http://t.co/rdADtHa">Anything
You
Want</a>.</p>

<p>Derek was a musician who started selling his own CDs online in the
days before Paypal. He agreed to help a friend by selling his friend's
CDs as well, and eventually CD Baby was born. He built it into a
successful business and sold it for $22 million. This book is a set of
stories of how that happened. An <a href="http://onstartups.com/tabid/3339/bid/57644/Anything-You-Want-21-Inspiring-Ideas-From-Derek-Sivers.aspx">excellent bullet point
summary</a>
of the book is available. This short book was filled with interesting
advice and stories, but here's my main takeaways.</p>

<h3>Focus on helping people</h3>

<p>It would seem like the way to build a successful business would be to
focus on things like profits, or markets, or costs, but Derek says to
ignore all that and focus on helping people. He started by helping out
a fellow musician, and he made sure that every decision he made was in
the name of helping independent musicians. If big labels asked to be
added to CD Baby, he said no. If people recommended placing ads on his
site, he said no. If a business offered some kind of big money
partnership which required him to change the way he ran his business,
he said no. Find someone you can help and provide enough value to that
person to make them happy to pay you for the help and you will have a
successful business.</p>

<h3>Make something perfect, not big</h3>

<blockquote><p>So, I thought that by taking an unrealistically utopian approach, I could keep the business from growing too much. Instead of trying to make it big, I was going to make it small. It was the opposite of ambition, so I had to think in a way that was the opposite of ambitious.</p>

<p>The key point is that I wasn't trying to make a big business. I was just daydreaming about how one little thing would look in a perfect world.</p></blockquote>

<p>Derek actively tried to keep his business from growing. At some point,
he was making enough money that he felt the growth of the business
would only create more headaches for him. Instead of trying to get
more business, he would try to make his current business
perfect. Focus on ways to make the business run the way you want the
world to work. Build your utopia. If you are always focused on growing
the business, you eventually have to make compromises between what
your current customers want and what "potential" customers want. But,
if your current customers are the ones who you're passionate about
serving, then making their experience even better will paradoxically
bring growth, while also making your life as a business owner more
fulfilling.</p>

<h3>This book is not about business</h3>

<blockquote><p>It's important to know in advance, to make sure you're staying focused on what's honestly important to you, instead of doing what others think you should.</p></blockquote>

<p>It's really a book about life. Focus on helping people and good things
will happen to you. Figure out what makes you tick, what makes you
happy, and what drains you. Adjust your life to give you more time to
do what makes you happy and stop doing the things that drain
you. Derek's rule about this is "HELL, YEAH!" or "no". If someone
offers you an opportunity and you don't say "HELL, YEAH!", then say
"no". Don't go halfway. Do things that you love. (His actual rule is a
little more 'explicit', as he describes in this
<a href="http://mixergy.com/derek-sivers-blog-interview/">podcast</a>)</p>

<h3>A few other quotes that I loved</h3>

<br>


<h5>Getting things done isn't the only goal</h5>

<blockquote><p>[Other people] assume the only reason we do anything is to get it done, and doing it yourself is not the most efficient way. But that's forgetting about the joy of learning and doing.</p></blockquote>

<h5>Know thyself</h5>

<blockquote><p>Just pay close attention to what excites you and what drains you. Pay close attention to when you're being the real you and when you're trying to impress the invisible jury.</p></blockquote>

<h5>Unexpected twist</h5>

<blockquote><p>So I considered firing everyone and hiring a whole new crew. ... I never saw or spoke to my employees again. Never saw the office again.</p></blockquote>

<p>Wasn't expecting to read that. Thought that he would find a way to
patch things up, but stuff like this happens in the real world.</p>

<h3>How to do customer service</h3>

<p>This wasn't from the book, but was in a <a href="http://mixergy.com/derek-sivers-blog-interview/">great Mixergy
interview</a> that I
heard after finishing the book. He describes his customer service
philosophy as the <strong>Mick Jagger philosophy</strong>. Pretend that every customer
service request you get is from Mick Jagger. (Assuming your company is
in the music business). If someone emails you a request about how they
can't access a PDF file on your site, that might seem like an annoying
complaint. But if you pretend that it's coming from Mick Jagger, you'd
respond "Wow, thanks for emailing me. Here, let me just get that PDF
for you and attach it to this email. Again, please let me know if
there's anything else I can do for you!" And if that is heartfelt,
customers will love you.</p>

<h3>Bottom line</h3>

<p>I enjoyed this book. It's a quick read, it's cheap (I read the Kindle
version on my Android tablet for $7.99) and it's inspirational. I
<a href="http://t.co/rdADtHa">recommend it</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Growing a Business]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/11/07/growing-a-business"/>
    <updated>2010-11-07T20:31:19-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/11/07/growing-a-business</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read this book in 2005, but never posted this review. So here it
is...</p>

<h2><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0671671642?ie=UTF8&tag=vinodkurupshomep&linkCode=as2&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=0671671642">Growing a Business</a> by Paul Hawken</h2>

<p>This is an honest and practical guide to running a business. I don't
remember where I first heard about this book. Maybe <a href="http://pinds.com">Lars</a>?</p>

<p>It was written in 1987. Hawken talks about building a business. It's
often portrayed as a heroic or glamorous endeavor, but really it's
not. It's a lot of hard work, but also a lot of common sense. He spends a
chapter talking about a quality that you need to be successful in your own
business. He calls it Tradeskill.</p>

<p>It's like intuition, for business. He says its something you can't acquire
easily, except perhaps in childhood. People that were drawn into business
activities at a young age have it. Those that weren't, don't. And no amount
of book-smarts can make up for the lack of Tradeskill. If you're not
comfortable haggling in a flea market, you should think twice about going
into business. Instead, he recommends dipping your feet in the water,
without starting a business yourself. Take a part time job in a business
that you're interested in and try to take on as many roles as possible in
that business.</p>

<p>Another theme in his book is the wisdom of growing slowly. Having too much
money while starting a business is worse than no having enough. It's
something I read a lot now (Arsdigita, Paul Graham, 37Signals), but it's
interesting to see it written way back when as well.</p>

<h3>Things I learned from this book</h3>

<h2>It's probably not for me</h2>

<p>Starting your own business is not for everyone. It takes a temperament that
isn't easily learned. I don't think I have Tradeskill. I'm not going to let
that stop me from learning about business, but I'm going to be a little
more thorough in my planning and preparation if I ever do it.</p>

<h2>The 5-15 report is a good idea</h2>

<p>He mentions something called a 5-15 report. it's a report that every
employee in a company should have to write <strong>every</strong> week. It should take
less than 15 minutes to write and less than 5 minutes to read. Part I is a
progress report for the week, Part II is a report on the morale of the
department and Part III is one idea to make the company better. I like the
idea of a weekly low-commitment progress report.</p>

<h2>Overstaffing is the root of all evil</h2>

<p>A major problem of big business is over-staffing. Once an employee
learns that their work is redundant, or requires little effort, they
realize their job is expendable and that they must spend all their
time preserving their job - through hijacking credit, office politics,
etc. The basic result is that <strong>people hoard information</strong>. Information
that, if freely disseminated, would allow the company to function
better. If I have useful information that other employees don't have,
then I am valuable. Understaffed companies (start-ups) work in the
opposite way. I have enough work as it is, so I'm happy to share
information with you, because perhaps it will allow you to help me out
with my workload. The company becomes more efficient. I see this
effect of over-staffing where I work (although I didn't recognize it
as such until reading this book)</p>

<h3>random quotes / concepts from the book</h3>

<p>Flat management/employee structures are good. Trust the people you work with and
give them wide latitude.</p>

<p>Problems are opportunities - dive into them.</p>

<p>"A good business has interesting problems. A bad business has boring ones." (p. 39)</p>

<p>Have a partner. You shouldn't ever think of going it alone.</p>

<p>"Being in business is not about making money. It is a way to become who you are." (p. 19)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
