<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hospitalist on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/hospitalist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hospitalist on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 05:35:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/hospitalist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SHM 2011</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/13/shm-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 05:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/13/shm-2011/</guid>
      <description>Here are some (unorganized) thoughts about my experience at the Society of Hospital Medicine (SHM) 2011 conference in Dallas, TX.
Opening Plenary The initial presentation dissected the SHM Annual Compensation survey, discussing regional variations in pay and work effort over time. I understand the importance of that stuff, but ever since I got my first $638.36 paycheck as an intern, money hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an issue for me.
The second talk was by Bob Kocher, an Obama insider during the recent healthcare reformd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primary Care Doctors</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/06/primary-care-doctors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/06/primary-care-doctors/</guid>
      <description>I used to be a primary care physician, but switched to being a hospitalist in 2007. I loved parts about being a PCP, namely the relationship that I developed with the patient over many years. I miss that. I think PCPs offer huge value in providing low cost, quality care, especially if they can stay engaged throughout the hospitalization process. Atul Gawande recently wrote a powerful article on the Hospice system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospitalist Notes 1</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/29/hospitalist-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/29/hospitalist-notes-1/</guid>
      <description>My last night shift was a little less busy than most, so I forced myself to pick something about each patient I admitted and look it up. I tend to do this anyway, but I never keep notes or write about it. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I wrote about that night:
Does Buspar (buspirone) need to be tapered? Answer: No. The full report on Micromedex was a little conflicting, because it stated that there may be some withdrawal symptoms from Buspar, but this quote in the same profile suggests otherwise:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m alive</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/08/02/im-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/08/02/im-alive/</guid>
      <description>OK, I know it&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since I updated this blog, but rest assured that I&amp;rsquo;m still alive and kicking. The observant among you will notice that the design of the blog has changed. The even more observant will notice that huge swaths of content are now missing. Things like my photo albums, my running log, old comments, and Kavi&amp;rsquo;s little site are now gone. They may make a reappearance someday, especially if I get prodded sufficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospitalist Handbook</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/22/hospitalist-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/22/hospitalist-handbook/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a clear, concise handbook for Hospitalist Medicine, check out the UCSF Hospitalist Handbook, available free online. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s up-to-date (the copyright notice states 2002), but it still seems relevant and useful. And I&amp;rsquo;m not just saying that because my cousin Deepu Nair wrote the Night Calls section.
Comments from old site You read my mind
 Vin you read my mind I have been waiting for a handbook on hospitalist medicine, thank you so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night shifts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/09/14/night-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/09/14/night-shifts/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be here in Green Bay for a little while longer, probably until Thanksgiving. So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working mostly night shifts, bringing back vivid memories of &amp;lsquo;night float&amp;rsquo; during residency. Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying it. Everyone&amp;rsquo;s really nice and welcoming. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a change from residency when you&amp;rsquo;re the low man on the totem pole. The patient population is more primary care oriented. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen one transplant patient so far, wheras I used to see almost one-a-day in residency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to the homeland!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/08/06/going-to-the-homeland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/08/06/going-to-the-homeland/</guid>
      <description>I found out recently that I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending 3 weeks (maybe longer) in Green Bay, WI. I&amp;rsquo;ll be working as a hospitalist at St. Vincent&amp;rsquo;s Hospital (Prevea HealthCare). It&amp;rsquo;s a 580 bed hospital with 40 ICU beds and I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing 12 hour shifts - mostly day shifts, but a couple nights. It should be fun! I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to being back in Wisconsin, especially Green Bay, for football season. Go PACKERS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/15/waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/15/waiting/</guid>
      <description>Still waiting to hear where my first assignment will be. Possibilities include a VA Hospital in Maine, a hospitalist practice in Green Bay, WI, a practice in Racine, WI, or an outpatient practice in Minnesota. Details to follow&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>