<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gladwell on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/gladwell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gladwell on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/gladwell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gladwell blogs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/gladwell-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/gladwell-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Sorry for two posts about Gladwell in one day, but I just found out that Gladwell has started a blog. Looks like he started the day after his Columbia speech which is interesting because he put some blame on the internet for our society&amp;rsquo;s bias towards Picasso. Maybe he&amp;rsquo;s trying to test his theories :-)
Gladwell is one of most interesting writers I have read and is as adept a speaker as he is a writer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picasso vs Cézanne</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/24/picasso-vs-c%C3%A9zanne/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/24/picasso-vs-c%C3%A9zanne/</guid>
      <description>We saw Malcolm Gladwell talk at Columbia on Tuesday. He&amp;rsquo;s the author of Blink and The Tipping Point and he&amp;rsquo;s a staff writer at the New Yorker. He spoke about different types of genius. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to recreate his main points from memory, so I apologize in advance if I&amp;rsquo;ve remembered things incorrectly.
His talk was about the artists Picasso and Cézanne. An economist named David Galenson did an analysis of the market value of paintings of these great artists and concluded that they represented two distinct types of genius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are SUVs safe?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/10/are-suvs-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/10/are-suvs-safe/</guid>
      <description>Interesting article about SUV safety. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quote:
 Most of us think that S.U.V.s are much safer than sports cars. If you asked the young parents of America whether they would rather strap their infant child in the back seat of the TrailBlazer or the passenger seat of the Boxster, they would choose the TrailBlazer. We feel that way because in the TrailBlazer our chances of surviving a collision with a hypothetical tractor-trailer in the other lane are greater than they are in the Porsche.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>