<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>podcasts on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/podcasts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in podcasts on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 21:51:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/podcasts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Doggcatcher</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/23/doggcatcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 21:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/23/doggcatcher/</guid>
      <description>I talked yesterday about how I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the Google Listen podcast client. I did a little Googling and found a nice solution (somewhat ironic, in an Alanis Morrissette kinda way): Doggcatcher. It costs $6.99 and I spent an extra $3.99 for Presto Sound Library which allows you to speed up the podcasts a little. Sorry Merlin! (He hates when people do this). Doggcatcher seems to do everything I mentioned as requirements in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Listen doesn&#39;t rock</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/22/google-listen-doesnt-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 20:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/22/google-listen-doesnt-rock/</guid>
      <description>In the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to podcasts, I&amp;rsquo;ve only found 2 podcast clients that I&amp;rsquo;ve really liked: iTunes (back around 2005-2007) and a bash script that I wrote which simply copied files downloaded by podget onto my iPod nano. Google Listen on my Droid X (Android 2.2) is tolerable, but only barely. I think my requirements are simple. I want to put in URLs and have the client get all the podcasts in that URL and stick them in a queue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 by 5</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/21/5-by-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 20:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/21/5-by-5/</guid>
      <description>My commute to work is 25 minutes each way, so I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a podcast to listen to. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of the 43folders website for years and Merlin Mann recently started a podcast called Back To Work with Dan Benjamin. Dan Benjamin, it turns out, is the founder of a network called 5by5, which he says has been called &amp;ldquo;NPR for geeks&amp;rdquo;. The shows I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to have all been sharp and entertaining so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Shorts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/01/29/selected-shorts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/01/29/selected-shorts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to thank Deepu for giving me a list of some cool podcasts to check out. My commute is about 30 minutes each way, and listening to podcasts I enjoy helps keep me sane. I added the Moth Podcast, NPR Selected Shorts, and RadioLab to my podcast list and have been enjoying all of them. NPR Shorts is my favorite of the bunch. It&amp;rsquo;s usually 2 short stories being read live somewhere in NYC.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>