<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>new-york-city on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/new-york-city/</link>
    <description>Recent content in new-york-city on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/new-york-city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Louie and Ernie&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/04/louie-and-ernies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/05/04/louie-and-ernies/</guid>
      <description>Louie and Ernie&amp;#39;s Pizza  We treated ourselves to our favorite New York Pizza today - Louie and Ernie&amp;rsquo;s. In my mind, it&amp;rsquo;s the perfect pizza. The thin crust is crispy on the bottom, and chewy on the top. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of cheese and the sauce has some flavor. The only problem with this place is that it&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near public transportation and they don&amp;rsquo;t deliver. It&amp;rsquo;s probably a good thing though, or we&amp;rsquo;d be eating this ALL the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTA sucks</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/mta-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/mta-sucks/</guid>
      <description>I had the commute from hell this morning. The 4 train went &amp;ldquo;Out of service&amp;rdquo; at 149th street, so we all got off and crowded onto the other nearly-full 4 train going downtown. They closed the doors for a minute, then opened the doors and said &amp;lsquo;This 4 is out of service&amp;rsquo;. So now there are 2 train-fulls of people trying to get to the 5 train downstairs. It was chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restaurant Review: BLT Fish Shack</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/restaurant-review-blt-fish-shack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/29/restaurant-review-blt-fish-shack/</guid>
      <description>It looks like a fish shack, but the service is much more attentive. We had clam chowder and crabcakes as appetizers, then the fish &amp;amp; chips and BLT tuna sandwich as entrees. The tuna was seared just on the edges. It was mixed with bacon, hard-boiled eggs, and avocado on fresh chewy bread. Mala says, &amp;ldquo;Best Tuna Fish sandwich ever,&amp;rdquo; and I can&amp;rsquo;t argue. All of the fried stuff was delicious and not too greasy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Marathon Eve</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/05/new-york-marathon-eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/05/new-york-marathon-eve/</guid>
      <description>The marathon is tomorrow. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty nervous. I really want to break 5 hours this time. You can track me online at the NY Marathon site. I&amp;rsquo;ll be runner number 27072.
UPDATE 2005-11-14:
I finished in 4:28:09 (chip time). I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with my time and the whole experience. Running down 4th avenue in Brooklyn was crowded, but just breathtaking. You could see a river of people for what seemed like miles ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pics Pics Pics</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/03/23/pics-pics-pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/03/23/pics-pics-pics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning to write about my trip to India, but since I&amp;rsquo;m the biggest procastinator in the world, I have a feeling that might not happen. Suffice it to say that Mala and I had a blast visiting our families and taking in some amazing sights. Thanks to everyone there for taking such great care of us. Without further delay, go look at some photos:
 The India Trip Layover in Amsterdam We got back just in time for the last day of The Gates exhibition  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Meals under $10</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/31/100-meals-under-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/31/100-meals-under-10/</guid>
      <description>The Daily News has found 100 restaurants under $10 (not including tip or drinks) in NYC. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to 9 of them - El Paso Taqueria, Carl&amp;rsquo;s (aweome cheesesteaks!), Blue 9, The Burger Joint, Sassy&amp;rsquo;s Sliders, Crif Dogs, Papaya King (of course), Mandler&amp;rsquo;s and Pomme Frites.
Looks like we have some eating to do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let there be light!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/16/let-there-be-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/16/let-there-be-light/</guid>
      <description>The power finally came back on at around 7:20 PM tonight. I was sitting on my futon trying as hard as I could not to sweat, when I heard a loud cheer from the courtyard and saw that the lights had gone on in the apartments outside my window.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a weird couple of days. The power went out around 4:15 PM yesterday while I was looking up some labs in the preceptor&amp;rsquo;s room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/01/snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/02/01/snow/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s snowing in NYC. Really hard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>