<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: interesting | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/interesting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-30T21:57:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Literature delivered to your inbox]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox"/>
    <updated>2007-03-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://dailylit.com">DailyLit.com</a> is an interesting service that takes classic books and chops them up in to bite-sized pieces that you can read in just a few minutes. It then emails you one piece at a time until you finish the book. You can customize how often you get the emails.</p>

<p>I just finished "The Art of Money Getting", by P.T. Barnum. It has a lot of practical advice, and predates (by 100 years) a lot of what you see these days in self-help books. There are a lot of gems in here, but this is one of my favorite quotes:</p>

<blockquote><p>Strict honesty, not only lies at the foundation of all success in life (financially), but in every other respect. Uncompromising integrity of character is invaluable. It secures to its possessor a peace and joy which cannot be attained without it--which no amount of money, or houses and lands can purchase.</p></blockquote>

<p>I can't wait to figure out what I'm reading next.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beautiful mind]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/beautiful-mind"/>
    <updated>2006-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/beautiful-mind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://youtube.com/watch?v=0TibQ_1zH3U">This is one of the most amazing things I've ever seen.</a> An autistic man takes a 45 minute helicopter ride over Rome and recreates what he sees with near perfect accuracy on paper. <a href="http://xenmate.blogspot.com/2006/05/human-camera.html">More information about him</a></p>

<p>This guy's brain is structurally the same as mine, yet its capabilities make my brain seem like it's broken. It's not unreasonable to think that my brain could have the same capability if it were exposed to the proper conditions. I have no idea what those conditions are, or else I'd be able to cure autism. But seeing feats like this show me that there is so much that we don't know about our brains and their function. And that's kinda exciting.</p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>Wiltshire's remarkable talent</b></p>
<p>
This is mind blowing :)
</p>
<p>
The first message sent by telegraph (see
http://memory.loc.gov/ammem/today/may24.html ) seems an apt
description: What hath God wrought?
</p>
<p>
Thanks for pointing this out, Vinod.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Prem Thomas</span>
<span class="date">2006-10-03 13:53:48</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking History is history]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/08/04/talking-history-is-history"/>
    <updated>2006-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/08/04/talking-history-is-history</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of my favorite podcasts is going on hiatus. (A <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Podcast">podcast</a> is basically a fancy word for a radio show that you can download to your MP3 player.) <a href="http://talkinghistory.oah.org/">Talking History</a> is produced by the Organization of American Historians and because of budget problems, they cutting funding for Talking History.</p>

<p>The host Brian LeBeau is the epitome of a great interviewer. He mostly stays in the background, giving the stage to the historian, but when he asks a question, you immediately feel like it's a question that you would want to ask. He makes interviewing seem simple. It's clear that not only has he read the work of the historian he's interviewing, he understands the impact of their work. But most of all, the show is great because of the content. They choose great topics with great authors and historians. If you have any interest in history, go back and listen to their <a href="http://talkinghistory.oah.org/arch2006.html">shows for the past couple years</a> (which will remain up despite the hiatus). Hope the hiatus is short...</p>

<p>(Don't forget to <a href="https://www.oah.org/giving/index.html#Anchor-11176">donate to their cause</a> if you enjoy the content as much as I do)</p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>History and more</b></p>
<p>
While Talking History takes its hiatus, you might check out the
Teaching Company ( http://www.teach12.com/teach12.asp?ai=16281 ). They
scout out good teachers from universities across the US for lectures
on a variety of topics.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Prem Thomas</span>
<span class="date">2006-08-07 12:45:00</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="my-comment">
<p><b>I'm too cheap</b></p>
<p>
You're right Prem, the content looks enticing. But, it's a little on
the expensive side and I'm really a fan of the podcast format. Let the
audio come to me :)
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Vinod Kurup</span>
<span class="date">2006-08-09 14:05:29</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>awesome</b></p>
<p>
This is awesome!  We need more of this.  Mo' podcasts, mo' podcasts,
mo' podcasts!
</p>
<p>
It's hard to find the quality stuff, though.  The free marketplace has
been inundated.  All part of the process, I know, I know (quality will
rise to the top).  It would be cool to have a site that has a good
rating system for free podcasts.  There probably already is one or
ones like it.  Haven't seen it/them, but perhaps it can be filtered,
fine tuned.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Dave T</span>
<span class="date">2006-08-15 13:42:39</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="my-comment">
<p><b>True</b></p>
<p>
That's my problem too. Finding good stuff. There are a few sites that claim to help you (Just do a google search for 'podcast directory'), but I haven't been overwhelmed with their usefulness.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Vinod Kurup</span>
<span class="date">2006-08-24 16:09:31</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gladwell blogs]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/gladwell-blogs"/>
    <updated>2006-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/02/25/gladwell-blogs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for two posts about Gladwell in one day, but I just found out that <a href="http://gladwell.typepad.com/">Gladwell has started a blog</a>. Looks like he started the day after his Columbia speech which is interesting because he put some blame on the internet for our society's bias towards Picasso. Maybe he's trying to test his theories :-)</p>

<p>Gladwell is one of most interesting writers I have read and is as adept a speaker as he is a writer. It's funny though. If you were to grade his speaking based on some well accepted criteria, you'd say he was a poor speaker. He says "Ummm" and other interjections a lot. He goes off on tangents. There were times where he lost a word and he seemed stuck for a few seconds. He didn't know the nitty gritty details of everything he talked about. At one point he was giving an example (during a tangent) and he couldn't remember the name of the guy who Cheney shot, so he made up a name.</p>

<p>But he's a great speaker because he tells stories very very well. He has a point that he wants passionately to get across. Finally, it's obvious that he's deeply thought about what he's talking about. As a listener, you ignore the conventional shortcomings because you're immersed in his story and you want to understand what he does. I thoroughly enjoyed his presentation and I'm subscribed to his blog.</p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>hi vinod</b></p>
<p>
I found your blog,
</p>
<p>
I have no idea how to navigate around but it is fun.  I will check
this guy out.  And I looked at a lot of your wedding pictures.  You
guys have a lot to choose from- a lot of good ones.
</p>
<p>
Go Eagles :)
</p>
<p>
-Nicole
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Unregistered Visitor</span>
<span class="date">2006-03-31 15:51:44</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Picasso vs Cézanne]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/02/24/picasso-vs-cezanne"/>
    <updated>2006-02-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/02/24/picasso-vs-cezanne</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We saw <a href="http://www.cuarts.com/cu_arts_blog/2006/02/malcom_gladwell.html">Malcolm Gladwell talk at Columbia</a> on Tuesday. He's the author of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0316172324/vinodkurupshomep">Blink</a> and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0316346624/vinodkurupshomep">The Tipping Point</a> and he's a staff writer at the New Yorker. He spoke about different types of genius. I've tried to recreate his main points from memory, so I apologize in advance if I've remembered things incorrectly.</p>

<p>His talk was about the artists Picasso and Cézanne. An economist named David Galenson did an analysis of the market value of paintings of these great artists and concluded that they represented two distinct types of genius. Picasso did his greatest work in his youth and then not much of worth after that, while Cézanne did little or nothing in his youth and then produced amazing things in his fifties and sixties. He looked at other painters and they also seemed to fit into these two distinct groups - the young prodigy and old late-bloomer. Not only can they be differentiated by their ages, but also by their styles. The Picasso's have a clear direct vision that they can explain to you before they start painting. They are conceptual. They know exactly what they want their art to convey and they can execute that vision. Cézanne's can't tell you how they work or what they're trying to convey. If you follow their work over time, you don't see a clear thread, but rather a hodgepodge of experiments, one of which eventually works and propels them to fame. These quotes seem to delineate the difference.</p>

<blockquote><p>I seek in painting.
-- <em>Paul Cézanne</em></p>

<p>I don't seek; I find.
-- <em>Pablo Picasso</em></p></blockquote>

<p>Gladwell discussed Galenson's research into this phenomenon and expands it into other creative areas, bringing out some other entertaining comparisons.</p>

<table> 
<tr><th>Picasso</th><th>Cézanne</th></tr> 
<tr><td>The Eagles</td><td>Fleetwood Mac</td></tr> 
<tr><td>Apple</td><td>Dell</td></tr> 
<tr><td>GM/Ford</td><td>Toyota/Honda</td></tr> 
<tr><td>Orson Welles</td><td>Alfred Hitchcock</td></tr> 
<tr><td>(I can't remember his example here)&nbsp;&nbsp;</td><td>Mark Twain</td></tr> 
</table>


<p></p>

<p>Some of the examples were a bit contrived and the idea that all genius fits into two categories is simplistic, but Gladwell went on to make some interesting observations. The Cézanne examples blow away the myth that all genius happens in youth. That point alone satisfied me since it allows me to explain why I haven't become famous yet. There is a separate type of creative process that seems to benefit from, or even require, long hard experimentation. Gladwell's thesis is that our society is biased to favor the Picasso type genius and that the Cézanne type will no longer be able to flourish. Both, he asserts, are valuable to society.</p>

<p>Take pharmaceutical development, he says. In the old days (or even in the present day), drug development was trial and error. You'd run a bunch of compounds against a disease and see what worked. Explaining why it worked is left as a postscript, sometimes never to be answered. He mentions that to this day we don't truly understand why Tylenol works, yet it clearly has helped millions of people. In the future, and in some cases today, we'll be able to identify specific genes which are responsible for a disease. Targeting those genes will treat the disease. If two entreprenuers ask you for money and one says he's got a specific gene that he can target while the other says he's got some smart scientists who are going to create a bunch of compounds and hope for the best, most people would be more willing to fund the first startup. But, if all of our society is aimed that way, then we'll miss out on some important breakthroughs, that only a Cézanne-type effort would find.</p>

<p>It's a very interesting thesis, but I'd be concerned about solutions that purported to give support to pre-Cézanne's in the hope that a Cézanne would develop. What if a major ingredient in the development of a Cézanne is the struggle. The persistence despite failure. The ability to maintain passion over long periods of time. The ability to delay gratification, to be forced to experiment. What if we had made Cézanne comfortably wealthy in his youth. Would he have continued on his path to greatness? Would his later work have been as remarkable?</p>

<p>Without question, there is a bias towards Picasso in our society. It's basically a bias towards short term results. I'm just not sure its much different than it was historically, nor that providing support to find/grow Cézanne's would be beneficial. It might actually be harmful.</p>

<p>Here are some great links that I found along the way. Thanks to Gladwell for such a stimulating presentation (and to the Columbia Arts Initiative for presenting it free!)</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.eh.net/lists/archives/hes/may-2002/0044.php">A review of Galenson's book</a>, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0674006127/vinodkurupshomep">Painting Outside the Lines</a></li>
<li><a href="http://chronicle.uchicago.edu/020124/quantifyingart.shtml">A very concise description of Galenson's finding</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.pupress.princeton.edu/chapters/s8019.html">The first chapter of Galenson's new book</a> <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0691121095/vinodkurupshomep">Old Masters and Young Geniuses</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.nber.org/reporter/fall03/galenson.html">An original article by Galenson which summarizes his work</a>, with pretty graphs!</li>
</ul>


<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>Me too</b></p>
<p>
Guess I am a Cezanne type too :) Thanks for the post, I think they are
both great artists.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Dave Bauer</span>
<span class="date">2006-02-25 11:31:13</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>time</b></p>
<p>
You'll get there, buddy, in time.
</p>
<p>
Hey, I see you're tagging.   Party on.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Dave T</span>
<span class="date">2006-03-12 23:03:18</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>Mark Twain's Picasso</b></p>
<p>
I just heard Malcom give this same discussion to the Women President's
Organization in Boston April 25, 2008.  The author he compared Mark
Twain to was Herman Melvil.
</p>
<p>
You did a good job of putting the main points of the talk together --
something I was looking for as I am now seeking to communicate the
message back to my company.
</p>
<p>
I find it reassuring that while the world focuses on the overnite
sensations, there is great value in those of us who bloom later.
</p>
<p>
Thanks for the links.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Unregistered Visitor</span>
<span class="date">2008-04-26 17:19:03</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
