<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: brooklyn | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/brooklyn/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-08T21:26:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long Ride, Long Run]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2007/04/15/long-ride-long-run"/>
    <updated>2007-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2007/04/15/long-ride-long-run</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did something yesterday that I haven't done before. I took a ride on the subway from one end all the way to the other end. I took the D train from 205th street in the Bronx to Coney Island/Stillwell Avenue in Brooklyn, passing through Manhattan on the way. Left at 6:04 AM and arrived at 7:46 AM, just in time to make it to the start of the Brooklyn Half Marathon. It was a beautiful day to run.</p>

<p>I've only been running for a few weeks since taking a "long" time off,
so I was happy with my 2:00:50 finish.</p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>Glad to hear you're back on the bike</b></p>
<p>
so to speak!
</p>
<p>
I had a short stab at getting back into sport after a lengthy break
last month, but it didn't last too long ;)
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Mark Aufflick</span>
<span class="date">2007-04-15 23:00:09</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brooklyn Half Marathon]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/03/18/brooklyn-half-marathon"/>
    <updated>2006-03-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/03/18/brooklyn-half-marathon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was cold out there today. I was wearing a long sleeve shirt, long pants, a headband and gloves, and I was still cold. I doubted whether I'd be able to break 2 hours, like I'd hoped. A mile into the race I was sure I wouldn't be able to do it. It felt like I was just running in place. As usual though, I eventually warmed up and felt pretty good.</p>

<p>I planned to take the first 5 miles real easy and I came through in 47:28. Not bad. I wanted to do the next 5 miles in 45 minutes. I came through in 45:41. Not  bad. Finally, I wanted to really pick it up the last 5K (3.1 miles). I came through in 26:43, about 8:30 pace. Again, not bad. The last 3 miles seemed like it was all hills. Even the finish was on a hill! I finally saw the finish line, checked my watch and saw 1:59:13, and promptly took off like a crazy person.</p>

<p>Final tally: 1:59:52!</p>

<p>This is the first time I ran Brooklyn and I really liked it. We started on the boardwalk at Coney Island and ran along the beach for about 3 miles. Then, there was a long straight road stretch for about 5-6 miles and we finally finished with a few loops inside Prospect Park. They just need to flatten out some of those hills...</p>

<p>Half marathons this year:</p>

<ul>
<li>Jan 28: 2:21:30 (10:48 pace) Manhattan</li>
<li>Mar 18: 1:59:52 (9:09 pace) Brooklyn</li>
</ul>


<p>Scheduled:</p>

<ul>
<li>Jul 9: Bronx</li>
<li>Aug 27: New York City</li>
<li>Oct 1: Grete's Gallop</li>
<li>Oct 15: Staten Island</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://derekrose.com/wp/?p=864">Read more race reports at Derek Rose's blog.</a></p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>good job</b></p>
<p>
Hey, looks like you made substantial headway since Manhattan half,
that's great.  Nice race report.  And don't worry about the hills; the
more you run them, the less high they seem.  (I'm lying of course!)
that's my home training ground, so they seem like predictable friends
to me...
</p>
<p>
see you at Bronx Half I hope.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Anonymous</span>
<span class="date">2006-03-18 23:55:01</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="my-comment">
<p><b>Thanks</b></p>
<p>
Lucky you - It must be nice to train in Prospect Park. I love the
Bronx, but I haven't found a dependable course yet. I'm a mile away
from Van Cortlandt park, but it doesn't have any runner-friendly loops
like Prospect Park or Central Park. But it does have hills - I guess I
should work there a bit more, huh?
</p>
<p>
My Manhattan time is misleading because I didn't train at all for
it. I was expecting the Manhattan half to be in August like it was
last year, so I was slacking off in my running :-)
</p>
<p>
How'd you do? See ya at the Bronx!
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Vinod Kurup</span>
<span class="date">2006-03-19 08:22:50</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
