<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sysadmin on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/sysadmin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sysadmin on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 21:58:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/sysadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing wireless on eeePC</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/09/08/fixing-wireless-on-eeepc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 21:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/09/08/fixing-wireless-on-eeepc/</guid>
      <description>I have an ASUS eeePC 1000, running Ubuntu 10.10. Wireless worked flawlessly at home, which is where I use it 99% of the time. On our most recent trip, however, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t working. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect to a WPA-secured network. Here are the relevant error messages:
NetworkManager[770]: &amp;lt;warn&amp;gt; Activation (wlan0/wireless): association took too long. NetworkManager[770]: &amp;lt;warn&amp;gt; (wlan0): link timed out. NetworkManager[770]: &amp;lt;warn&amp;gt; Activation (wlan0) failed for access point (linksys) NetworkManager[770]: &amp;lt;warn&amp;gt; Activation (wlan0) failed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inotify</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/16/inotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/16/inotify/</guid>
      <description>incron seems to be a pretty neat tool. It&amp;rsquo;s cron-for-file-activities. Cron is a common unix tool that allows you to run any command at a specified time. It&amp;rsquo;s immensely useful for running anything that you want to occur on a regular basis: backups, daily reminder emails, downloading podcasts, etc. If you&amp;rsquo;ve used unix to any significant extent, you&amp;rsquo;ve used cron.
incron takes that cron metaphor and applies it to file activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pound update kills my website</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/17/pound-update-kills-my-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/17/pound-update-kills-my-website/</guid>
      <description>No one but me noticed, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, but my website was down for part of yesterday. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, refunds to paying customers are on their way :-)
What happened? I was doing my regular debian apt-get upgrade and the reverse proxy that I use, pound, got updated. The upgrade was a pretty significant one. Pound 2.0 changed the way that it expects configuration files to be formatted. Unfortunately, the Debian update didn&amp;rsquo;t mention this, so the new version of pound tried to read my old config file, got confused and shut down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editing as root in emacs</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/editing-as-root-in-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/12/20/editing-as-root-in-emacs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using emacs for 7 years and I just learned today that you can edit files as root while you&amp;rsquo;re logged into emacs as an unprivileged user. Using sudo, of course. The details are here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup strategy</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/02/backup-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/02/backup-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Badgertronics.com, borkware.com, and company went through the same ordeal that kurup.org did and MarkD has promptly published his new backup strategy. He uses rsync over SSH which, interestingly enough, is the same strategy that I came up with. Great minds must think alike.
The canonical standard for doing backups on UNIX systems is tar (short for tape archive). tar converts directories of files into a single tar archive file which you would then spit to an attached tape drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m back!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/17/im-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/17/im-back/</guid>
      <description>This site was down for the past few days due to a SNAFU with acornhosting&amp;rsquo;s upstream provider. You&amp;rsquo;d think I&amp;rsquo;d have learned to have a backup strategy in place by now, but you&amp;rsquo;d be overestimating my intelligence. Luckily, Cathy was somehow able to negotiate with her failed upstream provider to get my (and other acornhosting customers&amp;rsquo;) data back. After this episode, I promise to backup religiously and I&amp;rsquo;m even more sold on acornhosting as a solid web hosting provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up WEP</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/16/setting-up-wep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/16/setting-up-wep/</guid>
      <description>How to set up WEP encryption:
 SMC Barricade Basestation Airport Extreme Wireless Card Mac OS X 10.2.6  Note that if things don&amp;rsquo;t go 100% right, you may lock yourself out of your wireless network. Be sure you know how to get back in before you follow any of these instructions.
 Set up non-encrypted transmission first. Make sure you can connect to your basestation and surf on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Mail Woes</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/05/more-mail-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/05/more-mail-woes/</guid>
      <description>I spent most of this afternoon struggling with a mail issue and I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it documented well anywhere else, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to write about it here in the hopes that it might help someone else.
What I was trying to do: Setup qmail + vpopmail + courier imap for imap and pop3d
Problem I was having: For some users, checking POP3 mail would work for a while (about 5 minutes), but then would fail:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>me vs. daemontools</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/29/me-vs.-daemontools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/29/me-vs.-daemontools/</guid>
      <description>I have a love/hate relationship with daemontools. It&amp;rsquo;s powerful way to manage services (like web servers and mail servers), but it sometimes doesn&amp;rsquo;t act the way I expect it to.
Today, I tried to set up qmail-pop3d. I set up a directory called /var/qmail/supervise/qmail-pop3d and put a file named &amp;lsquo;run&amp;rsquo; inside it. This contained:
#!/bin/sh PATH=/var/qmail/bin:/usr/local/sbin:/usr/local/bin:/usr/bin:/bin export PATH tcpserver -H -R 0 pop-3 /var/qmail/bin/qmail-popup vkurup.acornhosting.net /home/vpopmail/bin/vchkpw /var/qmail/bin/qmail-pop3d Maildir &amp;amp;  Then I connected the run script to my /service directory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>compiling vpopmail</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/28/compiling-vpopmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/28/compiling-vpopmail/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m setting up vpopmail 5.2.1 - a POP3 email manager for qmail, but it won&amp;rsquo;t compile out of the box.
gcc -I. -Icdb -g -O2 -Wall -c vconvert.c In file included from vconvert.c:35: vmysql.h:53:22: missing terminating &amp;quot; character vmysql.h:60:35: missing terminating &amp;quot; character make[2]: *** [vconvert.o] Error 1 make[2]: Leaving directory `/usr/local/src/vpopmail-5.2.1&#39; make[1]: *** [all-recursive] Error 1 make[1]: Leaving directory `/usr/local/src/vpopmail-5.2.1&#39; make: *** [all-recursive-am] Error 2  Whenever make gives you an error, look for the first error you can find.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>