<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-09T07:01:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parenting Highs and Lows]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/03/03/parenting-highs-and-lows"/>
    <updated>2011-03-03T21:11:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/03/03/parenting-highs-and-lows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Written a few weeks ago</em></p>

<p>I came home late today, so Anika and Kavi had already eaten dinner and
taken their baths. As I drove down the driveway, I could see Kavi's
excited little head poking over the upstairs windowsill. I parked the
car and opened the door into the house. I was immediately met a voice
screaming, "Daddy, Daddy!" with pure joy in his voice. He ran down the
stairs and gave me a huge hug. I just love that. There is nothing
better than coming home to such a loving family. It makes all the
stress and BS at work melt away.</p>

<p>Then I followed him upstairs and Anika ran over and gave me a big hug
and then started "Dancing on the diaper pad!" (Will have to upload a
video of that someday). I watched for a few moments and then got up to
go change my clothes. She started to get upset, so I held her hand and
walked her down the hallway with me. That's another thing I
love. Seeing this sweet little girl with her arm extended as high as
she can possibly reach to hold my hand, walking with me, like I'm the
most important person in the world, just makes my heart melt. I don't
know what I've done to deserve such love and admiration. I just hope
that I can live up to their expectations.</p>

<p>Kavi had a scary episode on Superbowl Sunday. We were just getting
ready to go next door for the Superbowl party. I was upstairs with
Anika and she had just been getting upset about how she wanted to go
downstairs. Kavi and Mommy were downstairs, but they were coming
upstairs, so I wanted Anika to stay up here, rather than go down and
then come up again. I picked her up and held her in my arms to keep
her happy. I heard Kavi start coming up the stairs, and normally I
would have opened the baby-gate for him, but this time I didn't want
Anika to see me opening the gate, because I thought she'd start
getting upset again, wanting to go downstairs. Instead, I just stood a
few feet away from the gate, telling Anika, "See, Kavi's coming
upstairs." He's opened the gate hundreds of times and has never had
any trouble doing it. This time, however, he opened the gate, lost his
balance and the gate started swinging open over the stairs. He held on
to the gate and swung with it. He was hanging on tightly and I could
see his feet dangling, trying to find a foothold on a step, but since
the gate had swung open over the stairs, he was too high to reach the
stairs. I vividly saw the fear in his huge eyes and ran to the gate,
but by the time I got there, the gate had given way and he was
tumbling down the stairs.</p>

<p>Time stopped.</p>

<p>He screamed with the most terrified scream that I've ever heard. He
initially landed on his feet in the middle of the staircase, but the
momentum made him fly down the stairs and his head banged against the
far wall. The gate followed close behind and landed on top of
him. Anika started screaming in my arms. She instinctively knew that
something bad had happened. I initially bent over to put her down at
the top of the stairs and then quickly reconsidered, knowing that she
would want to come down with me and might fall in the process. I
picked her back up and headed down the stairs as Mala raced up from
the kitchen. I gave Anika to Mala as I grabbed Kavi and looked him
over. He had a tiny scrape on his head, but no bleeding. He seemed to
be complaining most about pain in his left arm and shoulder. It
reassured me a bit, because I was worried about his head, but then I
got worried that maybe he had broken his arm or something. We held him
for a while and put ice on his head and shoulders. Anika was tearful
watching all of this but calmed down quickly. Then I went upstairs to
fix the gate.</p>

<p>Within a few minutes he was bouncing around without any sign that he
had fallen. I was so relieved, but I still have visions of his eyes
being full of fear as he was hanging from that swinging gate. I know
how lucky I am and how lucky we have been, in general. I also know
that there will be other scary moments in the future - it's a part of
life. Weathering this admittedly minor mishap took all the strength
and fortitude that I could muster. How do people do it? How do people
withstand bad things happening to their kids? I just don't know how
people can take so much potential pain.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I retract my previous tweet]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/04/i-retract-my-previous-tweet"/>
    <updated>2011-02-04T21:43:53-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/02/04/i-retract-my-previous-tweet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I take it back. I was upset, OK? Never tweet when you're upset. I'm
writing this blog post to make up for it. See, a whole blog post. That
definitely outweighs a tweet, right?</p>

<p>Last week, my 1996 Altima died. The starter seemed to be firing, but
the engine never turned over. We tried jumping it, but that didn't
work. I called a tow truck and then
<a href="http://twitter.com/vkurup/status/31553126746038272">tweeted</a> about
how upset I was with the universe.</p>

<blockquote><p>hey universe, I would love to go a full 6 months without a car dying. #kthxbye</p></blockquote>

<p>Snarky, huh? Even stuck the childish #kthxbye in there. Blaming the
universe is kinda like getting upset with God, in a scientist's mind.</p>

<p>But, it's been a week now, and I've had time to think about it and I
now realize how lucky I am. Not just in general, because that's
certainly true and something that I remember every time I come home
and see my beautiful wife and kids. But, how lucky I am that my car
died. Let's look at some details. The car was in our neighborhood's
parking lot when it died. I was coming home from work and saw Mala and
the kids playing at the playground, so I pulled into the parking lot
and played with them for a while. When we got in the car to go home,
the car wouldn't start. The car was dead in a parking lot, in a safe
neighborhood, walking distance from our house. Just think of all the
other places that it could've died. How lucky that it died in that
location, where it was easy for a tow truck to access, where it was
not in the way of traffic, where it was safe, and most importantly,
where it was easy for everyone to get home. The kids enjoyed just
about every moment of the experience (just like Kavi did when our RAV4
died in much more stressful circumstances in NYC last fall).</p>

<p>The tow truck came, did a little testing and then dutifully towed the
car to my mechanic and dropped the key in their dropbox. They found a
distributor filled with oil and some worn out spark plugs. The fixes
weren't cheap, but they weren't too expensive (using rebuilt
parts). I was driving again about 48 hours after the car died and life
is back to normal now. Again, how lucky is that?</p>

<p>I was also thinking about the previous time that the Altima died. I
remember writing this affirmation in my journal, while I was waiting
for the tow truck back in September 2008:</p>

<blockquote><p>Late entry. This was written on the day that the Nissan's battery
died. Everything will be fine. I will find out later how this will
be a blessing in disguise. This car will give us another 2-3 years
of great service.</p></blockquote>

<p>It's now been 2 and a half years since then and the car has been
steady and reliable throughout that time. How lucky can a guy get?
The Nissan is pushing 140,000 miles and it's not the most convenient
car with the 2 carseats taking up the whole back seat, so I think it's
time for a new car, but how lucky that I have the luxury of taking my
time to find one?</p>

<p>So, Thank you Universe! I look forward to the next lesson that you've
got in store for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy New Year]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/01/03/happy-new-year"/>
    <updated>2010-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/01/03/happy-new-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is going to be a great year. I was working on New Year's Eve. My shift
was supposed to end at midnight, which meant that I would normally be home
around 12:30 AM, but my colleague let me out early since the ER was
unusually light. I got home at 11:55 PM, so I was able to kiss my beautiful
wife as the new year began. If that's not an auspicious start to a year, I
don't know what one would be.</p>

<p>I am so lucky. I have a great job, which is getting better all the time. I
work hard, but I get some pretty good karmic rewards. It's not perfect and
maybe someday I'll rant about the pitfalls of being a hospitalist, but it's
certainly better than my life was as a primary care doctor.</p>

<p>I live in a beautiful house where I feel comfortable and "at home". I have
a loving extended family who, thankfully, are all pretty happy and healthy.</p>

<p>Most importantly, I have an amazing wife and 2 darling children who can
lift my heart into the heavens just by looking at me a certain way. They
can also make me feel completely unfit to be a father sometimes, but I
guess that's part of being a father. I have so much to teach them and they
have so much to teach me.</p>

<p>This is starting to feel like a "Thanksgiving" post rather than a "New
Year's" post. The bottom line is that I have a great feeling that this is
going to be a great year for me and my family.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soon there will be two]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2008/12/17/soon-there-will-be-two"/>
    <updated>2008-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2008/12/17/soon-there-will-be-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kavi has been getting bored being surrounded by adults all the time. He is very happy to announce that a sibling is on its way. We're calling it blueberry. If things go on schedule, blueberry will be born sometime in June, so we'll have 2 June babies, a couple years apart.</p>

<p>Pregnancy has been uneventful, unless you count those recurrent waves of nausea and vomiting that Mala's been experiencing. Hopefully that will get better as we move into the second trimester.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.kurup.org/images/blueberry-12wks-best.jpg"><img title="blueberry-12wks-best" src="https://www.kurup.org/images/blueberry-12wks-best-300x202.jpg" alt="blueberry" width="300" height="202" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm alive]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2008/08/02/im-alive"/>
    <updated>2008-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2008/08/02/im-alive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OK, I know it's been almost a year since I updated this blog, but rest assured that I'm still alive and kicking. The observant among you will notice that the design of the blog has changed. The even more observant will notice that huge swaths of content are now missing. Things like my photo albums, my running log, old comments, and Kavi's little site are now gone. They may make a reappearance someday, especially if I get prodded sufficiently. I have my old site running locally on my laptop, but I'm too lazy to bring it all back right now.</p>

<p>If you're just interested in pics of Kavi (and I know that's most of you), go visit <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/vvkurup">my Picasa photo album</a>.</p>

<p>Cathy Sarisky, who had so kindly hosted kurup.org for a few years now, has decided to exit the web hosting business. I took the opportunity to scale down my web operations a bit. This blog is now powered by <a href="http://wordpress.org">WordPress</a> instead of <a href="http://www.openacs.org">OpenACS</a>. I'm hoping that "outsourcing" the tech stuff to WordPress will allow me to focus more on writing stuff, rather than tweaking settings. Hold me to it! I've stolen the design for this blog from <a href="http://diveintomark.org">diveintomark</a>. I've always enjoyed his writing and his design sense. I hope he doesn't mind.</p>

<p>So much has changed since my last post. Kavi has just continued to grow and amaze us. I know for a fact that he is the most adorable little boy in the universe. He's gotten even more adorable now that he sleeps through the night (as of the past month!). We've moved into a house for the first time in our adult lives. We are now residents of Chapel Hill, NC. We're living the American Dream. I'm going to skip right over the whole purchase process which was more nightmarish than it should have been thanks to some very difficult sellers. Since moving in, we've replaced a missing toilet tank, shampooed carpets, changed locks, and hired painters, landscapers, electricians, pest control people, gutter cleaners and house cleaners. Almost makes you want to move back into an apartment. :-)</p>

<p>I started work as a hospitalist last September, and I'm starting to get into a groove now. It was quite a shock to switch from outpatient, academic practice to inpatient, private practice. At times, I still feel like a resident, but for the most part, I find this job to be much more rewarding intellectually and spiritually. It's more exhausting than I thought it would be, though. I can't see myself working this kind of schedule for the rest of my life. So, as always, I'm still trying to figure out exactly what I want to do when I grow up.</p>

<p>Well, enough rambling for my first post back. Hope to speak to y'all soon (That's the southerner in me now!)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
