<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>happiness on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/happiness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in happiness on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 10:24:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/happiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A great moment</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/16/a-great-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 10:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/16/a-great-moment/</guid>
      <description>I woke up, got ready and went downstairs. I am not a morning person. I try to do as little thinking as possible, because thinking eventually leads to the rational conclusion that I should just go back to bed. I get to the coffee machine, grab my plastic mug and start pouring. Suddenly, I&amp;rsquo;m woken from my daze. I hear little footsteps pounding across the hallway above me. I look towards the bottom of the stairs and see a little figure race around the corner with a determined, slightly fearful look in her face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Found the Carolina North trail</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/10/09/found-the-carolina-north-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/10/09/found-the-carolina-north-trail/</guid>
      <description>When Mala and I started looking for homes, we listed on a yellow notepad all the things that were important to us. Like most little notes in my life, it got lost. I found it a few days after we moved into our home and was pleasantly surprised that we had gotten everything on our list, except a lake view. Not bad, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lake about a half mile from our door.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re married!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/23/were-married/</guid>
      <description>Mala and Vinod  Life update time. If you&amp;rsquo;re a keen follower of this site, you&amp;rsquo;ll have noticed the little box in the upper left hand corner announcing my wedding to Mala. We got married a few months back and it was documented in photos by friends, family and even an official photographer. (Time wasting warning: There are 500 pictures from friends and family, 1200+ proofs from our photographer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>She said YES!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/27/she-said-yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/09/27/she-said-yes/</guid>
      <description>And I&amp;rsquo;m so happy!
{: .inset width=500}
Comments from old site Congratulations
 :) Jade Rubick 2004-09-27 12:40:29   Nice
 May all your troubles be *little ones*. ;-) Carl Robert Blesius 2004-09-27 17:58:23   Congratulations
 Hey Vin that&#39;s great, you two make a great looking couple, I wish you many happy years together. Again Congratulations. Andy Drout 2004-09-27 18:18:54   Congratulations Dude
 I&#39;m excited that I&#39;m gonna have a brother :) Puja Puri 2004-09-29 20:46:14   Best wishes</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>