<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: informatics | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/informatics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-07T22:18:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting again]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2008/12/13/starting-again"/>
    <updated>2008-12-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2008/12/13/starting-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the remaining 2 readers of kurup.org (one of them being me), let me apologize for the lack of posts here over the past couple years. I have always meant to write more, but most of my writing seems to consist of apologies for not writing, short bursts of writing, and then long stretches of inactivity. We are nearing the end of a long stretch of inactivity now, so it's time for the apologies.</p>

<p>A part of my apprehension has always been that someone will read my writing and laugh at how ridiculous I am. How could I possibly take myself seriously? Yes, I am quite self conscious. But, I figure that now that I've posted just about nothing for the past year, anyone left here is going to be pretty forgiving of what I write.</p>

<p>So, I hereby announce my plan to start writing blog posts again. I don't know what exactly I'll write about, but I don't think there will be much focus. Whatever I'm happening to think about will become the new focus of kurup.org.</p>

<p>Kavi is now 18 months old. He loves to sing, dance and make art. He has about 25 words that he says, although you have to be his father or mother to understand most of them. To my delight, he loves to sit in my lap just before bedtime and listen to me read stories. His favorite at the moment is a book called "We're Going on a Bear Hunt." It's a silly book that has a repeating theme with the words "Uh oh" and "Oh no!" at regular, predictable places in the story. And whenever I get to those words, Kavi sings them back to me as only a toddler can. "Uh ooooooooh!" and "Nu nooooo!". I'm actually going to miss these days once he's speaking coherently someday...</p>

<p>Work has been getting better. I've been at DRH for over a year now and I'm starting to feel more comfortable as a hospitalist. I have much more confidence in my gut feelings than I did a year ago. Medicine, however, is always humbling, so whenever you start feeling comfortable, you can almost guarantee that something is going to blindside you and make you re-evaluate your thought processes and assumptions. I had a case like that the other day, which I'm not going to go into at the moment, since it's too fresh and I haven't had time to figure out what lessons I need to learn from it yet. On the whole, though, I am feeling better about work. I've even volunteered to lead a project to institute online progress notes (Electronic Medical Records) at the hospital. This, to me, is scary. There are so many things that can go wrong with any computerization project in healthcare and this is one that I badly want to go right. If there are any people who have been through this process before, I would love to hear from you.</p>

<p>PS. Thanks <a href="http://mark.aufflick.com">Mark</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Primary Care Dying?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/is-primary-care-dying"/>
    <updated>2006-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/is-primary-care-dying</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kurup.org/dave/blog/2006/09/07/primary-care-medicine-perspective">Dave referenced an interesting article</a> in the NEJM titled <a href="http://content.nejm.org/cgi/content/full/355/9/861">"Primary Care -- Will it Survive?"</a> These two quotes summarize the problem:</p>

<blockquote><p>A 2006 report from the Center for Studying Health System Change reveals that from 1995 to 2003, inflation-adjusted income decreased by 7.1 percent for all physicians and by 10.2 percent for primary care physicians.</p></blockquote>

<p>and</p>

<blockquote><p>It has been estimated that it would take 10.6 hours per working day to deliver all recommended care for patients with chronic conditions, plus 7.4 hours per day to provide evidence-based preventive care, to an average panel of 2500 patients (the mean U.S. panel size is 2300).</p></blockquote>

<p>Compensation is down and responsibilities are up. I've been especially aware of this as more than a few of my colleagues have left, without being replaced. So not only do we have more to do per patient, we have more total patients per doc. This will worsen as the population ages. These conditions are leading to a decrease in the number of students and residents who choose primary care, which of course creates a vicious cycle.</p>

<p><a href="http://content.nejm.org/cgi/content/full/355/9/861/F1"><img src="http://content.nejm.org/content/vol355/issue9/images/large/01f1.jpeg" alt="primary care over time" /></a></p>

<p>One of the interesting solutions proposed in the article was a heavier use of web-based solutions:</p>

<blockquote><p>A more thoughtful solution to physicians' time constraints requires a combination of team care and electronic encounters. Nonphysician team members working with Web- and e-mail- based patient portals can perform routine preventive care functions and manage less complex chronic care. However, forging cohesive and efficient teams is a challenge, and few payers adequately reimburse these services.</p></blockquote>

<p>I'm interested in creating those types of solutions. The problem is that when you use these solutions and begin to speed up patient care, the temptation will be to increase the number of patients seen, rather than to spend more quality time with each patient. If you do that, you begin to break the doctor-patient relationship - a relationship that is more valuable than the purely technical aspects of care alone.</p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>In decline, yes</b></p>
<p>
I'm not sure about dying. But conditions may have to get really bad, or more likely, a high-profile personage will have to die because of the lack of  good primary care before things change.
</p>
<p>
A recent conversation with a colleague from residency, a general
internist in private practice, revealed a high level of frustration
with policy makers who are totally disconnected from front line
realities. In large part I agree with him.
</p>
<p>
Policy makers are busy studying questions like this:
</p>
<p>
"Television Watching and Other Sedentary Behaviors in Relation to Risk of Obesity and Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus in Women" (JAMA. 2003;289:1785-1791)
</p>
<p>
in order to come to conclusions like this:
</p>
<p>
Obesity is an important problem, but please, do we need a study to
prove that watching TV doesn't help you get thinner? Next will be a
guideline that primary care docs quantify how many hours each patient
watches T.V. .....
</p>
<p>
My friend detailed regulatory changes in nursing home care that make
it harder for him to do the right thing for patients.
</p>
<p>
Perhaps another way that the internet can play a positive role in this
mess is to channel such feedback to policy makers who truly are
interested in change or to expose to the public eye frustrations
voiced by docs in private.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Prem Thomas</span>
<span class="date">2006-10-03 14:47:01</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="my-comment">
<p><b>So true</b></p>
<p>
<i>Next will be a guideline that primary care docs quantify how many
hours each patient watches T.V. .....</i>
</p>
<p>
I laughed out loud when I read this. Because it's so true. Lately it
seems that everyone has another 'pet' project that we need to
implement. HIV screening for everyone - only takes a few
minutes. Depression screening for everyone - just a few minutes. And
it's hard to argue with it because they seem like worthwhile to do,
yet it really squeezes the time that you have with the patient.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Vinod Kurup</span>
<span class="date">2006-10-04 12:50:17</span>
</address>
</div>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>From a Patient's Perspective</b></p>
<p>
As a patient with chronic depression, I find dealing with primary care
physicians to be such a frustrating and humiliating experience, I
stopped going.  Every ailment I have presented to a primary care
physician has been quickly dismissed as being "all in my head," with
no real analysis of my symptoms.  Even potentially serious conditions,
such as 12 years of infertility or rectal bleeding, are dismissed as
being pychiatric in nature.  How a primary care physician can make a
determination that my symptoms are baseless, without doing blood work
or even a basic physical exam, is amazing to me.  That's why I have
totally given up going to the doctor all together.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Unregistered Visitor</span>
<span class="date">2007-01-30 10:32:45</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
