<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>computers on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/computers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in computers on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 16:09:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/computers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve gone to the dark side</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/14/ive-gone-to-the-dark-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 16:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/10/14/ive-gone-to-the-dark-side/</guid>
      <description>I was a huge Apple fan growing up and IBM was Apple&amp;rsquo;s enemy. Buying an IBM computer would have been unthinkable.
Well, the unthinkable has happened. Of course IBM doesn&amp;rsquo;t make laptops anymore, but their computers live on under the Lenovo name. I am the proud owner of a new Lenovo Thinkpad T420S. I love this computer. It&amp;rsquo;s an ugly black boxy thing, but it&amp;rsquo;s light (4 lbs), quiet and speedy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Computers</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/04/02/my-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/04/02/my-computers/</guid>
      <description>My introduction to computers came when I was about 6 or 7 years old - I can&amp;rsquo;t quite remember exactly when&amp;hellip; Venu Mammen (my uncle) brought home a terminal from work. It looked like a typewriter, but it had 2 suction-cup-thingys where you could attach a phone headset. (Phone headsets were pretty much all the same shape back then). Venu Mammen issued some magical command and then up on the screen came the most amazing phrase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R.I.P.</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/09/22/r.i.p./</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/09/22/r.i.p./</guid>
      <description>Bad news! My Powerbook G3 went kaput yesterday. After a day or so of troubleshooting, I&amp;rsquo;m blaming it on a dead Power Management Unit. I bought it used in 1999 and have been using it heavily since. It&amp;rsquo;s lived in 7 apartments with me (yup, 7!) from Boston to Green Bay to Minneapolis to Boston (again!) and now to NYC. I still think that 4-5 years is way too short a lifespan for a computer, especially since it was meeting my needs in every other way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>