<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hospitalist | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/hospitalist/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-07T22:18:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospitalist Heaven]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/17/hospitalist-heaven"/>
    <updated>2011-08-17T21:41:09-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/17/hospitalist-heaven</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whenever things get too busy in the hospital, morale drops. I
<a href="/blog/2011/08/06/when-i-get-too-busy">complained about that</a> a little
while ago. Now I have a little good news to report. Administration has
been planning to add another line to the schedule because of the
increased volume. They asked a few of the hospitalists (I wasn't
involved) to come together to figure out the best way to use that
additional line. Instead of just adding another rounder or another
admitter, we're going to have a flex-admitter. Yeah, they just made
that word up. The flex-admitter will be scheduled to work from 7AM to
4PM doing just admissions and holding the painful 9050 pager. (That's
the pager that gets all the calls from the ER, consults, and outside
hospitals). At 3PM, the flex-admitter hands over the 9050 pager to the
evening admitter, and ties up loose ends in order to be able to get
out by 4 (as long as it's not too busy). They then come in the next
day and start their rounding shifts, which means that they get to keep
taking care of the patients they just admitted. Yay for continuity!</p>

<p>The flex part comes in when it gets busy. Right now, when it gets
busy, we don't have a lot of options. We try to find people to come in
on their off-days, or find moonlighters, but that is difficult and
expensive. Now, if the census rises above a certain number
(tentatively 15 patients per doc), then the flex-admitter will
automatically switch from an admitter to a rounder. They'll still come
in at 7AM, but will be assigned 10 patients and will be responsible
for the 9050 pager until noon. After that, they can focus on rounding
on their patients with a goal of getting out by 7PM. This is similar
to how our Day 1 currently functions, so it's doable. They've also
recommended changes in the way the 9050 pager is handed off, so the
overnight person holds the 9050 pager for a shorter period of
time. It's key to make our night shifts more palatable so we can hold
on to our valuable nocturnist and hopefully hire a few more.</p>

<p>We'll have to see how this works in practice, but I see this change as
improving continuity, making night shifts better, making the first day
shift better, and making our responsiveness to high census better, all
of which should help overall morale. I love that the decision-making
power for these changes was given to hospitalists in the trenches,
rather than made from above by administration.</p>

<p>We're hiring hospitalists, nocturnists and PA's, so if you're
interested in working with super-intelligent docs (and me), in a
<a href="http://www.durhamregional.org">great community hospital</a> where you
can actually make changes in the way healthcare is delivered, while
having the backing of an academic giant (Duke) in the background,
contact me and I'll put you in touch with the people in charge.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When I Get Too Busy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/06/when-i-get-too-busy"/>
    <updated>2011-08-06T19:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/08/06/when-i-get-too-busy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been writing a lot lately (<a href="http://750words.com">750 words a day</a>
for the last 85 days, to be precise), but most of it is for my own
purposes. I want to be a better writer and I know that writing every
day is the first step in that process. Sharing that writing with the
world is also important, but that's a lot scarier to me. I'm trying to
let go of my inhibitions knowing that my 3 readers will not judge me
harshly, but it's still difficult. Today I'm sharing something that I
wrote a while back...</p>

<hr />

<p>Work was rough today. It is so hard to walk into a census of 18
patients on Day 1 and feel like you are doing any good. Near the end
of the day, I'm just going through the motions and not really properly
diagnosing or listening to patients. That's not quite true. I always
try to listen. It is the one thing that I do well. I can listen and
hear things that other people never hear. I am pretty good at
understanding what someone is really concerned about. Sometimes I
don't want to know. Like the drug abuser who is concerned that she
isn't getting enough pain meds, but presents it as a failing of the
nurses or the doctors who have taken care of her before. I know what
she wants, but I don't want to give it to her and if she's not even
going to be honest about it, then I'm not going to go digging to try
to figure it out. But overall, I am good at listening.</p>

<p>I lose other skills on days like today. I don't think as much. I don't
try to figure out why the patient with improving foot wounds and
improving peri-rectal abscesses has a rising white count. Something
else is going on, but I haven't figured it out. So I end up falling
back on the plan that the previous providers put into place, without
really taking the time to investigate what might be going on.</p>

<p>I lose the skill of diligence. When I come in on day 1 and have 12
patients, I take the time to investigate and document each of their
active diagnoses and I at least pay lip service to the nonactive
ones. I make sure that I've addressed commonly overlooked items like
DVT prophylaxis, code status, smoking cessation, PQRI measures and
living situation. They are easy to overlook because they don't present
themselves as active problems in most cases (i.e. code status) or they
are handled by other services (like nursing or pharmacy), so I feel
like I can drop the ball on them and know that they will be
addressed. But when things aren't busy, I take the time to cross each
T and dot each I. I definitely don't do that when I walk into 18
patients.</p>

<p>It's at times like this that I realize what a failing I am as a
doctor. The doctors that I looked up to in medical school and
residency would never accept what I do now. They would never leave the
hospital just because it was getting late and they wanted to see their
family. They would stay late and sacrifice in order to make sure that
everything was done. I can honestly say that I don't think I'm putting
patients in harm's way by practicing the way I do, but I know I could
do better. I just know if I did better, I would not be able to keep
working this job. I feel burned out as it is, and more time away from
my family would just make that so much less bearable.</p>

<p>On the flip side, I know that I do many good things that other
hospitalists don't do well. I keep track of how patients do after I
discharge them. When I'm feeling really energetic, I contact them, but
at a minimum, I add them to a list in eBrowser so that I can keep
track of how they do. I also relish spending time with patients and
families. It's without question my favorite part of the job. I try my
best not to let my stress level shine through when I'm with
patients. I make a point of slowing down and talking in a
conversational tone and language, even on the busiest days. I don't
answer my phone or respond to pages once I've started talking with a
patient unless it is clearly an emergency. And if I do leave, then I
apologize. I encourage patients to ask questions and contact me
whenever they have questions, though I encourage them to write their
questions down and consolidate family questions for efficiency
purposes. But if a new family member comes in after I've talked to
everyone else and they have questions, I try to come back and talk to
them. I know that this particular situation annoys the heck out of
physicians, but I can understand how it happens in the real world, so
I try to accomodate. I have a good sense of sick and not-sick, even if
I'm not the most skilled diagnostician. I also have a good sense of
what to expect in a given situation. I think those are things born of
experience and it allows me to take care of patients better. I guess
I'm saying all this to make myself feel better. To tell anyone reading
this that I'm not really a slacker. Which means I'm being defensive,
which tells me that I shouldn't have to be defensive. I should just be
doing what I'm supposed to be doing so that I don't have to make
excuses for myself. OK, fine. Let's address the diligency part. What
are the things that I should be addressing in every patient that is in
the hospital?</p>

<hr />

<p>Here is a checklist that I started using in all my patients after
writing that little rant. It's helped me focus on the little things
and more than a couple colleagues have started to use something
similar after seeing mine.</p>

<ul>
<li>PCP</li>
<li>Disposition: Home/HH/ALF/SNF/DRI, estimated LOS</li>
<li>DVT prophylaxis</li>
<li>Smoking</li>
<li>PQRI: CHF/MI/Pneumonia/Stroke</li>
<li>Primary family contact: Contacted today?</li>
<li>Code status</li>
<li>Goals of care</li>
<li>Tubes/lines: What's installed, how do the sites look?</li>
<li>Bowels: Last moved?</li>
<li>Activity: Can they walk?</li>
<li>Reviewed meds?</li>
<li>Pending labs?</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SHM 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/05/13/shm-2011"/>
    <updated>2011-05-13T05:35:21-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/05/13/shm-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are some (unorganized) thoughts about my experience at the
Society of Hospital Medicine (SHM) 2011 conference in Dallas, TX.</p>

<h3>Opening Plenary</h3>

<p>The initial presentation dissected the SHM Annual Compensation survey,
discussing regional variations in pay and work effort over time. I
understand the importance of that stuff, but ever since I got my first
$638.36 paycheck as an intern, money hasn't been an issue for me.</p>

<p>The second talk was by <a href="http://www.whorunsgov.com/Profiles/Robert_Kocher">Bob
Kocher</a>, an Obama
insider during the recent healthcare reformd. Gerry would have loved
this one. He briefly described how a bill becomes a law... it
apparently doesn't follow the Schoolhouse Rock model anymore. At one
point, reform looked dead, when the Catholic Nuns came out in favor of
the legislation allowing multiple congress members to change their
vote to "Yes". As Kocher put it (paraphrasing), "When the Nuns broke
with the Bishops, healthcare reform could move forward." Doesn't that
seem like a statement that should be in a history book about medieval
times, rather than a statement about 2010 United States politics?
Maybe it's just me...</p>

<h3>Neurologic emergencies</h3>

<p>The Neurologic emergencies talk was entertaining, though maybe more
useful to an intensivist. David Likosky is hilarious in a geeky kind
of way. A few things I learned:</p>

<p>Always maintain a good differential diagnosis and don't jump to a
conclusion too quickly. He described a case of an alcoholic who
presented in coma and had dynamic pupils making a brainstem stroke the
most likely diagnosis. A lot of time was spent to rule that out, and
then his labs came back with a sugar of 13, indicating that the
diagnosis of hypoglycemia was missed. He described some of the reasons
that happened and I can see them happening to me. Never get fixated on
a diagnosis, especially before you've made the proper initial
evaluaation. A fingerstick glucose should always be done in a coma
workup.</p>

<p>A few points on status epilepticus (SE)</p>

<ul>
<li>Convulsive SE is a seizure that lasts more than 5 minutes, and is a medical
emergency.</li>
<li>Lorazepam is probably better than Diazepam and don't be
afraid to use high doses (Start at 4 IV). We commonly underdose and
underdosing hurts.</li>
<li>Nonconvulsive SE is considered as a medical urgency. A lot of
patients have SE on EEG after convulsions have stopped and many have
persistent subclinical seizures after SE is controlled. So, repeat the
EEG, and consider transfer to a center that can do continuous EEG monitoring.</li>
<li>Absence seizures is really a diagnosis of children. (Not really
about SE, but interesting)</li>
</ul>


<p>Things to make you think that a CVA may be posterior circulation: Loss
of consciousness, pupillary abnormalities, superhigh BP. Allow it to
stay superhigh and keep the patient flat. Because posterior
circulation strokes have such bad outcomes, it's OK to intervene after
the normal time window if there doesn't seem to be any other hope.</p>

<h3>Dermatology images (Paul Aronowitz)</h3>

<p>When approaching a rash, ask 3 questions: Did the patient cause this
rash? Did we do that to the patient? (Ask this twice). Is this rash a
manifestation of some other disease? We often jump to the third
question, but should consider the first two.</p>

<p>The snake bite risk factors are pretty interesting:
- Male
- Age 17-27
- Deliberate attempt to handle, harm or kill snake
- Summer months
- Alcohol intoxication
- Tattoos</p>

<p>DRESS (Drug reaction with eosinophilia and systemic symptoms) usually
occurs 2-6 weeks after the drug is started, but occurs quicker after
rechallenge with the drug.</p>

<p>Reactive arthritis can be seen after Clostridium difficile infections.</p>

<p>20% of cases of Neisseria meningitidis do not have meningitis.</p>

<h3>Poster presentations</h3>

<p>The poster presentations are always fun to read, though if I see one
more poster about the readmission problem, I will vomit.</p>

<h3>Research Abstract Awards</h3>

<p>The winning research abstracts were very interesting.</p>

<ul>
<li>UCSF described changes that they made to meet new ACGME requirements
while decreasing costs and improving certain quality measures.</li>
<li><p>Johns Hopkins hospitalists modified their CPOE system to show the
costs of specific lab tests, hoping to change provider behavior. They
were able to show that providers ordered less tests when they saw the
cost. Duh, you say, but there is so little cost information available
to providers, so this is innovative if only for that reason.</p></li>
<li><p>Hospitalists (in Colorado, I think?) used the Toyota Production
System to model problems with current intern work schedules. They then
reworked the schedule to minimize waste of resident resources, while
improving continuity and resident satisfaction. They were able to
basically eliminate moonlighter and jeopardy use. I didn't understand
the schedule because it was presented quickly, but I like the idea of
taking a nonmedical thought approach and applying it to medicine. I
also like that they optimized for continuity of care, so that after
the intervention there was a huge increase in the amount of patients
that were seen only by 1 intern during their stay. Very interesting!</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>SHM promotion</h3>

<p>My attention faded during the award presentations and SHM motivational
speeches, but Joseph Li, the incoming SHM president, did come clean
and acknowledge that he was born outside the U.S., despite his lack of
an accent. The birthers were right!</p>

<h3>Geographic rounding</h3>

<p>Emory Hospitalists then presented a talk which was titled 'Utilizing
Technology to Improve Clinical and Operational Performance of
Hospitalists' but it should really have been titled "Geographic
Bedside Rounds: Just Do It!". They did mention the IT improvements
they've made to support geographic rounding, but the value of the talk
was in describing how they implemented geographic rounding and how it
has been received by the involved parties. Moving to geographic
rounding helps providers the least. It's basically an addition to our
workload. On the other hand, patients, nurses, and social workers get
a lot of benefit and obviously, the patients are the most important
factor here. We will have to see the patient more than once and our
workflow will have to change, but it seems that the benefits outweigh
the extra costs to the individual provider. Paraphrased, "Nurses and
social workers would riot if we stopped this system, but even
hospitalists wouldn't want to go back to the old way, if put to a
referendum." Something that only came out in the post-talk questions
was how this has improved overall teamwork. They used to have a
complicated system about how new admissions were assigned, taking into
account census numbers, discharge numbers, and other factors. Now,
with the new system, there are days that one hospitalist will have
completely unequal numbers or new patients than another hospitalist,
but it is understood that things will even out over time. That has
encouraged hospitalists to stop focusing on numbers and instead to
focus on making things run better, so hospitalists who were previously
"anti-teamwork" are now offering to help out when they're done with
their work. Anecdotal, but I like stories like that.</p>

<p>They also mentioned that they created a video dramatization of their
bedside rounds. If I can find it, I will link to it.</p>

<h3>Updates in Hospital Medicine</h3>

<ul>
<li>Oral prednisone 60 mg daily as good as 600 mg IV for COPD
exacerbation (Presented at DRH Journal club)</li>
<li>OK to extend peripheral IVs rather than change routinely (Emailed to
me by DRH Hospitalist)</li>
<li>Getting appts for COPD exacerbation pts within 30 days may decrease
rehospitalization (duh!)</li>
<li>Benefit for tPA in stroke up to 4.5 hours, but earlier is better
(DRH Journal club)</li>
<li>Gurgling sounds predict pneumonia and ICU transfer (duh)</li>
<li>Routine ID consultation in Staph aureus bacteremia significantly
improves mortality (HR 0.44) (NEW TO ME)</li>
<li>Coagulopathy in liver disease doesn't protect against VTE (duh)</li>
<li>Metformin does not cause lactic acidosis (old news, but nice to be
data-supported now)</li>
<li>Enteral nutrition better than TPN in pancreatitis (DRH email/conversations)</li>
<li>In ICU palliative care situations, only 47% of family members based
their survival estimates on MD's prognosis advice.</li>
</ul>


<p>I skipped the ICU stuff. Only one of these updates was new to me
(listed as NEW in the list above). I attribute that to my colleagues
at Durham Regional who have been sharing the knowledge that they've
been collecting from various meetings and readings this year.</p>

<h3>Careers in Academic Medicine</h3>

<p>This was a workshop on how to pursue your ideal life in academic
medicine. I loved the energy and enthusiasm of the instructors. This
probably would've benefited from being a longer course with fewer,
more involved participants. The basic premise was to document what
exactly you are doing now, what you're getting paid to do, and what
you enjoy doing. Reconcile the differences in those 3 lists and try to
identify how to make them match.</p>

<h3>No wireless</h3>

<p>This would have been posted a lot earlier if I could ever get on the
SHM wireless network at the Gaylord Convention Center. "Please
wait. You will be redirected to the authentication page in 5 seconds."
You lie!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Primary Care Doctors]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/08/06/primary-care"/>
    <updated>2010-08-06T11:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/08/06/primary-care</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I used to be a primary care physician, but switched to being a hospitalist
in 2007. I loved parts about being a PCP, namely the relationship that I
developed with the patient over many years. I miss that. I think PCPs offer
huge value in providing low cost, quality care, especially if they can stay
engaged throughout the hospitalization process. Atul Gawande recently wrote
<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2010/08/02/100802fa_fact_gawande?currentPage=all">a powerful article on the Hospice system</a>. It's
worth reading to being to understand the complex issues involved in
end-of-life care, not to mention for the emotional storytelling that is his
strength. But, to me, the unsung hero in that story was Chuck Morris, the
primary care physician, who came in at the proper moment and provided
perspective to the patient that he knew so well, allowing them to make the
sane, yet horribly difficult decision to pursue a palliative path. Reading
that made me miss primary care medicine a little. I perform much more
actual "medical" work as a hospitalist than I ever did as a PCP. But, when
I think of the concept of a <em>doctor</em>, in my head, I'm thinking of a primary
care doc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospitalist Notes 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/07/29/hospitalist-notes-1"/>
    <updated>2010-07-29T13:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2010/07/29/hospitalist-notes-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My last night shift was a little less busy than most, so I forced myself to pick something about each patient I admitted and look it up. I tend to do this anyway, but I never keep notes or write about it. Here's what I wrote about that night:</p>

<h3>Does Buspar (buspirone) need to be tapered?</h3>

<p>Answer: No. The full report on Micromedex was a little conflicting, because it stated that there may be some withdrawal symptoms from Buspar, but this quote in the same profile suggests otherwise:</p>

<blockquote><p>Data suggest that buspirone does not cause physical dependence and as such, no withdrawal effects have been noted (Rickels et al, 1988a; Tyrer et al, 1985; Cole et al, 1982).</p></blockquote>

<h3>Staging COPD</h3>

<p>I always forget the cutoffs for the stages of COPD. There are 2 different guidleines - GOLD and ATS/ARS, but fortunately they are almost identical:</p>

<p>Patients need to have an FEV1/FVC ratio &lt; 0.70. Staging is then based on the FEV1.</p>

<ul>
<li>Stage I (Mild): FEV1 > 80% predicted</li>
<li>Stage II (Moderate): FEV1 50-80% predicted</li>
<li>Stage III (Severe): FEV1 30-50% predicted</li>
<li>Stage IV: (Very Severe): FEV1 &lt; 30% predicted, or &lt; 50% with signs of chronic respiratory failure</li>
</ul>


<p>Reference: <a href="http://www.annals.org/content/147/9/633/T2.expansion.html">Annals</a></p>

<h3>How to determine calorie level of ADA diet?</h3>

<p>We always put diabetic patients on an ADA diet and I choose the calorie level by gestalt. I figured there must be some formula to calculate the calorie level based on the patient's weight. Looking it up, I found a different answer altogether. The ADA no longer recommends an ADA diet in the hospital. Instead, they recommend a consistent-carbohydrate diet. In long-term care facilities (i.e. nursing homes), they go a step further and recommend a 'Regular' diet with consistency in the amount and timing of carbohydrate. They specifically state that there is no evidence to support the classic 'No concentrated sweets' diet. These guidelines are from 2007, but they obviously have not been widely disseminated yet.</p>

<blockquote><p>It is recommended that the term “ADA diet” no longer be used, since the ADA no longer endorses a single nutrition prescription or percentages of macronutrients.</p></blockquote>

<p>Reference: <a href="http://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/30/suppl_1/S48.full">Diabetes Care</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
