<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>free-software on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/free-software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in free-software on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/free-software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>clamz to the rescue</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/04/clamz-to-the-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/04/clamz-to-the-rescue/</guid>
      <description>Kottke linked to some great deals on classical music at amazon. In order to download them, you need to have the amazon mp3 downloader installed. They now offer a Debian (linux) version, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it working. It&amp;rsquo;s meant for an older version of Debian, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize the newer versions of the libraries installed on my system. I thought about doing some fancy apt-getting to try to get the right versions, but just thinking about that made my head throb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source saved my photos!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/05/open-source-saved-my-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2004/01/05/open-source-saved-my-photos/</guid>
      <description>Loyal readers of my blog will remember that my Powerbook Wallstreet G3 died on September 21st, 2002. Since I&amp;rsquo;m probably the only one that remembers, I&amp;rsquo;ll point you to that blog entry. The good news was that the hard drive was intact, the bad news was that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have an easy way of accessing it. I have a Firewire enclosure, and my old Powerbook was running Linux, so I figured it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too difficult to get my new Powerbook to read the data off the old HD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCO</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/11/sco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/11/sco/</guid>
      <description>Open Letter to SCO.
Loud Applause
Comments from old site The Nigerian SCO Connection
 There is a great parody of the nigerian scam spam letter crossed over with SCO over at here(ArsTechnica).  I am very annoyed with these &#34;johnny come lately&#34; types who are trying to claim stake to internet technologies *after* they are already mature. It&#39;s like the company that tried to lay claim to hyperlinks, even though xerox showed the technology back in the 60s, or the recent claim by another company that claims it owns the technology for embedding things like Flash, movies, etc as part of the web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Medicine</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/24/open-source-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/24/open-source-medicine/</guid>
      <description>I wrote up a little intro piece on the use of open source software in medical applications (PDF). HTML below&amp;hellip;
Improving the communication of patient information is the key to improving healthcare quality and efficiency. In most health care organizations, written records are the main conduit of this information, yet they are notoriously illegible and difficult to browse. Reviewing past problems and past interventions is time-consuming, if not impossible. The record is used mostly as a one-way device for the clinician to record data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhotoDB fixed</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/06/19/photodb-fixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/06/19/photodb-fixed/</guid>
      <description>I fixed some security issues in the OpenACS photodb module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bunch of stuff</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/26/bunch-of-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/05/26/bunch-of-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Life has been moving too quickly for me to document my menial existence. Check back again soon when my existence is not so menial! In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a Cliff Note&amp;rsquo;s version (may Cliff rest in peace) of the past 5 months (in no particular order).
 I left medicalrecords.com I began doing freelance web development I finished a Palm-based interface for The Answer Page I began moonlighting at MIT&amp;rsquo;s After Hours Medical Center, thus getting in touch with my &amp;ldquo;medical&amp;rdquo; side again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first OpenACS port</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/01/04/my-first-openacs-port/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/01/04/my-first-openacs-port/</guid>
      <description>I finished porting the homepage module from ACS to OpenACS. Actually, it had already been ported, but the ACS version changed substantially, so I guess I merged the new ACS version with the old OpenACS version. Anyway, it works! Here&amp;rsquo;s the file -&amp;gt; homepage.tar.gz</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y2K1</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/01/02/y2k1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2001/01/02/y2k1/</guid>
      <description>I found a Y2K1 bug &amp;hellip; well, not really, but I found and fixed a minor problem in the OpenACS toolkit that only occurs on the first of every year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>