<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 22:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Steal My Web App Idea</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/09/steal-my-web-app-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 22:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/09/steal-my-web-app-idea/</guid>
      <description>Now that we have 3 kids, I&amp;rsquo;m always internally comparing one to the other. Sure that&amp;rsquo;s not healthy and will probably breed resentment in them during their teenage years, but what&amp;rsquo;s a bad parent to do?
I need an app that takes 2 kids&amp;rsquo; birthdays and then shows me what day it was when the older kid was the age that the younger kid is now. Wow, that&amp;rsquo;s a confusing sentence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter Sweep</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/04/letter-sweep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 06:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/03/04/letter-sweep/</guid>
      <description>Tim Bray posted the links that his browser displays when he types each letter of the alphabet. Here&amp;rsquo;s mine:
[A]dSense. I spend too much time watching the zero&amp;rsquo;s pile up.
[B]orkware. Always good for a quickie. Wait&amp;hellip; that didn&amp;rsquo;t sound right.
[C]ite-U-Like. I&amp;rsquo;ve started to use this site to keep track of journal articles that I read.
[D]ocs (Google). I store my Habits spreadsheet, my weight spreadsheet, our address book spreadsheet (because Google contacts aren&amp;rsquo;t shareable) and other random documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 Up and Running</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/25/html5-up-and-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/25/html5-up-and-running/</guid>
      <description>I preordered Mark Pilgrim&amp;rsquo;s HTML5, Up and Running from Amazon back in March. It&amp;rsquo;s available for free as Dive into HTML5. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of Mark&amp;rsquo;s writing for a while, so buying the book was a way to thank him &amp;ldquo;with a buck&amp;rdquo;. Interestingly, the online book and paper book are not identical. For starters, the titles are different. In addition, the beautiful fonts and cutesy images of the online version are gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prettier permalinks</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/28/prettier-permalinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/28/prettier-permalinks/</guid>
      <description>Permalink stands for &amp;lsquo;permanent link&amp;rsquo;. When you create a blog post, it gets added to the top of your blog, pushing older entries down. Eventually, posts get pushed off the front page, so it&amp;rsquo;s important that you have a way to refer to old blog posts. A permalink is the link that will always point to a specific post.
OpenACS (lars-blogger) permalinks look like this:
http://kurup.org/blog/one-entry?entry_id=58950  This works and it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to code, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give much information about the content or date of the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tag Cloud</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/01/tag-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/03/01/tag-cloud/</guid>
      <description>And now I have a pretty tag cloud on the side of my blog (that I pretty much stole from del.icio.us)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Blog Application using the OpenACS Content Repository</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/16/creating-a-blog-application-using-the-openacs-content-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/02/16/creating-a-blog-application-using-the-openacs-content-repository/</guid>
      <description>I created a very simple blog application using the OpenACS Content Repository (CR). When I say simple, I mean simple, probably to the point of being useless. I just wanted to try writing something as quickly as possible using the CR. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick run-through of the code, in case it might help someone else understand how to use the CR. I&amp;rsquo;m not including much commentary; email me (or comment) if you&amp;rsquo;d like me to expound more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lists in CSS</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/14/lists-in-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/11/14/lists-in-css/</guid>
      <description>A-ha! This article by Eric Meyer explains why &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;&amp;rsquo;s can appear differently in MSIE and Mozilla browsers. Both indent the list items, but MSIE does so by setting the padding to 2.5 em, while Mozilla does so by setting the margin to 2.5 em. These are on the &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt; selectors, not the &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;. So, in order to get consistent display on both browsers, you need to set both padding-left and margin-left to whatever you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCRIPT Tag on MSIE</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/04/script-tag-on-msie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/01/04/script-tag-on-msie/</guid>
      <description>Word to the wise. MSIE5 (Mac) doesn&amp;rsquo;t like:
 &amp;amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;blah&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;blah&amp;quot; /&amp;amp;gt;  It only likes:
 &amp;amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;blah&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;blah&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;lt;/script&amp;amp;gt;  It&amp;rsquo;s quite stubborn. If you try the first example, it will refuse to show any of your page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why OpenACS?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/29/why-openacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/29/why-openacs/</guid>
      <description>Bhavesh responded to my seemingly irrational exuberance about OpenACS asking, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the excitement about OpenACS?&amp;rdquo;
There are much better answers to this question, starting with Why OpenACS?, by my web host Cathy Sarisky, but here&amp;rsquo;s my super brief answer.
OpenACS is a toolkit to build online communities, that is, sites which value users and their contributions. OpenACS provides applications which allow users to create and manage content - applications like forums, photo albums, blogs, calendars, wikis, and file storage areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AOLserver CGI errors</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/20/aolserver-cgi-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/07/20/aolserver-cgi-errors/</guid>
      <description>Scenario: You&amp;rsquo;re trying to run a CGI program under AOLserver and you see this in your error log:
19/Jul/2003:00:00:23 Error: exec /home/vinod/cgi-bin/mt: execve() failed: Permission denied 19/Jul/2003:00:00:23 Error: waitpid(-3) failed: No child processes 19/Jul/2003:00:00:23 Error: nscgi: wait for /home/vinod/cgi-bin/mt failed: No child processes  I&amp;rsquo;m trying to run /home/vinod/cgi-bin/mt/mt.cgi. Why isn&amp;rsquo;t this working? Because I need to tell AOLserver about each and every directory which might contain CGI programs.
So I need to change my nsd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to OpenACS</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/22/moving-to-openacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/06/22/moving-to-openacs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m slowly in the process of moving my site from PHP/MySQL to OpenACS. Things are broken in the meantime. Specifically, I need to import all my old photos, steal MarkD&amp;rsquo;s book module, and implement my family-tree module. If you find something that&amp;rsquo;s broken, feel free to let me know.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently using an open-source stylesheet from The NYPL, but I need to edit it at some point. But for now, at least, it looks better than anything I could drum up by myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerry and Kim - the website</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/01/07/gerry-and-kim-the-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/01/07/gerry-and-kim-the-website/</guid>
      <description>I finally finished Gerry and Kim&amp;rsquo;s wedding site. The HTTP address is temporary. I had made a promise to Kim back in September that I would finish it, but that I needed a deadline. My brain seems to refuse to work without a deadline. Anyway, she said, &amp;ldquo;end of the year&amp;rdquo; and sure enough, it went live on 12/31/2002. It&amp;rsquo;s running on OpenACS 4 (CVS HEAD 12/25/2002), using an Open Source CSS stylesheet from http://w3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>