<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: virus | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/virus/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-07T22:17:08-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New virus?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/08/20/new-virus"/>
    <updated>2003-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/08/20/new-virus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been getting weird emails over the past day or so. The <code>From:</code> address is always different, there is no body text and there is an attachment called <code>your_document.pif</code>. The <code>From:</code> address is sometimes recognizable, but seems to be spoofed.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=your_document.pif">Google only gave me 1 document for "your_document.pif"</a> and that document states that <a href="http://www.f-secure.com/v-descs/sobig_f.shtml">this is a new virus called W32/Sobig.F-mm</a> (link changed due to 404). Not much info about it yet, but it seems pretty widespread.</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> Wow, google only had 1 document for the above search when I wrote this a few hours ago and now it has 391! Looks like this virus is just taking off. <a href="http://www.local6.com/news/2420899/detail.html">Fastest. Virus. Ever.</a></p>

<div id="comment-box">
<h2>Comments from old site</h2>

<div class="one-comment">
<p><b>Sobig.F</b></p>
<p>
According to an article in today's paper (Milwaukee Journal Sentinel
8/21/03) This was called the fastest growing virus ever by MessageLabs
Inc. It halted CSX Transportation trains in Washington DC and infected
more than 2000 computers at the University of Wisconsin Madison.  It
infects PC's running Microsoft Windows, and turns PCs into relayers of
spam e-mail clogging computer servers on the internet and crashing
networks.  The subject line could say "Details", Thank You", or
"Wicked screensaver". The virus doesn't appear to be destroying data
or causing other lasting damage to the machines or networks it has
infected.  You just have to face the daunting task of deleting a ton
of virus e-mails.
</p>
<address class="signature">
<span class="author">Andy Drout</span>
<span class="date">2003-08-21 15:56:28</span>
</address>
</div>

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
