<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>android on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in android on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 21:39:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ClojureScript and PhoneGap</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/11/12/clojurescript-and-phonegap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 21:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/11/12/clojurescript-and-phonegap/</guid>
      <description>Phonegap is a tool that allows you to develop apps in HTML5 + javascript and makes it easy to deploy them to multiple mobile platforms, including Android and iOS.
ClojureScript is a dialect of the awesome language, Clojure, that compiles to Javascript (after a pass through the Google Closure optimizer). Because Clojure, ClojureScript and Google Closure can be confusing terms, I&amp;rsquo;ll use CLJS instead of ClojureScript for the remainder of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doggcatcher</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/23/doggcatcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 21:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/23/doggcatcher/</guid>
      <description>I talked yesterday about how I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the Google Listen podcast client. I did a little Googling and found a nice solution (somewhat ironic, in an Alanis Morrissette kinda way): Doggcatcher. It costs $6.99 and I spent an extra $3.99 for Presto Sound Library which allows you to speed up the podcasts a little. Sorry Merlin! (He hates when people do this). Doggcatcher seems to do everything I mentioned as requirements in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Listen doesn&#39;t rock</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/22/google-listen-doesnt-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 20:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/22/google-listen-doesnt-rock/</guid>
      <description>In the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to podcasts, I&amp;rsquo;ve only found 2 podcast clients that I&amp;rsquo;ve really liked: iTunes (back around 2005-2007) and a bash script that I wrote which simply copied files downloaded by podget onto my iPod nano. Google Listen on my Droid X (Android 2.2) is tolerable, but only barely. I think my requirements are simple. I want to put in URLs and have the client get all the podcasts in that URL and stick them in a queue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android ResourcesNotFoundException</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/16/android-resourcesnotfoundexception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 20:44:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/16/android-resourcesnotfoundexception/</guid>
      <description>If you see this error:
E/AndroidRuntime( 457): android.content.res.Resources$NotFoundException: File Yamba1 from xml type layout resource ID #0x7f060000  &amp;hellip; try deleting the bin/ and gen/ directories in your app. It should clear the error.
Reference: http://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=2726#c6</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Android Review</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/08/learning-android-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 22:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/08/learning-android-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished reading Learning Android. I have a Droid X, Mala has a Droid Eris, and I just bought a Viewsonic g-tablet, so I have plenty of Android devices. While I still have trouble with the idea of typing on a touchscreen, I know that we are moving towards a future where mobile devices are our primary computers. This is not earth shattering. Philip Greenspun mentioned it 5 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>