<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: family | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/family/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-29T21:34:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peanut Allergy, a personal clinical review]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/21/peanut-allergy-a-personal-clinical-review"/>
    <updated>2013-01-21T07:49:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2013/01/21/peanut-allergy-a-personal-clinical-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>A Vignette</h2>

<p>A 22-month-old previously healthy girl was brought to the emergency
room in respiratory distress. She had been well until the day of
presentation. Shortly after disembarking from an airline flight, she
developed cough with one episode of emesis. En route to the emergency
room, her breathing became labored and she developed hives. She was
diagnosed as having an allergic reaction and treated aggressively with
IV methylprednisolone, IV diphenhydramine, inhaled albuterol, and
oxygen. Mechanical ventilation was not required and her symptoms
improved rapidly. She was monitored in the emergency room for an
extended period and discharged in stable condition with a prescription
for diphenhydramine and methylprednisolone solutions. No specific
allergen was identified. She was seen by a pediatric allergist where
she was found to have a 6 mm response to peanut on skin prick testing,
and a peanut-specific IgE level of 52 kU/L. She was diagnosed as
having severe peanut allergy and avoidance was strongly recommended.</p>

<h2>Discussion</h2>

<p>Peanut allergy affects between 0.4 and 2.0% of children. Prevalence
has been increasing in recent years, but the reason for this increase
is not well understood. If reactions are identified immediately,
treatment is usually effective. Despite this, about 200 people die
each year from peanut reactions. Biphasic reactions, in which the
initial reaction subsides, but then recurs within a few hours, are
common. The second portion of a biphasic reaction is often less
treatable. Because of this risk, patients should be monitored for at
least 4 hours after a reaction. Patients who successfully treat their
own reactions with subcutaneous epinephrine should still seek medical
attention, again to monitor for biphasic reactions.</p>

<p>The gold standard for diagnosis is a double blind placebo controlled
food challenge (DBPCFC), but this is rarely done. A diagnosis can
usually be reliably made with clinical history, skin prick testing and
a peanut-specific IgE blood test (psIgE). A skin prick test involves
pricking the skin with a needle that is exposed to peanut extract and
measuring the allergic rash that develops. The psIgE blood test
measures the amount of antibody against peanut proteins. The higher it
is, the more allergic the patient is. A positive skin test or psIgE is
not sufficient for the diagnosis. Some type of reaction to peanuts is
required (either spontaneous, or via monitored food challenge).</p>

<p>Peanut allergy was previously felt to be permanent, but recent
evidence documents that 20% of children outgrow their allergy. More
than 60% of patients with an psIgE level of less than 5 passed a food
challenge. IgE levels correlate inversely with likelihood of
resolution, but this correlation is by no means perfect. Some patients
with undetectable psIgE levels will fail a challenge, while some
patients with very high psIgE levels will pass. One expert recommends
waiting until the age of 4 to consider a challenge, and to use a
cutoff psIgE level of less than 5 kU/L in most patients. Recurrence
of peanut allergy after resolution is rare, but is associated with the
lack of regular peanut intake after resolution of the allergy.</p>

<p>Controversy exists regarding risk factors for developing peanut
allergy. The AAP initially recommended that peanut not be introduced
early in a child's life, but rescinded that advice given the lack of
evidence behind it. This leaves a void for parents as there is no
recommendation to withold or introduce peanuts to toddlers. It is also
not clear if maternal peanut intake during pregnancy or breast feeding
increases the risk of developing peanut allergy in children. Studies
have been conflicting, so more definitive studies are underway. No
evidence-based advice can be given one way or the other to pregnant or
breastfeeding women, but at the minimum, there is no good evidence to
support avoiding peanuts.</p>

<p>The mainstay of treatment is education. Parents should be taught not
only how to identify peanuts in foods, but to identify situations
which are high-risk for exposure to peanuts. Avoidance of buffets,
ice-cream parlors, and bakeries is recommended because the risk of
cross-contamination in those setting is high. Religious reading of
food labels is important. Patients who are allergic to peanuts are
often also allergic to tree nuts, despite the dissimilarity in those
food types. Highly refined peanut oil is usually <em>NOT</em> a risk, but
cold-pressed peanut oil is not safe.</p>

<p>Most importantly, an epi-pen should be carried at all times and extra
doses should be left at daycare facilities and schools. All caregivers
should be comfortable giving an epi-pen injection and this should be
provided at the first sign of a systemic allergic reaction. Waiting to
give diphenhydramine or other therapies a "chance to work" can be
dangerous. Follow a <a href="http://www.foodallergy.org/files/media/food-allergy-action-plan/FAAP.pdf">Food Allergy Action
Plan</a>
Over 80% of people who died from allergic reactions were not given
appropriate instructions on how to prevent future reactions. Most
mortality occurs because of late treatment. If you take one thing away
from this long post, keep an epi-pen handy and use it liberally.</p>

<p>Trials are underway investigating various oral-based immunotherapies,
but none are strongly recommended at this point. Injection
immunotherapy has not been found to be useful.</p>

<h2>Personal Comment</h2>

<p>So, the 22 month old above is Anika and she gave us the scare of our
life a couple years ago. The scary part now is that we never saw her
actually eat a peanut, so we're especially vigilant now. Fortunately,
Anika seems to understand the importance of avoiding peanuts. When she
was diagnosed, I did some research but never documented my notes. She
recently had another allergist appointment, so I reviewed those notes
and any new data. I figured I should write up my notes so I wouldn't
have to review this again from scratch every year. I didn't intend it
to come out so 'medical-speaky', but there it is. Anika and Kavi are
sitting next to me as I write this and they want to give some
information to you, too.</p>

<p>Kavi says:</p>

<blockquote><p>"Always ask at the restaurant if things have peanuts and make foods
at home that do not have peanuts. Always check if there are peanuts in
every food you eat."</p></blockquote>

<p>Anika says:</p>

<blockquote><p>"We might have to go to the doctor if we eat peanuts. If I eat
peanuts by accident, my teacher will give me a Happy-Pen (epi-pen)."</p></blockquote>

<h2>References</h2>

<ol>
<li>Sampson HA. Peanut Allergy. N Engl J Med, 2002;346;1294-8.
http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMcp012667</li>
<li>Fleischer DM, et. al. The natural progression of peanut allergy:
Resolution and the possibility of recurrence. J Allergy Clin
Immunol, 2003;112;183-9.
http://www.jacionline.org/article/S0091-6749(03)01251-X/abstract</li>
<li>O'B Hourihane J. Peanut Allergy. Pediatr Clin N Am, 2011;58;445-57.
http://www.pediatric.theclinics.com/article/S0031-3955(11)00006-X/abstract</li>
<li>Rinaldi M, et. al. Peanut allergy diagnoses among children
residing in Olmstead County, Minnesota. J Allergy Clin Immunol, 2012:130:945-50.</li>
<li>Burks AW. Early peanut consumption: postpone or promote? J Allergy
Clin Immunol. 2009:123:417-423.
http://www.jacionline.org/article/S0091-6749(08)02436-6/fulltext</li>
</ol>


<h2>RSS URL:</h2>

<p>Here's a
<a href="http://eutils.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/eutils/erss.cgi?rss_guid=1t7jLQ--MCbUSbgzXRNqEMLPWIMWlZiqoEMdLvUTNUIFZ-UsA4">medline feed URL</a>
that I monitor which should show new studies or reviews related to
this topic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Avik Arrives!]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/09/04/avik-arrives"/>
    <updated>2012-09-04T08:30:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/09/04/avik-arrives</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Anika, Kavi, Mala and I are so proud to announce the birth of healthy, happy baby boy!</p>

<p>His name is Avik Puri Kurup and he was born at 11:01 PM on September
3rd, 2012. He is 6lbs, 12oz and about 19 inches long.</p>

<p>A few pics:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/avik-1.jpg" width="1024" alt="Avik" /><br/>
<img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/avik-2.jpg" width="768" height="1024" alt="Avik" /></p>

<p>And the obligatory pseudo-nostalgic photo:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/avik-3.jpg" height="1024" width="768" alt="Avik" /></p>

<p>Mom and Baby are doing great! Thanks for all the well wishes and support!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surprise, I'm 40!]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/09/06/surprise-im-40"/>
    <updated>2011-09-06T14:01:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/09/06/surprise-im-40</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/vinod40-1.jpg" title="Vinod is surprised" ></p>

<p>Have you ever been in one of those dreams where everything seems
normal and then a flying car (or something equally crazy) comes out of
nowhere? I'm used to having experiences like that when I'm dreaming,
but it was quite surreal to have it during waking hours.</p>

<p>Mala and Kavi had gone ahead (surreptiously to plan a surprise party
for someone else!). We were to meet at the ferris wheel at the Navy
Pier. I found her and she took my hand. She started leading me through
the crowds of tourists. I could sense excitement in her demeanor, but
didn't think anything of it. She led me towards a group of people and
I caught a glimpse of someone who looked like my Dad. That's
weird... why would he be here? It's at that point that neurons started
to malfunction and I began to feel like I was in a dream. Then I saw
Mala's mom and got even more confused. Slowly the group of strangers
came into focus and revealed themselves as my friends and family from
around the country. It was, without a doubt, the best birthday present
that I have ever received, or expect to receive. Thanks to Mala for
months of planning, and for wanting to make me feel special even
though I feel this way every day when I wake up next to her. Thanks to
all my friends and family who could make it and to the ones who
couldn't. If this is the culmination of 40 years on this earth, I
can't wait for the next 40!</p>

<p><img src="/images/vinod40-2.jpg" title="Vinod is 40" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daivame Kaithozham]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/07/20/daivame"/>
    <updated>2011-07-20T19:15:29-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/07/20/daivame</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever since I was a boy, I have been singing a song called 'Daivame
Kaithozham', which is pronounced 'Dave-O-May Kie-Tho-Ram'. My parents
taught it to me when I was about 5 years old, so I learned it by
learning the syllables in the song. I know bits and pieces of
Malayalam, but not enough to know what the words of the song
mean. Whenever I'm feeling stressed, I sing it under my breath and it
makes me feel better. Kavi wasn't the best sleeper as a baby, so we
spent a lot of time singing him back to sleep. Daivame Kaithozham was
one of my standbys and he has heard it literally thousands of
times. Even now, I sing it to him and Anika almost daily, though he
has requested that I cut it down to weekly. (He likes Laurie Berkner's
"Moon, moon, moon" better. Oh well.) Both Anika and Kavi have heard it
enough that they can mimic me singing it, though they don't know the
words...  mostly just the rhythm. But, it's the cutest thing in the
world to see Anika pick up her doll, put it on the floor and start
singing "Daivame..."</p>

<p>Anyway, I finally (after 30 something years) asked my parents what the
song means, so here is the translation. I'm not the most religious
person in the world, but if you replace God with whatever supernatural
force you believe in, I think it's a nice simple prayer.</p>

<h2>Daivame Kaithozham</h2>

<p>   Daivame kaithozham kelkumarakanam <br />
   Pavamamenne nee kakkumarakanam <br />
   Ennullil bhaktiyundakumarakanam <br />
   Ninne jnanennume kanumarakanam <br /></p>

<p>   Nervazhikkenne nee kondupoyeedanam <br />
   Nervarum sankadam bhasmamayeedanam <br />
   Dushtasamsargam varatheyayeedanam <br />
   Shishtarayullavar thozharayeedanam <br /></p>

<p>   Nalla karyangalil premamundakanam <br />
   Nalla vakkothuvan thraniyundakanam <br />
   Kruthyangal cheyyuvan sradhayundakanam <br />
   Satyam paranjeedan saktiyundakana <br /></p>

<h2>Translated</h2>

<p>   O’Almighty God my humble salutation, may you kindly listen to my prayers <br />
   May you always protect this poor innocent one from all my sufferings. <br />
   May my devotion to you flourish in my heart without any interruptions <br />
   May I always visualize your eternal divine form within and without. <br /></p>

<p>   O’ God lead me through the right path  <br />
   Annihilate all obstructions facing me  <br />
   And protect me from evil interactions <br />
   Provide me with serene and sober friends. <br /></p>

<p>   May I always impart compassion and love to all <br />
   O’ Lord provide me courage to talk only good words <br />
   May I be provided with the right convictions to do my duties <br />
   And give me your blessed strength to tell always the truth alone. <br /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boston with little kids]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/06/30/boston-with-little-kids"/>
    <updated>2011-06-30T11:50:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2011/06/30/boston-with-little-kids</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm sorry, but I just can't believe it's been almost 10 years since I
left Boston. Mala had a meeting there and we love to take advantage of
our employers' generosity <a href="Makes">^1</a>, so I TrippedIt <a href="Is">^2</a> back to Boston for
some nostalgia with 2 kids in tow (Ages 4 and 2). Buildings and
restaurants have come and gone <a href="Where">^3</a>, but it seems like so little has
changed in 10+ years. I forgot how "unfriendly" the city was. The trip
was a few weeks ago, so it's not fresh in my mind anymore, but I
remember thinking that vividly while I was there. You get the sense
that everyone has their shields up (or their guns drawn, to mix
metaphors) for whatever reason. None of the experiences were horrible,
but it was little things... Bathrooms are "broken" in every fast food
restaurant. Restaurants have arcane rules: "No, we only do takeout
after 3PM" or "Cash Only - there's an ATM over there". Customer
service people must be groomed to be rude. We're members of the
(AWESOME!)  <a href="http://www.ncmls.org/">Durham Museum of Life and Science</a>
which gives us free entry to science museums around the country, so we
walked up to the Members desk at Boston's version (Museum of Science)
and promptly got lectured about how we weren't really members and next
time we should go in the Nonmembers line. (Um, we're visiting from
North Carolina... there's probably not going to be a next time anytime
soon). I actually turned around and looked at all of the people behind
me and apologized for our rudeness. Wait! There was no one else
waiting! Just makes you feel small, which burns me up, because I know
that was her objective. I know none of that seems all that bad, but
that general attitude seemed prevalent and brought back memories of
Boston that I had repressed. We all had a great time in Boston, but I
am so glad that I'm living in North Carolina.</p>

<p>Wow, that little interlude took me from excited to depressed in no
time flat. Enough of that. Let's talk about the fun stuff we did. We
always research on the web to get a sense of things Kavi and Anika
might like. I had trouble finding good first-person stories about
<strong>Boston trips with little kids</strong>, so here's mine, in case someone has 2
kids exactly like ours. If this is useful, or if you have stuff to
add, please leave a comment or point to your blog.</p>

<h3>Things the kids loved:</h3>

<ul>
<li>Being in Boston: "We're in BOSTON!"</li>
<li>Walking the streets and seeing all kinds of vehicles: Taxis, buses,
trolleys, Ducks, police cars, and most excitingly, Minivans!.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/74NPRUFqKCQ7b1UdhOcphw?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-udiiy9uwK0I/Tf_Cs_JZjSI/AAAAAAAAStM/idfT4DGvVIg/s400/IMG_1819.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.marybakereddylibrary.org/exhibits/mapparium">Mapparium</a> at Mary Baker Eddy Library:
Kavi talked about this a lot for the rest of the trip, but at the
time didn't seem all that impressed by it. He was intrigued by the
fact that I wasn't allowed to take pictures inside it. He also liked
the Hall of Ideas and the computerized art programs upstairs.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bostoncentral.com/activities/parks/p2055.php">Boston Common Carousel</a>:
It's a carousel. Of course they loved it!
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/m-xAmdHOY3Oj7RLV7GqrfQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-VHxkS2HOz98/Tf_CIWq5aBI/AAAAAAAASn0/4OkxOELTRkM/s400/IMG_1565.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.swanboats.com/">Swan boats</a>:
Definitely a must-do. It's short and sweet.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/b3pFVNPd_qZN9f2aAxkOMg?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-fr-r42kU5Jk/Tf_CPpJ_PLI/AAAAAAAASo8/sShUbKnk9ak/s400/IMG_1633.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.schon.com/public/ducklings-boston.php">Ducklings in the Garden</a>:
Dressed in Bruins outfits while we were there. Those poor ducks were
constantly surrounded by little ones.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/gzG8lLrumqPoaaDWT89pCQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-JXMBbVQC5ss/Tf_B6IyTv-I/AAAAAAAASl4/EYX2c4gS4vI/s400/IMG_1483.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li>Boston Commons and Garden:
There's plenty of stuff for the kids to see and do here, but they're not so big that you'll get lost (think Central Park).
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/mAwQUzWgDQJEPExhJnUA4A?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Rdh48Xnk-14/Tf_CcSdfDBI/AAAAAAAASqY/29JAz9fhlcA/s400/IMG_1705.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://gocitykids.parentsconnect.com/attraction/boston-common-playground-boston-common-boston-ma-02111-us">Boston Commons Playground</a>:
Every parent on a trip knows that step one is finding all the local
playgrounds. This is a nice one and was close to the hotel. That
meets all the necessary requirements. By the way, while putting this
post together, I found this nice listing of <a href="http://gocitykids.parentsconnect.com/sub-category/boston-ma-usa/places-to-go/outdoors/playgrounds">playgrounds in Boston</a>.</li>
<li>Playground on Tremont:
We found a much smaller playground between the Hotel and NEMC that
Kavi and Anika liked a little better, mostly because they had it all
to themselves.</li>
<li>Playgrounds on the Charles River:
Take the bridge over to the Hatch shell, go left (west) and walk for
about half a mile. Nestled between Storrow Drive and the Charles
River, there's plenty to watch and play with. Kavi and Anika really
liked the little car. Oh, and if you happen to go right (east)
instead of left, there's a great playground near the tennis
courts, which is on the way to the Museum of Science. <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/VU9ZILbVTM3WjUQf8ewOVA?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ZyXEp8eIv8E/Tf_CXQ8c-II/AAAAAAAASp0/RwBruXMUjrI/s400/IMG_1675.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hatchshell.com/">Hatch shell</a>:
There was an AIDS race while we were there which meant lots of people and
balloons to keep the kids occupied. I heard it gets crazy on July
4th :-)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mos.org/">Museum of Science</a>:
Aside from the annoying registration employee, this was fun. The
<a href="http://www.mos.org/exhibits_shows/current_exhibits&amp;d=233">Discovery
Center</a>
didn't open for an hour, so we explored the regular museum
first. Most of it was above Kavi and Anika's age level, so they were
getting bored/overwhelmed. The Discovery Center was better, though we
didn't find the best part (the upstairs level) until near the end of
our stay. Kavi's favorite thing was watching the pneumatic tube
system. The volunteers up there were really engaging as well. <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/6tj5VGYyO33R1oOoJJII2A?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-92-8sBu_bEI/Tf_CxW7oNaI/AAAAAAAASuI/0kfvbLMTSvo/s400/IMG_1864.JPG" height="400" width="300" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bostonkids.org/exhibits.html">Children's Museum</a>:
The museum with the "rabbit sitting on top" and the big milk
bottle on the side. Predictably loved by Kavi and Anika.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.neaq.org">New England Aquarium</a>:
The kids were underwhelmed. They liked the
<a href="http://www.vanaqua.org/">Vancouver</a> and
<a href="http://www.georgiaaquarium.org/">Atlanta</a> ones more. We spent most
of our time in the toddler area playing with toys that are normally
found in doctors' waiting rooms. I think they'll love this in a
couple years. <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/UloiGxYpoMj-eJQ62shPrQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-GfsPi7jlpUE/Tf_BztUhHBI/AAAAAAAASlU/-iCxRKEUIMs/s400/IMG_1451.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://mbta.com">The T</a>:
We could have just ridden the T every day. It was loud, which freaks
Kavi out a bit, but not as loud as New York. We rode on the blue
line to get to the aquarium, and the Green line to come back to the
Hotel. He especially liked the Green line because the "floor turns". <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/a6oatS480Dl82Cs8vM6KXA?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-HmXUq5s0sK4/Tf_BywQN-kI/AAAAAAAASlM/eIse1aEcfhE/s400/IMG_1439.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bostonparkplaza.com/">Park Plaza</a>:
A decent hotel. Living mostly on reputation and location. I guess
we've been spoiled by modern hotels in other cities, so the Park
Plaza seemed dingy and overpriced. But the location is awesome, work was
paying for it, and our kids love any hotels, so I recommend it.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Dining:</h3>

<ul>
<li>Vapiano (pseudo-italian restaurant where Bennigan's used to be):
The kids liked their pastas and like sitting at the little tables.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.jaescafe.com/">Jae's Cafe</a>:
Not really a kids thing, but we went early on a weeknight and had a
really nice dinner. They have "training" chopsticks that the kids loved.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/-NPr0GAaytlcornbA7v9vg?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-wts4MU8llwA/Tf_Cgcrx0AI/AAAAAAAASrA/CUFx_h9mQdY/s400/IMG_1732.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mikescitydiner.com/">Mike's City Diner</a>: (Ouch, Flashy website)
Our first breakfast stop and we returned a few days later which is a
huge endorsement. Avoid it on weekends though, because it's
packed. Cash only. <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/HSbAj63Z9vcSgMhKWbkVmQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-MF8LJX6QkDM/Tf_B846X18I/AAAAAAAASmQ/ad_LUNxHneQ/s288/IMG_1505.JPG" height="216" width="288" /></a>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/RLS9xJP1S4jbCwxFC6m7JQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-ho4QA_1CRz8/Tf_B9yDYPgI/AAAAAAAASmY/q8qI5CTVJbs/s288/IMG_1506.JPG" height="216" width="288" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/charlies-sandwich-shoppe-boston">Charlie's Sandwich Shoppe</a>:
Another great breakfast place. We went on Kavi's birthday and were
just about the only ones in the restaurant, so the entire staff sang
Happy Birthday and put a candle on his pancake. He was so
thrilled. Cash only.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/gjT3uIvumJMC2YNhJRXzpg?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-zox0d2diKaM/Tf_Ckj9fGrI/AAAAAAAASr0/eBk3nvUaKUM/s400/IMG_1747.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li>Legal Seafood:
Quick dinner after arriving from the airport. Not the most kid
friendly place, but aside from a long wait, it was fine.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/oDgdkVHgyvxeagZs3GIhjw?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-4XoWN5kwIzE/Tf_BvZu_TVI/AAAAAAAASks/gPpBjKpnWoc/s400/IMG_1421.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li>Dunkin Donuts:
Nostalgic coffee and donuts, but NO BATHROOMS!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/asian-garden-boston">Asian Garden</a>:
The best salt &amp; pepper squid that I have ever had. Still as good as
I remember it 15 years ago! <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/bUxOVG-Gxd9RUfydEzit9Q?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-7kdUE3ux_Uc/Tf_B8KQJ1sI/AAAAAAAASmI/GDK1-ESwPxY/s400/IMG_1500.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li>Dim Sum at <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/hei-la-moon-boston">Hei La Moon</a>:
Mala was at her meeting, Anika was asleep and Kavi was sick, so only
I got to enjoy this luxury.
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/4LTUcmjuT_01BGLu-dXjzg?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-nob5EC9E9kk/Tf_Ce-ukRXI/AAAAAAAASqw/WiNBBq-RoJ0/s400/IMG_1722.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li>North End (Boston's Little Italy):
We went to visit Mala's friends and had great take out. The walk
from the Park Plaza was nice, since it crossed the Garden, the
government center area and the North End, all of which had sights
that the kids enjoyed</li>
<li><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/croissant-du-jour-boston">Croissant Du Jour</a>:
Great breakfast food and sandwiches.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.finaledesserts.com/">Finale</a>:
We went here for Kavi's birthday dessert. Nowhere near as good as I
remember it being, but that might be because Mala is just an amazing
cook, so my standards have risen. <br>
<a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/yagEwh3QcBswOTq0D_O1ZQ?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-M2Kx1_dLj0k/Tf_CwshBY8I/AAAAAAAASuA/y3DDBygZ1pU/s400/IMG_1835.JPG" height="300" width="400" /></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.parishcafe.com/index2.html">Parish Cafe</a>:
Sandwiches are awesome! We went there on Monday, which is the day
that we eat only veggies, so I couldn't try the Regis that I used to
love. The bread, though, was enough to satisfy my cravings. Sit
outside and the kids will be entertained by the constant traffic and
activity on Boylston Street.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Useful Android Apps:</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.yelp.android">Yelp</a>:
I downloaded a bunch of other ones including AAA Triptik, Tripadvisor,
HopStop, but I ended up using Yelp and Google Maps predominantly.</li>
<li><a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.tripit">TripIt</a>:
Not specific to Boston, but this app makes traveling easier. Keeps
track of all your flight info, hotel info and any other itinerary info
you want to stick into it.</li>
</ul>


<p>End result of the trip: Success!</p>

<p><a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/U9oMp1w9fSAl3RoGhwZWmA?feat=embedwebsite"><img class="inset" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-m4RatvhjowA/Tf_Cfk0LnQI/AAAAAAAASq4/8ChBYs5WBCo/s640/IMG_1724.JPG" height="480" width="640" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
