<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blackout | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/blackout/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-09T07:01:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let there be light!]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/08/16/let-there-be-light"/>
    <updated>2003-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/08/16/let-there-be-light</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The power finally came back on at around 7:20 PM tonight. I was
sitting on my futon trying as hard as I could not to sweat, when I
heard a loud cheer from the courtyard and saw that the lights had gone
on in the apartments outside my window.</p>

<p>It's been a weird couple of days. The power went out around 4:15 PM
yesterday while I was looking up some labs in the preceptor's
room. The A/C had been on full-blast, so we all thought that it was
just an overloaded circuit, but soon we got word that nearby buildings
were affected and everyone went smoothly into disaster-mode. Take care
of any urgent patient needs and encourage everyone else to go home. No
staff leaves until we know what's going on. Around 6:30, we got the
word that whoever was within walking distance could go home, provided
that they be back first thing in the morning. I figured 4 miles is
walking-distance, so I left. From the 80's to around 63rd St, 2nd
Avenue was packed with cars trying in vain to get to the Queensboro
bridge. Traffic lights were off, but it didn't seem to matter since
the cars weren't moving anyway. Civilians were trying to direct
traffic with varying success. The cars obeyed, but pedestrians were on
their own schedule. From the Queensboro down to the 40's, pedestrians
replaced the cars and swarmed over the street.</p>

<p>I got to my neighborhood around 8ish. Most of the local shops were out
of flashlights and running low on water. I swear the people at the
counter were just making up prices as they went along, but no one
really seemed to care. After getting settled at home, I went for a
short walk outside around 10PM. I was shocked at how dark New York was
without any lights. You could clearly see the stars in the sky. It was
dangerous to walk around without a flashlight because there would be
people just sitting on the sidewalk waiting to be tripped over.</p>

<p>But everything is back to normal now and the only casualty is my <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uptime">uptime</a></p>

<h1>Update:</h1>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.globalsecurity.org/eye/blackout_2003.htm">Satellite pics</a> via <a href="http://badgertronics.com/blog">Badgertronics</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.quicktopic.com/23/H/JwZLefNGAwM8/p-1.-1">Lots of more interesting stories</a> via <a href="http://boingboing.net/">BoingBoing</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
