<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book-review on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/book-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book-review on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 12:01:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Free Will</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/21/thoughts-on-free-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 12:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2012/08/21/thoughts-on-free-will/</guid>
      <description>Time for some pop philosophy. I&amp;rsquo;ve never thought too deeply about the concept of free will. Of course we have free will! I chose to live my life a certain way. I could choose to live a different way. It is my free will to choose how I live. I&amp;rsquo;ve never thought about it more deeply than that.
I recently read Walter Isaacson&amp;rsquo;s biography of Einstein and I was forced to think more deeply about free will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Get Fat Review</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/12/why-we-get-fat-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 12:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/08/12/why-we-get-fat-review/</guid>
      <description>Dear patients,
 Why We Get Fat  I am sorry. I have been giving you bad dietary advice. In medical school we learned that fat in your diet causes fat to accumulate in your arteries, causing heart attacks and strokes, so I told you to eat a low fat diet. Of course, looking back, we had no evidence to support that conclusion, but it just seemed rather obvious. Obvious ideas are often the most dangerous ideas of all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything You Want Review</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/07/04/anything-you-want-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 21:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/07/04/anything-you-want-review/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I keep reading books about entrepreneurship. I like the idea of building a business, having passion for something, and most importantly, living life on your own terms. I just don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m cut out for it. But see if that will stop me from devouring Hacker News, startup podcasts and books like Derek Sivers&amp;rsquo; Anything You Want.
Derek was a musician who started selling his own CDs online in the days before Paypal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Android Review</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/08/learning-android-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 22:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/08/learning-android-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished reading Learning Android. I have a Droid X, Mala has a Droid Eris, and I just bought a Viewsonic g-tablet, so I have plenty of Android devices. While I still have trouble with the idea of typing on a touchscreen, I know that we are moving towards a future where mobile devices are our primary computers. This is not earth shattering. Philip Greenspun mentioned it 5 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing a Business</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/07/growing-a-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 20:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/11/07/growing-a-business/</guid>
      <description>I read this book in 2005, but never posted this review. So here it is&amp;hellip;
Growing a Business by Paul Hawken This is an honest and practical guide to running a business. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember where I first heard about this book. Maybe Lars?
It was written in 1987. Hawken talks about building a business. It&amp;rsquo;s often portrayed as a heroic or glamorous endeavor, but really it&amp;rsquo;s not. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of hard work, but also a lot of common sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 Up and Running</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/25/html5-up-and-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/25/html5-up-and-running/</guid>
      <description>I preordered Mark Pilgrim&amp;rsquo;s HTML5, Up and Running from Amazon back in March. It&amp;rsquo;s available for free as Dive into HTML5. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of Mark&amp;rsquo;s writing for a while, so buying the book was a way to thank him &amp;ldquo;with a buck&amp;rdquo;. Interestingly, the online book and paper book are not identical. For starters, the titles are different. In addition, the beautiful fonts and cutesy images of the online version are gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flow</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/23/flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2009/07/23/flow/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found some old journal entries lying around my hard drive. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that these were meant to be cleaned up and edited before being spewed on the Internet, but in keeping with my newfound obsession with Imperfection, I now present them to you, my dear reader(s). Here is the first one, a review of the book, Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience
Bronx, NY, April 9th, 2007
I finished &amp;ldquo;Flow, The Psychology of Optimal Experience&amp;rdquo; by Mihaly Csikszenthmihalyi on the subway ride into work today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Survival</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/04/15/deep-survival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/04/15/deep-survival/</guid>
      <description>If you go on adventure trips, you should read &amp;ldquo;Deep Survival&amp;rdquo;, by Laurence Gonzales. I finished it on my marathon subway rides yesterday. It&amp;rsquo;s partly a voyeuristic look into how people do or don&amp;rsquo;t survive when bad things happen. This part is pure storytelling and who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love a good story? At times, the outdoorsy jargon made it hard for me to follow what exactly was going on, but on the whole I was sucked in, turning pages to see what happened to our poor characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literature delivered to your inbox</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/03/19/literature-delivered-to-your-inbox/</guid>
      <description>DailyLit.com is an interesting service that takes classic books and chops them up in to bite-sized pieces that you can read in just a few minutes. It then emails you one piece at a time until you finish the book. You can customize how often you get the emails.
I just finished &amp;ldquo;The Art of Money Getting&amp;rdquo;, by P.T. Barnum. It has a lot of practical advice, and predates (by 100 years) a lot of what you see these days in self-help books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Errata for Quick Calculus</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/11/errata-for-quick-calculus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/12/11/errata-for-quick-calculus/</guid>
      <description>I just read Quick Calculus: A Self-Teaching Guide, 2nd Edition by Daniel Kleppner and Norman Ramsey. I found a few errors, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find an errata listing online, so I&amp;rsquo;m documenting them here for future reference.
 Page 107, Frame 206. The quotient rule as it&amp;rsquo;s initially expressed is incorrect. The correct version is stated at the bottom of the page and also on page 102, Frame 194.
 Page 173, Frame 330.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>