<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>medicine on Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://kurup.org/categories/medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in medicine on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 07:49:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kurup.org/categories/medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Peanut Allergy, a personal clinical review</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/21/peanut-allergy-a-personal-clinical-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 07:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2013/01/21/peanut-allergy-a-personal-clinical-review/</guid>
      <description>A Vignette A 22-month-old previously healthy girl was brought to the emergency room in respiratory distress. She had been well until the day of presentation. Shortly after disembarking from an airline flight, she developed cough with one episode of emesis. En route to the emergency room, her breathing became labored and she developed hives. She was diagnosed as having an allergic reaction and treated aggressively with IV methylprednisolone, IV diphenhydramine, inhaled albuterol, and oxygen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHM 2011</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/13/shm-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 05:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/05/13/shm-2011/</guid>
      <description>Here are some (unorganized) thoughts about my experience at the Society of Hospital Medicine (SHM) 2011 conference in Dallas, TX.
Opening Plenary The initial presentation dissected the SHM Annual Compensation survey, discussing regional variations in pay and work effort over time. I understand the importance of that stuff, but ever since I got my first $638.36 paycheck as an intern, money hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an issue for me.
The second talk was by Bob Kocher, an Obama insider during the recent healthcare reformd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Student Oral Presentations</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/18/medical-student-oral-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 14:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/18/medical-student-oral-presentations/</guid>
      <description>I enjoyed @FutureDocs&amp;lsquo; guide to medical student oral presentations, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share the cheat sheet that I give to the medical students and PA students when I start each teaching block. As she mentioned, presentations always have to be tailored to the listener, and each attending is different, so you&amp;rsquo;ll see minor differences in what I recommend.
To me, the most important aspects are organization and preparation. I don&amp;rsquo;t like to have the sense that the student is &amp;ldquo;winging it&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Watson</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/17/dr.-watson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 19:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/17/dr.-watson/</guid>
      <description>All I could think of while watching the news about the supercomputer Watson beating humans at Jeopardy was how this could be used in medicine. Looks like I&amp;rsquo;m not alone.
Time to start looking for a new job?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspirin for everyone</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/16/aspirin-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 21:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2011/02/16/aspirin-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Aspirin is one of those wonder drugs - simple, cheap and effective versus so many deadly diseases. We know that aspirin prevents heart attacks and strokes, especially if you&amp;rsquo;ve had one before. There is also some data that it prevents colon cancers, but it was thought that this effect was only seen when using high doses of aspirin. The downside of aspirin is that it increases your risk of bleeding, especially gastrointestinal bleeding (usually from stomach ulcers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primary Care Doctors</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/06/primary-care-doctors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/08/06/primary-care-doctors/</guid>
      <description>I used to be a primary care physician, but switched to being a hospitalist in 2007. I loved parts about being a PCP, namely the relationship that I developed with the patient over many years. I miss that. I think PCPs offer huge value in providing low cost, quality care, especially if they can stay engaged throughout the hospitalization process. Atul Gawande recently wrote a powerful article on the Hospice system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospitalist Notes 1</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/29/hospitalist-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2010/07/29/hospitalist-notes-1/</guid>
      <description>My last night shift was a little less busy than most, so I forced myself to pick something about each patient I admitted and look it up. I tend to do this anyway, but I never keep notes or write about it. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I wrote about that night:
Does Buspar (buspirone) need to be tapered? Answer: No. The full report on Micromedex was a little conflicting, because it stated that there may be some withdrawal symptoms from Buspar, but this quote in the same profile suggests otherwise:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting again</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/13/starting-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2008/12/13/starting-again/</guid>
      <description>For the remaining 2 readers of kurup.org (one of them being me), let me apologize for the lack of posts here over the past couple years. I have always meant to write more, but most of my writing seems to consist of apologies for not writing, short bursts of writing, and then long stretches of inactivity. We are nearing the end of a long stretch of inactivity now, so it&amp;rsquo;s time for the apologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Update</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2007/05/27/life-update/</guid>
      <description>Once again, I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen behind on my life updates, so let&amp;rsquo;s get caught up.
 Mala&amp;rsquo;s pregnancy is going well, at least from the husband&amp;rsquo;s point of view. She&amp;rsquo;s due June 15th. We drove to Orlando for my CME conference because Delta cancelled our flight. It turned out to be a nice thing because we got to see Puja, Ethan and Loki on the way down and we got to stop in Charleston, SC on the way back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google, M.D.</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/27/google-m.d./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/27/google-m.d./</guid>
      <description>I remember telling people at a dinner party that I often entered symptoms into Google to help me diagnose patients. I remember them being apalled.
Turns out that Google is pretty accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Length of therapy with bisphosphonates</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/27/length-of-therapy-with-bisphosphonates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/27/length-of-therapy-with-bisphosphonates/</guid>
      <description>Sorry for another post linking to Journal Watch, but they really are doing a great job of reading my mind&amp;hellip;
In my talk to the residents about osteoporosis, I mentioned that one of the unanswered questions is how long to treat patients with bisphosphonates. Well, a randomized trial published in JAMA says &amp;ldquo;5 years&amp;rdquo;. Bone density in placebo-users decreased minimally and hip fracture risk stayed the same. Vertebral fracture risk increased, but vertebral fractures are much less significant than hip fractures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osteoporosis Talk</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/24/osteoporosis-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/12/24/osteoporosis-talk/</guid>
      <description>I gave the residents a talk on osteoporosis at noon conference on Friday. Here&amp;rsquo;s the powerpoint slides that I created, in case they might be useful to anyone. They&amp;rsquo;re licensed under a Creative Commons license and available in 2 formats - ODP (good) and PPT (bad).
Medical information changes constantly, so hopefully these will be useful until at least the end of 2006. I&amp;rsquo;ve also uploaded slides from previous talks on Abnormal Liver Function Tests and Adult Immunizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health at every size</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/10/23/health-at-every-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/10/23/health-at-every-size/</guid>
      <description>I read this article on &amp;ldquo;Health at Every Size&amp;rdquo; back in July 2005, took some notes and then put it in my &amp;ldquo;To Blog About&amp;rdquo; Folder. In the &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll get to it &amp;hellip; eventually&amp;rdquo; category, here are my notes from 16 months ago:
Here&amp;rsquo;s a really interesting take on the problem of obesity. The movement is called &amp;ldquo;Health at every size&amp;rdquo;. Proponents argue that society and the medical establishment is too concerned with getting people to lose weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Primary Care Dying?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/is-primary-care-dying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/09/09/is-primary-care-dying/</guid>
      <description>Dave referenced an interesting article in the NEJM titled &amp;ldquo;Primary Care &amp;ndash; Will it Survive?&amp;rdquo; These two quotes summarize the problem:
 A 2006 report from the Center for Studying Health System Change reveals that from 1995 to 2003, inflation-adjusted income decreased by 7.1 percent for all physicians and by 10.2 percent for primary care physicians.
 and
 It has been estimated that it would take 10.6 hours per working day to deliver all recommended care for patients with chronic conditions, plus 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurrent DVT</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/07/25/recurrent-dvt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/07/25/recurrent-dvt/</guid>
      <description>The duration of treatment for a deep venous thrombosis (DVT) is problematic. Most patients who have one will never have another one, yet those who do have a 5% risk of death due to their recurrent DVT. We need a simple test which separates one group from the other.
This weeks JAMA (no link as issue is not online yet) reports on an article claiming that thrombin generation may be that test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doc on Board</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/06/12/doc-on-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2006/06/12/doc-on-board/</guid>
      <description>Stop what you&amp;rsquo;re doing and go buy the July 2006 issue of Runner&amp;rsquo;s World. Flip to page 49 and read the fine article by Scott Douglas on things a runner should discuss with their physician.
Yep, the &amp;ldquo;Vinod Kurup&amp;rdquo; quoted is yours truly! I&amp;rsquo;m really grateful to Scott for using me as a source and thus making my dream of being in Runner&amp;rsquo;s World come true. :)
Here&amp;rsquo;s the online version of the article, but go check out the magazine because it&amp;rsquo;s, you know, much cooler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospitalist Handbook</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/22/hospitalist-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/08/22/hospitalist-handbook/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a clear, concise handbook for Hospitalist Medicine, check out the UCSF Hospitalist Handbook, available free online. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s up-to-date (the copyright notice states 2002), but it still seems relevant and useful. And I&amp;rsquo;m not just saying that because my cousin Deepu Nair wrote the Night Calls section.
Comments from old site You read my mind
 Vin you read my mind I have been waiting for a handbook on hospitalist medicine, thank you so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Guideline Clearinghouse</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/07/national-guideline-clearinghouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/07/national-guideline-clearinghouse/</guid>
      <description>I subscribe to the National Guideline Clearinghouse&amp;rsquo;s (NGC) email alert service. Sponsored by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, the NGC is a database of clinical guidelines from numerous sources. Sign up for their alert service to receive email whenever a guideline is added or changed.
It&amp;rsquo;s the first place I look when I want to find an evidence-based approach to a problem. Clinical practice guidelines are helpful, but they have problems, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of anemia with diastolic dysfunction among patients with coronary artery disease in the Heart and Soul Study</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/02/association-of-anemia-with-diastolic-dysfunction-among-patients-with-coronary-artery-disease-in-the-heart-and-soul-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2005/02/02/association-of-anemia-with-diastolic-dysfunction-among-patients-with-coronary-artery-disease-in-the-heart-and-soul-study/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to my cousin Deepu for getting published in the American Journal of Cardiology.
He found a strong association between anemia and diastolic dysfunction in patients with coronary disease. Diastolic dysfunction is a condition in which a patient has clinical signs of heart failure, but a normal left ventricular systolic function. So, for some reason, the heart is pumping vigorously, but fluid is still backing up (into the legs or into the lungs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>phew - not on this list</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/17/phew-not-on-this-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/09/17/phew-not-on-this-list/</guid>
      <description>The Worst Jobs in Science via badgertronics
The next time an intern complains to me about their job, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna say, &amp;ldquo;Yeah, you&amp;rsquo;re right, but read this!&amp;rdquo; :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>annual waste of time?</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/13/annual-waste-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/13/annual-waste-of-time/</guid>
      <description>Another interesting article in the Times today. Lo and behold, the annual physical exam is useless. Shocking, huh? Well, no - not really. The first questions about the annual physical cropped up 20 years ago and recent studies have only confirmed these initial doubts.
So, do I perform annual physicals? Yup. Why? A few reasons&amp;hellip;. As a relatively young doc, I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to examine LOTS and LOTS of normal patients in order to get a firm sense of what&amp;rsquo;s normal and what&amp;rsquo;s abnormal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASD</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/01/asd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2003/08/01/asd/</guid>
      <description>A young guy came in as a walk-in with some mild shortness of breath on exertion and associated chest pain. He was the last patient that I saw during a long, busy day and his symptoms were very mild. I was thinking that maybe he had mild asthma or a respiratory infection, but he didn&amp;rsquo;t look sick at all. Then I listened to his heart. A loud holosystolic murmur throughout with a fixed split S2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Medicine</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/24/open-source-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/11/24/open-source-medicine/</guid>
      <description>I wrote up a little intro piece on the use of open source software in medical applications (PDF). HTML below&amp;hellip;
Improving the communication of patient information is the key to improving healthcare quality and efficiency. In most health care organizations, written records are the main conduit of this information, yet they are notoriously illegible and difficult to browse. Reviewing past problems and past interventions is time-consuming, if not impossible. The record is used mostly as a one-way device for the clinician to record data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delay</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/06/20/delay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/2002/06/20/delay/</guid>
      <description>OK, OK&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s been way too long since I&amp;rsquo;ve updated this page. I just moved to Manhattan to take a job as an internist at Metropolitan Hospital. I&amp;rsquo;ve got pics from a mini-residency-reunion as well as an awesome trip to the Grand Canyon that I need to put up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Massachusetts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/12/06/back-to-massachusetts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/12/06/back-to-massachusetts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started a new rotation in at a chronic rehab hospital in Waltham, Massachusetts. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a different pace from any other work I&amp;rsquo;ve done before. I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning a lot about bed sores and tube feeding!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medicalrecords.com</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/12/06/medicalrecords.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/12/06/medicalrecords.com/</guid>
      <description>An opportunity arose that I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass up. I&amp;rsquo;ve been offered a position with an internet startup company. The company is medicalrecords.com and is focused on providing a place for patients to store their own medical records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night shifts</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/09/14/night-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/09/14/night-shifts/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be here in Green Bay for a little while longer, probably until Thanksgiving. So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working mostly night shifts, bringing back vivid memories of &amp;lsquo;night float&amp;rsquo; during residency. Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying it. Everyone&amp;rsquo;s really nice and welcoming. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a change from residency when you&amp;rsquo;re the low man on the totem pole. The patient population is more primary care oriented. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen one transplant patient so far, wheras I used to see almost one-a-day in residency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to the homeland!</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/08/06/going-to-the-homeland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/08/06/going-to-the-homeland/</guid>
      <description>I found out recently that I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending 3 weeks (maybe longer) in Green Bay, WI. I&amp;rsquo;ll be working as a hospitalist at St. Vincent&amp;rsquo;s Hospital (Prevea HealthCare). It&amp;rsquo;s a 580 bed hospital with 40 ICU beds and I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing 12 hour shifts - mostly day shifts, but a couple nights. It should be fun! I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to being back in Wisconsin, especially Green Bay, for football season. Go PACKERS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/15/waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/15/waiting/</guid>
      <description>Still waiting to hear where my first assignment will be. Possibilities include a VA Hospital in Maine, a hospitalist practice in Green Bay, WI, a practice in Racine, WI, or an outpatient practice in Minnesota. Details to follow&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Done with residency</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/02/done-with-residency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1999/07/02/done-with-residency/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally finished my internal medicine residency at New England Medical Center. WooHoo! I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to be a real doctor now&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m planning to spend the next year as a locum tenens physician. I&amp;rsquo;ll be travelling throughout the country, working for 1-2 months at a time. Hopefully, I will get a broad exposure to different types of primary care medicine, so that I can make an informed decision down the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trivandrum Medical College</title>
      <link>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/12/01/trivandrum-medical-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurup.org/blog/1998/12/01/trivandrum-medical-college/</guid>
      <description>In November 1998, I travelled to India to visit family and work in an Infectious Disease Clinic. I visited the Trivandrum Medical College and the Sree Chitra Tirunal Institue For Medical Sciences &amp;amp; Technology. The experience at the Trivandrum Medical College was a little disappointing, but I was very impressed by the Sree Chitra Institute. I got a personal tour of the hospital and operating rooms from Dr. Krishnamanohar (a close friend of my brother-in-law).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>