<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: computers | Vinod Kurup]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/categories/computers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.kurup.org/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-31T20:09:28-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.kurup.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinod Kurup]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinod@kurup.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I've gone to the dark side]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/10/14/ive-gone-to-the-dark-side"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T16:09:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2012/10/14/ive-gone-to-the-dark-side</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was a huge Apple fan growing up and IBM was Apple's enemy. Buying an
IBM computer would have been unthinkable.</p>

<p>Well, the unthinkable has happened. Of course IBM doesn't make laptops
anymore, but their computers live on under the Lenovo name. I am the
proud owner of a new <a href="http://shop.lenovo.com/us/laptops/thinkpad/t-series/t420s">Lenovo Thinkpad
T420S</a>. I
love this computer. It's an ugly black boxy thing, but it's light (4
lbs), quiet and speedy. And the keyboard is just pure awesome. That's
the main reason that I bought the T420S as opposed to the current T430
line. The new line has the chicklet keyboard that is being used on all
laptops these days. The T420 is the last one with the old-fashioned
clicky keyboard, which I love.</p>

<p>I also feel very lucky to get the deal that I got. I bought it from
<a href="http://outlet.lenovo.com">Lenovo's Outlet store</a>, which had about
thirty T420s's in stock when I was shopping. This one was about half
the price of the others, by my estimation. It's so underpriced that
I'm wondering if I'm missing an obvious flaw, but I don't see it.
(Please let me know if you do!)</p>

<p>Here's a comparison between the specs of my computer compared to one
that was available at the Outlet store on October 4th, 2012:</p>

<table border="1">
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;</td>
<td>Mine</td>
<td>Other one</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Part Number</td>
<td>417153U</td>
<td>4170CTO</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Processor</td>
<td>Core i5-2540</td>
<td>Core i5-2540</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>OS</td>
<td><strong>Windows 7 Pro</strong></td>
<td>Windows 7 Home</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Graphics</td>
<td>Intel HD3000</td>
<td>Intel HD3000</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Memory</td>
<td>4 GB</td>
<td><b>8 GB</b></td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Display</td>
<td>14" 1600x900 HD+</td>
<td>14" 1600x900 HD+</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>HD</td>
<td>128GB SSD</td>
<td>128GB SSD</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Optical</td>
<td>DVD recordable</td>
<td>DVD recordable</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Battery</td>
<td>6-cell</td>
<td>6-cell</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Network</td>
<td>Intel Centrino Advanced</td>
<td>Not specified</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Bluetooth</td>
<td>V3.0</td>
<td>Not specified</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Fingerprint reader</td>
<td>No</td>
<td>No</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Price</td>
<td class="big"><b>$ 663.72</b></td>
<td><b>$ 1,355.39</b></td>
</tr>
</table>


<p>The RAM is better on the other model, but Windows 7 Professional is an
upgrade on my model. I don't really understand why mine was so cheap,
but I'm pretty happy about it!</p>

<p>I added another 4G of RAM, moved Windows to a VirtualBox image and
installed Arch Linux with Xmonad. It takes about 10 seconds to get
from the BIOS screen to a working computer. I'll post some info on my
setup in a future post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Computers]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/04/02/my-computers"/>
    <updated>2003-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2003/04/02/my-computers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My introduction to computers came when I was about 6 or 7 years old - I
can't quite remember exactly when... Venu Mammen (my uncle) brought home a
terminal from work. It looked like a typewriter, but it had 2
suction-cup-thingys where you could attach a phone headset. (Phone headsets
were pretty much all the same shape back then). Venu Mammen issued some
magical command and then up on the screen came the most amazing
phrase. ADVENTURE v1.0. (Actually, I can't remember for sure if it was a
LED screen or if it was a dot matrix printer output - Do you remember
Manu?.) Anyway, I stayed up late that night (read: 9PM) moving around an
endless maze without really ever getting anywhere. I always sucked at
adventure games... Despite this failure, I was hooked on computers.</p>

<div style="float:right;">
<img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/zx80.gif" height="188" width="380" alt=" [Sinclair ZX-80] " />
</div>


<p>Around 1980, my father brought home a <a
href="http://oldcomputers.net/zx80.html">Sinclair
ZX-80</a>. This computer had a whole 1K of RAM, and if you filled up the
RAM - no need to worry. Just hook it up to any handy portable cassette
recorder and you could save all the information you'd ever need (well,
about 20K or so). I think my brother wrote a 'number guessing' program... I
was so impressed.  He saved the program on a cassette tape and I still
remember trying to listen to the tape on the cassette player, half
expecting it to speak, "Guess a number from 1 to 100." No luck, though -
programming apparently was a bit more complicated.</p>

<div style="float:left;">
<img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/iie.gif" height="135" width="200" alt=" [Apple IIe] " />
</div>


<p>Some time later, we moved up to the big time (in my
estimation). An <a href="http://apple-history.com/?page=gallery&amp;model=aIIe&amp;performa=off&amp;sort=date&amp;order=ASC">Apple
IIe</a> with the Apple III monitor, 1 MHz processor, 64K of RAM (which we
later upgraded to 256K!!!!), 2 floppy disk drives and AppleWorks
software. This computer served me throughout high school. I began to dabble
with programming in BASIC and assembly. I think that Apple is still sitting
in my parents basement. I'll have to see if I can load up One-on-One
again...</p>

<p>My dad bought a Mac Plus for work when it came out and he let me play on it. I couldn't believe what I was seeing. No command line interface. A little arrow that moved in response to my movements on a "mouse". Folders that you could move around. I was in heaven! I perused all the manuals that came with it trying to learn as much as I could about this new beast. Around this time, my dad asked me to help him computerize the medical testing that his lab does. I fooled around with HyperCard for about a week and wrote my first Macintosh program.</p>

<div style="float:right;">
<img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/classicii.gif" height="167" width="200" alt=" [Mac Classic II] " />
</div>


<p>The first couple years of college, I was computerless. My junior year, I
decided to splurge and I bought a Mac Classic II - 4 MB RAM, 80 MB HD, 16
MHz 68030 processor. That was 1992, back in the beginning days of the
internet. It's pretty surprising, but this was actually marketed as a
business computer. I used that computer faithfully for 5 years. Even after
buying a new computer, I kept my old Classic II cuz I just couldn't bear to
sell it (especially since I'd probably only get $20 for it). I finally
donated it to Goodwill in June of 1999.</p>

<div style="float:left;">
<img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/pcenter.jpg" height="195" width="310" alt=" [PowerCenter] " />
</div>


<p>In February 1997, I decided I needed a new computer. Apple was in the middle of their worst year financially - losing over $1 billion. And unfortunately, their line of computers was a reflection of their financial incompetence. Despite this, I still liked the Mac OS platform, so I investigated the Mac Clones which were much more technically sound. I bought a Power Computing PowerCenter 150 MHz PowerPC 604 with 48 MB RAM, 2 gig HD. So far, this has been an ideal computer and I see it being usable for at least another couple years. (and perhaps even longer, now that I've installed Linux on it!)</p>

<div style="float:right;">
<img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/powerbook.gif" height="189" width="225" alt=" [PowerBook G3 Series] " />
</div>


<p>I spent most of 1999 travelling around the country (see my <a href="work.phtml">Work</a> page), so I decided I needed a laptop...ok, ok... I <b>wanted</b> a laptop. So, I donated my PowerCenter to my roommate, <a href="imagetable/gerry2.phtml">Gerry</a>, and bought a used PowerBook on <a href="http://www.ebay.com/">eBay</a>. It's a Wallstreet 2 - 266 MHz PowerPC  G3, 192 MB, 4 gig HD, and a DVD. I bought this in July 1999 and it was everything I could have imagined. I've extracted all my CD's into MP3 format and I bought Virtual Game Station, so I could play Playstation games. This computer is now a complete entertainment system - and it only weighs 8 lbs! Now that I have 192 megabytes of RAM, it's hard to believe that our original ZX80 had only 1 kilobyte of RAM! And even my Classic II had a only a 80 megabyte hard drive! That's less than half the amount of <b>RAM</b> I have now... The way things are going, this computer should last at least a few weeks!</p>

<div style="float:left;">
<img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/emac.jpg" height="255" width="254" alt=" [eMac] " />
</div>


<p>Wow, it's been a while since I updated this page. Around the time I wrote that
last paragraph, I was beginning to get interested in Linux, so I bought
a cheap AMD-K6 processor and put together a little Linux playground. After trying out a few other distros, I finally installed to run
<a href="http://debian.org">Debian GNU/Linux</a> and it's provided me a
wide-open window into the world of <a href="http://fsf.org">Free Software</a>
(I'm <a href="http://member.fsf.org">associate member</a> #1088). I'm not
coming back :-). <a href="http://www.fsf.org/register_form?referrer=1088"><img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/fsf-member.png" alt="[FSF Associate Member]" width="88" height="31" /></a></p>

<div style="float:right;">
<img src="https://www.kurup.org/images/pg4_12.jpg" height="157" width="215" alt=" [Powerbook 12] " />
</div>


<p>My Wallstreet finally died in the fall of 2002 and I mercilessly sold it
for the value of its parts. I bought an <a
href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EMac">eMac</a> because it appealed to my
sense of "bang for the buck", but I missed the portability of my
laptop. So, I sold the eMac to Sung's parents and bought the <a
href="http://www.everymac.com/systems/apple/powerbook_g4/stats/powerbook_g4_1.33_12.html">12-inch
Powerbook</a> in the Spring of 2003. I miss the beautiful, expansive screen
of the eMac, but I really love this new toy. The most lovable part of the
Mac is the new operating system, <a href="http://apple.com/macosx">OS
X</a>. It combines the stability and geekiness of UNIX with the beauty and
don't-make-me-think usability of the Mac.</p>

<p>Apple pictures and movie obtained from <a href="http://www.apple-history.com/">Apple-History</a> website. ZX-80 picture obtained from <a href="http://utopia.knoware.nl/users/stuurmn/">Albert's Virtual Computer Museum</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[R.I.P.]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.kurup.org/blog/2002/09/22/rip"/>
    <updated>2002-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.kurup.org/blog/2002/09/22/rip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bad news! My Powerbook G3 went kaput yesterday. After a day or so of
troubleshooting, I'm blaming it on a dead Power Management Unit. I
bought it used in 1999 and have been using it <em>heavily</em> since. It's
lived in 7 apartments with me (yup, 7!) from Boston to Green Bay to
Minneapolis to Boston (again!) and now to NYC. I still think that 4-5
years is way too short a lifespan for a computer, especially since it
was meeting my needs in every other way. But, alas, that's life in
these days of planned obsolescence.</p>

<p>Anyway, the really bad news is that I stored <em>everything</em> on that
computer. I'm hoping that my diagnosis above is correct and that the
hard drive is unharmed, but we'll find out soon. If not, I'll have
lost lots and lots of stuff...</p>

<p>I'm replacing it with an <a href="http://www.apple.com/emac/">eMac</a>. It has a
700 Mhz G4, a combo drive (CDRW,DVDROM) and a 17" screen. I came
<em>this</em> close to making an impulse purchase at the Apple Store in Soho
when I saw the 17" iMac, but my brother was able to talk me down :-)
The iMac is real pretty, but the eMac has everything that I need at
almost half the price ($1049 vs $1999). I did end up making one
impulse buy though - an iPod. But, I blame that on
<a href="http://badgertronics.com/blog">MarkD</a> since he slyly let me use his
while he was visiting last weekend. I have no question that he's
getting a kickback somehow :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
